[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "Question": "When was the first version of Microsoft SQL Server released?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1983",
            "b) 1988",
            "c) 1990",
            "d) 1991"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Microsoft released its first version of SQL Server in the year of 1988. This version was developed jointly by Microsoft and Sybase for the OS/2 platform."
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "Question": "Which of the following companies originally worked together to create and market the first version of SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Microsoft",
            "b) Sybase",
            "c) Ashton-Tate",
            "d) All of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: First version of SQL Server was designed for the OS/2 platform and was developed jointly by Microsoft and Sybase along with Ashton-Tate."
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "Question": "Which of the SQL Server RTM included native support for managing XML data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 7.0",
            "b) 6.5",
            "c) 8",
            "d) 9"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Support for XML is integrated into all the components from SQL Server 2005 RTM 9."
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "Question": "Codename for SQL Server 2012 is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Kilimanjaro",
            "b) Katmai",
            "c) Denali",
            "d) Hekaton"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Codenames for SQL Server 2005, 2008, 2008 R2, 2012, 2014 are Yukon, Katmai, Kilimanjaro, Denali and Hekaton respectively."
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "Question": "SQL Server 2005 has the following features?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Dynamic Management Views",
            "b) FILESTREAM",
            "c) Powerpivot",
            "d) In-memory capability"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server 2005 introduced DMVs (Dynamic Management Views), which are specialized views and functions that return server state information. FILESTREAM, Powerpivot and in-memory capability were introduced in 2008,2008 R2 and 2014 respectively."
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "Question": "_________ is a software application first launched with the Microsoft SQL Server 2005.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Enterprise Manager",
            "b) Query Analyzer",
            "c) Business Intelligence Development Studio",
            "d) SQL Server Management Studio"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS) is an integrated environment that combines the features of Enterprise Manager, Query Analyzer, and Analysis Manager, included in previous releases of SQL Server, into a single environment."
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "Question": "LocalDB was introduced in which of the following versions of SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2012",
            "b) 2008",
            "c) 2014",
            "d) 2008 R2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: LocalDB was introduced in SQL Server 2012 CTP3. It’s basically a new version of SQL Express, with same functionality, dedicated to developers."
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "Question": "_________ is free database software running free SQL Server technology.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server Express",
            "b) SQL Server Workgroup",
            "c) SQL Server Enterprise",
            "d) SQL Server Web"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server Express Edition is a scaled down, free edition of SQL Server, which includes the core database engine."
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "Question": "__________is the first true GUI-based database server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server 7.0",
            "b) SQL Server 6.5",
            "c) SQL Server 2005",
            "d) SQL Server 2008"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server 7.0 provides a graphical user interface to interactively build a query and view the result for data source types."
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "Question": "Which was the first version of SQL Server to introduce in-memory capability?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server 2012",
            "b) SQL Server 2014",
            "c) SQL Server 2005",
            "d) SQL Server 2008"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQL Server 2014 provides a new in-memory capability for tables that can fit entirely in memory (also known as Hekaton)."
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "Question": "Management Studio is ________ used for development of SQL Server database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Front end tool",
            "b) Back end tool",
            "c) Database engine",
            "d) SQL Server"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Management Studio is a front-end client tool used to manage SQL Server and develop databases."
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "Question": "Which panel presents a list of objects under the selected node?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Template Explorer",
            "b) Object Explorer",
            "c) Properties window",
            "d) Query Editor"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Object Explorer is used for administering and developing SQL Server database objects."
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "Question": "Template Explorer is used to manage ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) T-SQL scripts",
            "b) Registered Servers",
            "c) Properties",
            "d) Query design"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Template Explorer is used to create and manage T-SQL code templates."
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "Question": "Which of the following shortcut is used for displaying error list?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ctrl + /",
            "b) Ctrl + |",
            "c) Ctrl + \\",
            "d) Ctrl + !"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Error List (Ctrl+\\, Ctrl+E) lists multiple errors."
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "Question": "_____________ is not available on standard toolbar.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error List",
            "b) Object Explorer",
            "c) Query Editor",
            "d) Properties windows"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The most commonly used tools — Query Editor, Object Explorer, Template Explorer, and Properties windows are available on the standard toolbar."
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "Question": "Which command is used to reset default configuration in SSMS?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Clear",
            "b) Hide",
            "c) Reset all",
            "d) Reset"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: To reset Management Studio to its default configuration (Object Explorer ➪ Tabbed Documents ➪Property Window) use the Window ➪ Reset Window Layout menu command."
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "Question": "7._________ is tool in SSMS used to manage multiple servers.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Registered Servers",
            "b) Query Editor",
            "c) Template Explorer",
            "d) Context Explorer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Using Registered Servers, connection information can be maintained for connections to the Database Engine, Analysis Services, Reporting Services, SQL Server Mobile Edition Databases, and Integration Services."
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a database object?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Tables",
            "b) Triggers",
            "c) Functions",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SQL Server has many database objects such as service broker, views, tables and many more."
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "Question": "Which of the following tool is used for designing schema of the database in SSMS?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Query Designer",
            "b) Database Diagrams",
            "c) Table designer",
            "d) Query Editor"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Table Designer is used to create and modify tables (rows and columns)."
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "Question": "Which of the following pane option is not provided by Query Designer?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Diagram pane",
            "b) Grid pane",
            "c) Results pane",
            "d) Query pane"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Query Designer does not provide Query pane for querying database schema."
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "Question": "SMO in SQL Server stands for ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Server Management Object",
            "b) Service Management Object",
            "c) SQL Management Object",
            "d) SQL Server Management Object"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SQL Server Management Objects (SMO) is a collection of objects that are designed for programming all aspects of managing Microsoft SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "Question": "Which of the following feature is not provided by SSS 2008?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Automatic formatting",
            "b) IntelliSense",
            "c) Code Outlining",
            "d) SQLCMD"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Management Studio Query Editor does not provide automatic formatting of T-SQL. There are some free websites that enable you to submit a SQL statement and will then format the code, but I’ve been using SQL Prompt from Red Gate and I’ve come to depend on it for consistent formatting."
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "Question": "Ctrl+K+K  shortcut refers to ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Refresh IntelliSense",
            "b) Add or remove a bookmark",
            "c) Enable all bookmarks",
            "d) Move to the next bookmark"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To toggle bookmarks on/off within SSMS, press Ctrl+K+K."
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "Question": "Which of the following shortcut is used to clear all bookmarks?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ctrl+K+L",
            "b) Ctrl+K+O",
            "c) Ctrl+K+B",
            "d) Ctrl+K+P"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To delete all within SSMS, press Ctrl+K+L."
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "Question": "__________menu allows user to set up some keyboard shortcuts.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Edit",
            "b) File",
            "c) Tools",
            "d) None of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In SSMS click Tools, and then Options.  Select Keyboard from the Environment tree and set up the things you are like to type very often."
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "Question": "Which menu is used to restore windows to their original locations?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Edit",
            "b) File",
            "c) Tools",
            "d) Windows"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: To restore windows to their original locations, on the Window menu, click Reset Window Layout."
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used to build sql statements without writing code?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Registered Servers",
            "b) Query Designer",
            "c) Template Explorer",
            "d) Context Explorer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Within the Management Studio, Query Designer can build a SQL statement without having to write your own SQL code."
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a database object?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Database Diagrams",
            "b) Stored Procedures",
            "c) PowerShell",
            "d) Index"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: PowerShell is a tool utility not a database object."
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "Question": "______________ is schematic drawing used for representing relationships in database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Trigger",
            "b) Database Diagrams",
            "c) Table designer",
            "d) Query Editor"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Database diagram tool allows you to visualize a database structure for further analysis and generate a table relationship diagram from an existing schema."
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "Question": "The _________ database is used by SQL Server Agent for scheduling alerts and jobs, and recording operators.",
        "Options": [
            "a) model",
            "b) msdb",
            "c) master",
            "d) temp"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MSDB Database stores information related to database backups, DTS packages, Replication, SQL Agent information, SQL Server jobs."
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a large object data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) varchar(max)",
            "b) varbinary(max)",
            "c) nvarchar(max)",
            "d) image"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In SQL Server, based on their storage characteristics, some data types are designated as large value data types and large object data types."
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "Question": "Data types in SQL Server are organized into how many categories?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6",
            "b) 8",
            "c) 9",
            "d) 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server offers six categories of data types for your use:-exact numeric, Unicode character strings, approximate numeric, Binary strings, Date and time and Character strings."
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "Question": "Exact Numeric data type is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) bigint",
            "b) int",
            "c) smallmoney",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Exact numeric data types store numeric values where you wish to specify the precision of the variable. They may include integer or decimal numbers."
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "Question": "ntext data type falls under which category?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Exact numerics",
            "b) Character strings",
            "c) Unicode character strings",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ntext is fixed and variable-length data type for storing large non-Unicode and Unicode character."
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "Question": "A column of type __________ may contain rows of different data types.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ntext",
            "b) date",
            "c) smallmoney",
            "d) sql_variant"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: sql_variant is data type that stores values of various SQL Server-supported data types."
    },
    {
        "id": 36,
        "Question": "You want to track date and time of the last write access per row?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Add TIMESTAMP column to the table",
            "b) Add a DATETIME column to the table and assign getdate() as the default value",
            "c) Add a DATETIME column to the table and write a trigger that sets its value",
            "d) Add a UNIQUEIDENTIFIER column to the table and use it with SQL Server’s built-in functions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The correct answer is Add a DATETIME column to the table and write a trigger that sets its value."
    },
    {
        "id": 37,
        "Question": "7._________ is  a spatial data type.",
        "Options": [
            "a) geometry",
            "b) sql_variant",
            "c) cursor",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQL Server supports the geometry and geography data types for storing spatial data. These types support methods and properties that allow for the creation, comparison, analysis, and retrieval of spatial data."
    },
    {
        "id": 38,
        "Question": "Which of the following data type is not present in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) bit",
            "b) boolean",
            "c) hierarchyid",
            "d) geography"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQL Server doesn’t have a Boolean data type, at least not by that name. To store True/False, Yes/No, and On/Off values, use the bit data type. It accepts only three values: 0, 1, and NULL."
    },
    {
        "id": 39,
        "Question": "______________ is monetary data type in SQL Server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Smallmoney",
            "b) sql_variant",
            "c) Cursor",
            "d) None of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Monetary data types are data types that represent monetary or currency values such as smallmoney and money."
    },
    {
        "id": 40,
        "Question": "Which of the data type has a storage size of 8 bytes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) timestamp",
            "b) uniqueidentifier",
            "c) real",
            "d) smallmoney"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: uniqueidentifier, real and smallmoney data types have storage size of 16,4 and 4 bytes respectively."
    },
    {
        "id": 41,
        "Question": "______________ function  returns current date and time.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SET DATEFIRST",
            "b) SYSDATETIME",
            "c) Cert_ID",
            "d) GETDATE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: GETDATE function is used to obtain the current system date and time. Although GETDATE doesn’t have any input parameters, you still need to include the parentheses in your code because that’s how SQL Server typically identifies functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 42,
        "Question": "Which of the following function checks whether the expression is a valid date or not?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ISDATE",
            "b) ISDAY",
            "c) ISVALID",
            "d) ISYEAR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ISDATE() determines whether a datetime or smalldatetime input expression is a valid date or time value."
    },
    {
        "id": 43,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a mathematical function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ATN2",
            "b) POWER",
            "c) PI",
            "d) CEIL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SQL Server has CEILING function to get the smallest integer greater than the specified expression."
    },
    {
        "id": 44,
        "Question": "@@NESTLEVEL function  falls under which of the following category?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Configuration functions",
            "b) Cursor functions",
            "c) Mathematical functions",
            "d) Date and Time Data Functions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Configuration functions return information about the current configuration."
    },
    {
        "id": 45,
        "Question": "__________ are used for supporting encryption, decryption, digital signing and their validation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Cryptographic functions",
            "b) Cursor functions",
            "c) Configuration functions",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Encryption and decryption of data is done by cryptographic functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 46,
        "Question": "DecryptByKeyAutoCert is ________________  type function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Symmetric Encryption and decryption",
            "b) Encryption Hashing",
            "c) Asymmetric Encryption and decryption",
            "d) Symmetric decryption with Automatic key handling"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: DecryptByKeyAutoCert function decrypts by using a symmetric key that is automatically decrypted with a certificate."
    },
    {
        "id": 47,
        "Question": "Text and Image Functions are ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) nondeterministic",
            "b) deterministic",
            "c) table valued",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Text and image functions are nondeterministic. This means they do not always return the same results every time they are called, even with the same set of input values."
    },
    {
        "id": 48,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a conversion function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CAST and CONVERT",
            "b) PARSE",
            "c) TRY_CAST",
            "d) TRY_CASE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Conversion functions support data type casting and converting."
    },
    {
        "id": 49,
        "Question": "______________ returns the rank of rows within the partition of a result set, without any gaps in the ranking.",
        "Options": [
            "a) RANK",
            "b) NTILE",
            "c) DENSE_RANK",
            "d) ROW_NUMBER"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: DENSE_RANK function makes the rank of a row is one plus the number of distinct ranks that come before the row in question."
    },
    {
        "id": 50,
        "Question": "Built in Functions in SQL Server is categorized into how many categories?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 5",
            "c) 6",
            "d) 7"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server provides many built-in functions and also lets you create user-defined functions:- Rowset, Aggregate, Ranking and Scalar Function."
    },
    {
        "id": 51,
        "Question": "Which SQL function is used to count the number of rows in a SQL query?",
        "Options": [
            "a) COUNT()",
            "b) NUMBER()",
            "c) SUM()",
            "d) COUNT(*)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: COUNT(*) takes null value row in to consideration."
    },
    {
        "id": 52,
        "Question": "Which SQL keyword is used to retrieve a maximum value?",
        "Options": [
            "a) MOST",
            "b) TOP",
            "c) MAX",
            "d) UPPER"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The MAX() function returns the largest value of the selected column."
    },
    {
        "id": 53,
        "Question": "Which of the following SQL clauses is used to DELETE tuples from a database table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DELETE",
            "b) REMOVE",
            "c) DROP",
            "d) CLEAR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The SQL DELETE Query is used to delete the existing records from a table."
    },
    {
        "id": 54,
        "Question": "___________removes all rows from a table without logging the individual row deletions.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DELETE",
            "b) REMOVE",
            "c) DROP",
            "d) TRUNCATE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: TRUNCATE statement is a Data Definition Language (DDL) operation that marks the extents of a table for deallocation."
    },
    {
        "id": 55,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a DDL command?",
        "Options": [
            "a) UPDATE",
            "b) TRUNCATE",
            "c) ALTER",
            "d) None of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Data definition language (DDL) commands enable you to perform the following tasks:Create, alter, and drop schema objects."
    },
    {
        "id": 56,
        "Question": "Which of the following are TCL commands?",
        "Options": [
            "a) UPDATE and TRUNCATE",
            "b) SELECT and INSERT",
            "c) GRANT and REVOKE",
            "d) ROLLBACK and SAVEPOINT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Transaction control commands manage changes made by DML commands. These SQL commands are used for managing changes affecting the data."
    },
    {
        "id": 57,
        "Question": "________________ is not a category of SQL command.",
        "Options": [
            "a) TCL",
            "b) SCL",
            "c) DCL",
            "d) DDL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQL commands can be used not only for searching the database but also to perform various other functions.They are DDL,DML,TCL and DCL."
    },
    {
        "id": 58,
        "Question": "If you don’t specify ASC or DESC after a SQL ORDER BY clause, the following is used by default ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ASC",
            "b) DESC",
            "c) There is no default value",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ASC is the default sort order. Null values are treated as the lowest possible values."
    },
    {
        "id": 59,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is true?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DELETE does not free the space containing the table and TRUNCATE free the space containing the table",
            "b) Both DELETE and TRUNCATE free the space containing the table",
            "c) Both DELETE and TRUNCATE does not free the space containing the table",
            "d) DELETE free the space containing the table and TRUNCATE does not free the space containing the table"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The SQL TRUNCATE command is used to delete all the rows from the table and free the space containing the table."
    },
    {
        "id": 60,
        "Question": "What is the purpose of the SQL AS clause?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The AS SQL clause is used to change the name of a column in the result set or to assign a name to a derived column",
            "b) The AS clause is used with the JOIN clause only",
            "c) The AS clause defines a search condition",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Aliases are defined for columns and tables. Basically aliases are created to make the column selected more readable."
    },
    {
        "id": 61,
        "Question": "What does DML stand for?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Different Mode Level",
            "b) Data Model Language",
            "c) Data Mode Lane",
            "d) Data Manipulation language"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Data Manipulation Language is used to modify the records in the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 62,
        "Question": "With SQL, how do you select all the records from a table named “Persons” where the value of the column “FirstName” ends with an “a”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName=’a’",
            "b) SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName LIKE ‘a%’",
            "c) SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName LIKE ‘%a’",
            "d) SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName=’%a%’"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The SQL LIKE clause is used to compare a value to similar values using wildcard operators."
    },
    {
        "id": 63,
        "Question": "With SQL, how can you return all the records from a table named “Persons” sorted descending by “FirstName”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT * FROM Persons SORT BY ‘FirstName’ DESC",
            "b) SELECT * FROM Persons ORDER FirstName DESC",
            "c) SELECT * FROM Persons SORT ‘FirstName’ DESC",
            "d) SELECT * FROM Persons ORDER BY FirstName DESC"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The SQL SELECT statement queries data from tables in the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 64,
        "Question": "With SQL, how can you return the number of not null records in the “Persons” table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT COUNT() FROM Persons",
            "b) SELECT COLUMNS() FROM Persons",
            "c) SELECT COLUMNS(*) FROM Persons",
            "d) SELECT COUNT(*) FROM Persons"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: COUNT(column_name) is used to count the number of rows of a table where column name is a column that does not allow NULL values."
    },
    {
        "id": 65,
        "Question": "What does the ALTER TABLE clause do?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The SQL ALTER TABLE clause modifies a table definition by altering, adding, or deleting table columns and/or constraints",
            "b) The SQL ALTER TABLE clause is used to insert data into database table",
            "c) THE SQL ALTER TABLE deletes data from database table",
            "d) The SQL ALTER TABLE clause is used to delete a database table"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ALTER TABLE statement is used to add, delete, or modify columns."
    },
    {
        "id": 66,
        "Question": "The UPDATE SQL clause can _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) update only one row at a time",
            "b) update more than one row at a time",
            "c) delete more than one row at a time",
            "d) delete only one row at a time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The SQL UPDATE Query is used to modify the existing records in a table. You can use WHERE clause with UPDATE query to update selected rows otherwise all the rows would be affected."
    },
    {
        "id": 67,
        "Question": "The UNION SQL clause can be used with _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT clause only",
            "b) DELETE and UPDATE clauses",
            "c) UPDATE clause only",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The SQL UNION operator is used to combine the result sets of 2 or more SELECT statements. It removes duplicate rows between the various SELECT statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 68,
        "Question": "Which SQL statement is used to return only different values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT DIFFERENT",
            "b) SELECT UNIQUE",
            "c) SELECT DISTINCT",
            "d) SELECT ALL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The SELECT DISTINCT statement is used to return only distinct (different) values."
    },
    {
        "id": 69,
        "Question": "Which SQL keyword is used to sort the result-set?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ORDER BY",
            "b) SORT",
            "c) ORDER",
            "d) SORT BY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ORDER BY keyword sorts the records in ascending order by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 70,
        "Question": "How can you change “Hansen” into “Nilsen” in the “LastName” column in the Persons table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) UPDATE Persons SET LastName=’Hansen’ INTO LastName=’Nilsen’",
            "b) MODIFY Persons SET LastName=’Nilsen’ WHERE LastName=’Hansen’",
            "c) MODIFY Persons SET LastName=’Hansen’ INTO LastName=’Nilsen’",
            "d) UPDATE Persons SET LastName=’Nilsen’ WHERE LastName=’Hansen’"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In its simplest form, the syntax for the UPDATE statement when updating one table is:UPDATE table SET column1 = expression1,column2 = expression2,… WHERE conditions."
    },
    {
        "id": 71,
        "Question": "Which of the following command makes the updates performed by the transaction permanent in the database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ROLLBACK",
            "b) COMMIT",
            "c) TRUNCATE",
            "d) DELETE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Commit command is used to permanently save any transaction into the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 72,
        "Question": "Which TCL command undo all the updates performed by the SQL in the transaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ROLLBACK",
            "b) COMMIT",
            "c) TRUNCATE",
            "d) DELETE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Rollback is used for undoing the work done in the current transaction. This command also releases the locks if any hold by the current transaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 73,
        "Question": "SQL query to find all the cities whose humidity is 95.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT city WHERE humidity = 95",
            "b) SELECT city FROM weather WHERE humidity = 95",
            "c) SELECT humidity = 89 FROM weather",
            "d) SELECT city FROM weather"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  The SQL WHERE clause is used to filter the results and apply conditions in a SELECT, INSERT, UPDATE, or DELETE statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 74,
        "Question": "SQL query to find the temperature in increasing order of all cities.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT city FROM weather ORDER BY temperature",
            "b) SELECT city, temperature FROM weather",
            "c) SELECT city, temperature FROM weather ORDER BY temperature",
            "d) SELECT city, temperature FROM weather ORDER BY city"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ORDER BY keyword sorts the records in ascending order by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 75,
        "Question": "What is the meaning of LIKE ‘%0%0%’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Feature begins with two 0’s",
            "b) Feature ends with two 0’s",
            "c) Feature has more than two 0’s",
            "d) Feature has two 0’s in it, at any position"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The LIKE operator is used in a WHERE clause to search for a specified pattern in a column."
    },
    {
        "id": 76,
        "Question": "Find the names of these cities with temperature and condition whose condition is neither sunny nor cloudy.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT city, temperature, condition FROM weather WHERE condition NOT IN (‘sunny’, ‘cloudy’)",
            "b) SELECT city, temperature, condition FROM weather WHERE condition NOT BETWEEN (‘sunny’, ‘cloudy’)",
            "c) SELECT city, temperature, condition FROM weather WHERE condition IN (‘sunny’, ‘cloudy’)",
            "d) SELECT city, temperature, condition FROM weather WHERE condition BETWEEN (‘sunny’, ‘cloudy’);"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  The IN operator allows you to specify multiple values in a WHERE clause."
    },
    {
        "id": 77,
        "Question": "Find the name of those cities with temperature and condition whose condition is either sunny or cloudy but temperature must be greater than 70.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT city, temperature, condition FROM weather WHERE condition = ‘sunny’ AND condition = ‘cloudy’ OR temperature > 70",
            "b) SELECT city, temperature, condition FROM weather WHERE condition = ‘sunny’ OR condition = ‘cloudy’ OR temperature > 70",
            "c) SELECT city, temperature, condition FROM weather WHERE condition = ‘sunny’ OR condition = ‘cloudy’ AND temperature > 70",
            "d) SELECT city, temperature, condition FROM weather WHERE condition = ‘sunny’ AND condition = ‘cloudy’ AND temperature > 70"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The AND operator displays a record if both the first condition AND the second condition are true. The OR operator displays a record if either the first condition OR the second condition is true."
    },
    {
        "id": 78,
        "Question": "Find all the tuples having a temperature greater than ‘Paris’.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT * FROM weather WHERE temperature > (SELECT temperature FROM weather WHERE city = ‘Paris’",
            "b) SELECT * FROM weather WHERE temperature > (SELECT * FROM weather WHERE city = ‘Paris’)",
            "c) SELECT * FROM weather WHERE temperature > (SELECT city FROM weather WHERE city = ‘Paris’)",
            "d) SELECT * FROM weather WHERE temperature > ‘Paris’ temperature"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Subquery—also referred to as an inner query or inner select—is a SELECT statement embedded within a data manipulation language (DML) statement or nested within another subquery."
    },
    {
        "id": 79,
        "Question": "Find all the cities with temperature, condition and humidity whose humidity is in the range of 63 to 79.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT * FROM weather WHERE humidity IN (63 to 79)",
            "b) SELECT * FROM weather WHERE humidity NOT IN (63 AND 79)",
            "c) SELECT * FROM weather WHERE humidity BETWEEN 63 AND 79",
            "d) SELECT * FROM weather WHERE humidity NOT BETWEEN 63 AND 79"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  The BETWEEN operator is used to select values within a range."
    },
    {
        "id": 80,
        "Question": "The command to remove rows from a table ‘CUSTOMER’ is __________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP FROM CUSTOMER",
            "b) UPDATE FROM CUSTOMER",
            "c) REMOVE FROM CUSTOMER",
            "d) DELETE FROM CUSTOMER WHERE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The SQL DELETE Query is used to delete the existing records from a table. You can use WHERE clause with the DELETE query to delete selected rows."
    },
    {
        "id": 81,
        "Question": "What type of join is needed when you wish to include rows that do not have matching values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equi-join",
            "b) Natural join",
            "c) Outer join",
            "d) All of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:OUTER JOIN is the only join which shows the unmatched rows."
    },
    {
        "id": 82,
        "Question": "What type of join is needed when you wish to return rows that do have matching values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equi-join",
            "b) Natural join",
            "c) Outer join",
            "d) All of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Outer join returns the row having matching as well as non matching values."
    },
    {
        "id": 83,
        "Question": "Which of the following is one of the basic approaches for joining tables?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Subqueries",
            "b) Union Join",
            "c) Natural join",
            "d) All of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The SQL subquery is a SELECT query that is embedded in the main SELECT statement. In many cases, a subquery can be used instead of a JOIN."
    },
    {
        "id": 84,
        "Question": "The following SQL is which type of join: SELECT CUSTOMER_T. CUSTOMER_ID, ORDER_T. CUSTOMER_ID, NAME, ORDER_ID FROM CUSTOMER_T,ORDER_T WHERE CUSTOMER_T. CUSTOMER_ID = ORDER_T. CUSTOMER_ID?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equi-join",
            "b) Natural join",
            "c) Outer join",
            "d) Cartesian join"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Equi-join joins only same data entry field. For example, one table contains department id and another table should contain department id."
    },
    {
        "id": 85,
        "Question": "A UNION query is which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Combines the output from no more than two queries and must include the same number of columns",
            "b) Combines the output from no more than two queries and does not include the same number of columns",
            "c) Combines the output from multiple queries and must include the same number of columns",
            "d) Combines the output from multiple queries and does not include the same number of columns"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A single UNION can combine only 2 sql query at a time."
    },
    {
        "id": 86,
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is true concerning subqueries?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Involves the use of an inner and outer query",
            "b) Cannot return the same result as a query that is not a subquery",
            "c) Does not start with the word SELECT",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Subquery—also referred to as an inner query or inner select—is a SELECT statement embedded within a data manipulation language (DML) statement or nested within another subquery."
    },
    {
        "id": 87,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a correlated subquery?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Uses the result of an inner query to determine the processing of an outer query",
            "b) Uses the result of an outer query to determine the processing of an inner query",
            "c) Uses the result of an inner query to determine the processing of an inner query",
            "d) Uses the result of an outer query to determine the processing of an outer query"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A ‘correlated subquery’ is a term used for specific types of queries in SQL in computer databases. It is a subquery (a query nested inside another query) that uses values from the outer query in its WHERE clause."
    },
    {
        "id": 88,
        "Question": "How many tables may be included with a join?",
        "Options": [
            "a) One",
            "b) Two",
            "c) Three",
            "d) All of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Join can be used for more than one table. For ‘n’ tables the no of join conditions required are ‘n-1’."
    },
    {
        "id": 89,
        "Question": "The following SQL is which type of join: SELECT CUSTOMER_T. CUSTOMER_ID, ORDER_T. CUSTOMER_ID, NAME, ORDER_ID FROM CUSTOMER_T,ORDER_T?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equi-join",
            "b) Natural join",
            "c) Outer join",
            "d) Cartesian join"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Cartesian Join is simply the joining of one or more table which returns the product of all the rows in these tables."
    },
    {
        "id": 90,
        "Question": "Which is not a type of join in T-SQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equi-join",
            "b) Natural join",
            "c) Outer join",
            "d) Cartesian join"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A NATURAL JOIN is an inner join where the RDBMS automatically selects the join columns based on common columns names. Some RDBMS vendors, like Oracle but not SQL Server, implement a NATURAL JOIN operator."
    },
    {
        "id": 91,
        "Question": "What is a view?",
        "Options": [
            "a) A view is a special stored procedure executed when certain event occurs",
            "b) A view is a virtual table which results of executing a pre-compiled query",
            "c) A view is a database diagram",
            "d) None of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: VIEW is a virtual table, through which a selective portion of the data from one or more tables can be seen. A view do not contain data of their own."
    },
    {
        "id": 92,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a limitation of view?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ORDER BY Does Not Work",
            "b) Index Created on View Used Often",
            "c) Cross Database Queries Not Allowed in Indexed View",
            "d) Adding Column is Expensive by Joining Table Outside View"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Views created on indexed Columns are often used because of performance optimization problems."
    },
    {
        "id": 93,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is true?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Views could be looked as an additional layer on the table which enables us to protect intricate or sensitive data based upon our needs",
            "b) Views are virtual tables that are compiled at run time",
            "c) Creating views can improve query response time",
            "d) All of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Views are a valuable tool for the SQL Server Developer because they hide complexity and allow for a readable style of SQL expression."
    },
    {
        "id": 94,
        "Question": "SQL Server has mainly how many types of views?",
        "Options": [
            "a) one",
            "b) two",
            "c) three",
            "d) four"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In SQL Server we have two types of views-System Defined Views and User Defined View."
    },
    {
        "id": 95,
        "Question": "Dynamic Management View is a type of ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) System Defined Views",
            "b) User Defined View",
            "c) Simple View",
            "d) Complex View"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Dynamic Management Views were introduced in SQL Server 2005. These Views give the administrator information of the database about the current state of the SQL Server machine."
    },
    {
        "id": 96,
        "Question": "Syntax for creating views is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE VIEW AS SELECT",
            "b) CREATE VIEW AS UPDATE",
            "c) DROP VIEW AS SELECT",
            "d) CREATE VIEW AS UPDATE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL CREATE VIEW Syntax:CREATE VIEW view_name AS SELECT column_name(s) FROM table_name WHERE condition."
    },
    {
        "id": 97,
        "Question": "You can delete a view with ___________ command.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP VIEW",
            "b) DELETE VIEW",
            "c) REMOVE VIEW",
            "d) TRUNCATE VIEW"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: DROP VIEW removes one or more views from the current database."
    },
    {
        "id": 98,
        "Question": "What is SCHEMABINDING a VIEW?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Schema binding binds your views to the dependent physical columns of the accessed tables specified in the contents of the view",
            "b) These are stored only in the Master database",
            "c) These types of view are defined by users on a specified schema",
            "d) These are used to show database self describing information"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  SCHEMABINDING binds the view to the schema of the underlying table or tables. When SCHEMABINDING is specified, the base table or tables cannot be modified in a way that would affect the view definition."
    },
    {
        "id": 99,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a SQL Server INFORMATION_SCHEMA view?",
        "Options": [
            "a) INFORMATION_SCHEMA.CONSTRAINT_TABLE_USAGE",
            "b) INFORMATION_SCHEMA.DOMAIN_CONSTRAINTS",
            "c) INFORMATION_SCHEMA.KEY_COLUMN_USAGE",
            "d) sys.dm_exec_connections"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The INFORMATION_SCHEMA views allow you to retrieve metadata about the objects within a database.  These views can be found in the master database under Views / System Views and be called from any database in your SQL Server instance."
    },
    {
        "id": 100,
        "Question": "___________ is  stored only in the Master database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Database-scoped Dynamic Management View",
            "b) Complex View",
            "c) Catalog View",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Server-scoped Dynamic Management View is stored only in the Master database."
    },
    {
        "id": 101,
        "Question": "Aggregate functions are functions that take a ___________ as input and return a single value.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Collection of values",
            "b) Single value",
            "c) Double value",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Aggregate functions perform a calculation on a set of values."
    },
    {
        "id": 102,
        "Question": "SQL applies predicates in the _______ clause after groups have been formed, so aggregate functions may be used.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Group by",
            "b) With",
            "c) Where",
            "d) Having"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The with clause provides a way of defining a temporary relation whose definition is available only to the query in which the with clause occurs."
    },
    {
        "id": 103,
        "Question": "The ________ keyword is used to access attributes of preceding tables or subqueries in the from clause.",
        "Options": [
            "a) In",
            "b) Lateral",
            "c) Having",
            "d) With"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Select name, salary, avg salary from instructor I1, lateral (select avg(salary) as avg salary from instructor I2 where I2.dept name= I1.dept name);\nWithout the lateral clause, the subquery cannot access the correlation variable I1 from the outer query."
    },
    {
        "id": 104,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an aggregate function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Avg",
            "b) Sum",
            "c) With",
            "d) Min"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: With is used to create temporary relation and its not an aggregate function."
    },
    {
        "id": 105,
        "Question": "If we do want to eliminate duplicates, we use the keyword __________in the aggregate expression.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Distinct",
            "b) Count",
            "c) Avg",
            "d) Primary key"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Distinct keyword is used to select only unique items from the relation."
    },
    {
        "id": 106,
        "Question": "All aggregate functions except __________ ignore null values in their input collection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Count(attribute)",
            "b) Count(*)",
            "c) Avg",
            "d) Sum"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: * is used to select all values including null."
    },
    {
        "id": 107,
        "Question": "A Boolean data type that can take values true, false, and ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 0",
            "c) Null",
            "d) Unknown"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Unknown values do not take null value but it is not known."
    },
    {
        "id": 108,
        "Question": "The phrase “greater than at least one” is represented in SQL by ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) < all",
            "b) < some",
            "c) > all",
            "d) > some"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: > some takes at lest one value above it."
    },
    {
        "id": 109,
        "Question": "We can test for the nonexistence of tuples in a subquery by using the __________ construct.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Not exist",
            "b) Not exists",
            "c) Exists",
            "d) Exist"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Exists is used to check for the existence of tuples."
    },
    {
        "id": 110,
        "Question": "Which of the following command is used to get child items in powershell?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Get-Child",
            "b) Set-Alias",
            "c) Get-Command",
            "d) Get-ChildItem"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Get-ChildItem is used to get the contents of a folder or registry key."
    },
    {
        "id": 111,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Get-Command retrieve basic information about a command",
            "b) Trace-Command trace an expression or command",
            "c) Get-Content delete content from a file",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  Clear-Content remove content from a file/item."
    },
    {
        "id": 112,
        "Question": "3.___________ convert object properties into CSV objects.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ConvertFrom-CSV",
            "b) Convert-CSV",
            "c) ConvertFromCSV",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:   ConvertFrom-CSV convert object properties (in CSV format) into CSV objects."
    },
    {
        "id": 113,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">PS C:\\bin<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> notepad hello<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>ps1</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Text editor with “Hello world” scripted",
            "b) Text editor with “Hello” scripted",
            "c) Text editor with no script",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Code will bring up your text editor window so you can begin scripting with zero characters."
    },
    {
        "id": 114,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The first PowerShell cmdlet every administrator should learn is Get-Command",
            "b) Get-Event is used to find events in the PowerShell event queue",
            "c) Limit-EventLog is used to limit the size of the event log",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The first PowerShell cmdlet every administrator should learn is Get-Help.You can use this command to get help with any other command."
    },
    {
        "id": 115,
        "Question": "Syntax for viewing the methods and properties we can pipe our output to Get-Member by ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Get-Process",
            "b) Get-Member",
            "c) Get-Process | Get-Member",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The Get-Process cmdlet gets the processes on a local or remote computer."
    },
    {
        "id": 116,
        "Question": "Unrestricted execution policy can be set up in SQL Server can be done using __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Set-ExecutionPolicy Unrestricted",
            "b) Set-Policy Unrestricted",
            "c) Set-Policy Unrestricted",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Unrestricted removes all restrictions from the execution policy."
    },
    {
        "id": 117,
        "Question": "Code for creating an HTML report that lists the name of each service along with its status is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Get-Ser | ConvertTo-HTML -Property Name, Status > C:\\services.htm",
            "b) Get-Service | Property Name, Status > C:\\services.htm",
            "c) Get-Service | ConvertTo-HTML -Property Name, Status > C:\\services.htm",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ConvertTo-HTML is helpful to create a report so that you can send to someone."
    },
    {
        "id": 118,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a set function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) RANK",
            "b) NTILE",
            "c) Window",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The word ‘window’ is used to refer to the set of rows that the function works on."
    },
    {
        "id": 119,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Windowing functions were added to the standard SQL:2003",
            "b) Windowing functions were added to the standard SQL:2008",
            "c) Windowing functions were added to the standard SQL:2012",
            "d) Windowing functions were added to the standard SQL:2014"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Windowing functions were added to the standard SQL:2003 that is managed by the ISO and it was specified in more detail in SQL:2008."
    },
    {
        "id": 120,
        "Question": "Windowing function was added in which of the following versions of SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2003",
            "b) 2005",
            "c) 2008",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SQL Server has had only a partial implementation up to now, but it has come up in SQL 2012."
    },
    {
        "id": 121,
        "Question": "Which is the most important benefit of window function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Aggregation",
            "b) Association",
            "c) Generalization",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Most important benefit of window functions is that we can access the detail of the rows from an aggregation."
    },
    {
        "id": 122,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement related to window function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) They are used to provide details of a backup plans",
            "b) They are used to provide details of an aggregation",
            "c) They are used to provide details of an aggregation",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Window functions belong to a type of function known as a ‘set function."
    },
    {
        "id": 123,
        "Question": "Which of the function is not a ranking window function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) RANK",
            "b) NTILE",
            "c) ROW_NUMBER",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since SQL Server 2005 we have had support for some window functions, they are: ROW_NUMBER, RANK, DENSE_RANK and NTILE."
    },
    {
        "id": 124,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a type of window function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ranking window function",
            "b) Associate window function",
            "c) Analytic window functions",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There is an aggregate window function available in SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 125,
        "Question": "How many types of window functions are present in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 6"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Window functions are distinguished by the presence of an OVER() clause and come in three varieties."
    },
    {
        "id": 126,
        "Question": "Which of the following function is an analytic window function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) LAG",
            "b) LEAD",
            "c) FIRST_VALUE",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  There are 8 analytic window functions in SQL Server 2012."
    },
    {
        "id": 127,
        "Question": "LAST_VALUE comes in the category of _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ranking window function",
            "b) Associate window function",
            "c) Analytic window functions",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The analytic window functions are new for SQL Server 2012."
    },
    {
        "id": 128,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a ranking function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) RANK",
            "b) NTILE",
            "c) ROW_NUMBER",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Ranking functions are a subset of the built in functions in SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 129,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The ROW_NUMBER function simply assigns sequential numbering to the records of a result-set or to the records within groups of a result-set",
            "b) OVER clause is not required in all the ranking functions",
            "c) SQL Server introduced four different ranking functions",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: OVER clause is required in all the ranking functions and with that you specify the partitioning and ordering of records before the ranking functions are evaluated."
    },
    {
        "id": 130,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the simplest ranking function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) RANK",
            "b) NTILE",
            "c) ROW_NUMBER",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The ROW_NUMBER ranking function is the simplest of the ranking functions.Its purpose in life is to provide consecutive numbering of the rows in the result set by the order selected in the OVER clause for each partition specified in the OVER clause."
    },
    {
        "id": 131,
        "Question": "Which of the clause is not mandatory?",
        "Options": [
            "a) OVER clause",
            "b) ORDER BY clause",
            "c) PARTITION BY clause",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: PARTITION BY clause is not mandatory and if you don’t specify it all the records of the result-set will be considered as a part of single record group."
    },
    {
        "id": 132,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) RANK() returns the rank of each row in the result set of partitioned column",
            "b) DENSE_RANK() is same as RANK() function. Only difference is returns rank without gaps",
            "c) NTILE() distributes the columns in an ordered partition into a specified number of groups",
            "d) ROW_NUMBER() returns the serial number of the row order by specified column"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: NTILE divides the partitioned result set into specified number of groups in an order."
    },
    {
        "id": 133,
        "Question": "Which of the function provides consecutive numbering except in the case of a tie?",
        "Options": [
            "a) RANK",
            "b) NTILE",
            "c) ROW_NUMBER",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: RANK function is used when you want all tied rows to have the same ranking."
    },
    {
        "id": 134,
        "Question": "Which of the following will not raise error if not used?",
        "Options": [
            "a) OVER clause",
            "b) ORDER BY clause",
            "c) PARTITION BY clause",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: PARTITION BY clause is not mandatory and when you specify a column/set of columns with PARTITION BY clause then it will divide the result-set into record groups/partitions."
    },
    {
        "id": 135,
        "Question": "Which of the following error message will be displayed if ORDER CLAUSE is not mentioned in ROW NUMBER function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) “The ranking function “ROW_NUMBER” must have an ORDER BY clause.”",
            "b) “The ranking function “ROW_NUMBER” must have an OVER BY clause.”",
            "c) “The ranking function “ROW_NUMBER” must have an PARTITION BY clause.”",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ORDER BY CLAUSE is not optional clause in ROW NUMBER function."
    },
    {
        "id": 136,
        "Question": "Which of the following functions are similar?",
        "Options": [
            "a) RANK and NTILE",
            "b) RANK and DENSE_RANK",
            "c) DENSE_RANK and NTILE",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: DENSE_RANK() is same as RANK() function. Only difference is returns rank without gaps."
    },
    {
        "id": 137,
        "Question": "Which of the following function is used when you want all tied rows to have the same ranking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) RANK",
            "b) NTILE",
            "c) ROW_NUMBER",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The numbers assigned by RANK are not necessarily consecutive."
    },
    {
        "id": 138,
        "Question": "The ________ connective tests for set membership, where the set is a collection of values produced by a select clause. The _________ connective tests for the absence of set membership.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Or, in",
            "b) Not in, in",
            "c) In, not in",
            "d) In, or"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Avg() is used to find the mean of the values."
    },
    {
        "id": 139,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the function of client?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile queries",
            "b) Query optimization",
            "c) Receive queries",
            "d) Result formatting and presentation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Limit clause does not support partitioning, so we cannot get the top n within each partition without performing ranking; further, if more than one student gets the same GPA, it is possible that one is included in the top 10, while another is excluded."
    },
    {
        "id": 140,
        "Question": "Which server can join the indexes when only multiple indexes combined can cover the query?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL",
            "b) DBMS",
            "c) RDBMS",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Suppose that instead of going back a fixed number of tuples, we want the window to consist of all prior years we use rows unbounded preceding."
    },
    {
        "id": 141,
        "Question": "The ______ clause allows us to select only those rows in the result relation of the ____ clause that satisfy a specified predicate.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Where, from",
            "b) From, select",
            "c) Select, from",
            "d) From, where"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  Query optimization is used to improve the quality."
    },
    {
        "id": 142,
        "Question": "1. The query given below will give an error. Which one of the following has to be replaced to get the desired output?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> ID<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> name <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>_Order <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> instructor<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) _Order",
            "b) 2Order",
            "c) 3Order",
            "d) Instructor"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Table name should not start with numerical value as per naming convention in T-SQL."
    },
    {
        "id": 143,
        "Question": "To delete a database ___________ command is used.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Delete database database_name",
            "b) Delete database_name",
            "c) drop database database_name",
            "d) drop database_name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: This query do not have from clause which specifies the relation from which the values has to be selected."
    },
    {
        "id": 144,
        "Question": "The ________________ is essentially used to search for patterns in target string.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Like Predicate",
            "b) Null Predicate",
            "c) In Predicate",
            "d) Out Predicate"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Value keyword has to be used to insert the values into the table."
    },
    {
        "id": 145,
        "Question": "Which is a duplicate copy of a file program that is stored on a different storage media than the original location?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Concurrency",
            "b) Deadlock",
            "c) Backup",
            "d) Recovery"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: This will delete the database with its structure."
    },
    {
        "id": 146,
        "Question": "_______________ joins are SQL server default.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Outer",
            "b) Inner",
            "c) Equi",
            "d) None of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Like matches the pattern with the query."
    },
    {
        "id": 147,
        "Question": "To alter a database ___________ command is used.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER database database_name",
            "b) ALTER database_name",
            "c) ALTER database database_name",
            "d) ALTER database_name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Backup is required to protect the data."
    },
    {
        "id": 148,
        "Question": "The EXISTS keyword will be true if ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Any row in the subquery meets the condition only",
            "b) All rows in the subquery fail the condition only",
            "c) Both of these two conditions are met",
            "d) Neither of these two conditions is met"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: EXISTS keyword checks for existence of condition."
    },
    {
        "id": 149,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an aggregate function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Average",
            "b) Sum",
            "c) With",
            "d) Minimum"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  Sum is used to add set of values."
    },
    {
        "id": 150,
        "Question": "The command ________________ such tables are available only within the transaction executing the query, and are dropped when the transaction finishes.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Create table",
            "b) Create temporary table",
            "c) Create view",
            "d) Create label view"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  DDL statement is used alter structure of table."
    },
    {
        "id": 151,
        "Question": "4. In the query given above which one of the following is a temporary relation?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">WITH</span> max_budget <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw1\">VALUE</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"kw1\">AS</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">MAX</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>budget<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> department<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> budget\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> department<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> max_budget\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> department<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>budget <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw1\">MAX</span> budget<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>value;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Budget",
            "b) Department",
            "c) Value",
            "d) Max_budget"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: With clause creates a temporary relation."
    },
    {
        "id": 152,
        "Question": "Aggregate functions can be used in the select list or the_______clause of a select statement or subquery. They cannot be used in a ______ clause.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Where, having",
            "b) Having, where",
            "c) Group by, having",
            "d) Group by, where"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To include aggregate functions having clause must be included after where."
    },
    {
        "id": 153,
        "Question": "Which is the duplication of computer operations and routine backups to combat any unforeseen problems?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Concurrency",
            "b) Deadlock",
            "c) Backup",
            "d) Recovery"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Recovery means to take the backup data while there is a crash."
    },
    {
        "id": 154,
        "Question": "The UNION SQL clause can be used with ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT clause only",
            "b) DELETE and UPDATE clauses",
            "c) UPDATE clause only",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The SQL UNION operator is used to combine the result sets of 2 or more SELECT statements. It removes duplicate rows between the various SELECT statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 155,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is true?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DELETE does not free the space containing the table and TRUNCATE free the space containing the table",
            "b) Both DELETE and TRUNCATE free the space containing the table",
            "c) Both DELETE and TRUNCATE does not free the space containing the table",
            "d) DELETE free the space containing the table and TRUNCATE does not free the space containing the table"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The SQL TRUNCATE command is used to delete all the rows from the table and free the space containing the table."
    },
    {
        "id": 156,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a class of constraint in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) NOT NULL",
            "b) CHECK",
            "c) NULL",
            "d) UNIQUE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: NOT NULL specifies that the column does not accept NULL values. For more information."
    },
    {
        "id": 157,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) CHECK constraints enforce domain integrity",
            "b) UNIQUE constraints enforce the uniqueness of the values in a set of columns",
            "c) In a UNIQUE constraint, no two rows in the table can have the same value for the columns",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Constraints let you define the way the Database Engine automatically enforces the integrity of a database."
    },
    {
        "id": 158,
        "Question": "Which of the following constraint does not enforce uniqueness?",
        "Options": [
            "a) UNIQUE",
            "b) Primary key",
            "c) Foreign key",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: FOREIGN KEY constraints identify and enforce the relationships between tables."
    },
    {
        "id": 159,
        "Question": "Constraints can be applied on ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Column",
            "b) Table",
            "c) Field",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Constraints can be column constraints or table constraints."
    },
    {
        "id": 160,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Table constraints must be used when more than one column must be included in a constraint",
            "b) A column constraint is specified as part of a column definition and applies only to that column",
            "c) A table constraint is declared independently from a column definition and can apply to more than one column in a table",
            "d) Primary keys allow for NULL as one of the unique values"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Primary keys also enforce uniqueness, but primary keys do not allow for NULL as one of the unique values."
    },
    {
        "id": 161,
        "Question": "Purpose of foreign key constraint in SQL Server is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) FOREIGN KEY constraints identify and enforce the relationships between tables",
            "b) A foreign key in one table points to a candidate key in another table",
            "c) You cannot insert a row with a foreign key value, except NULL, if there is no candidate key with that value",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Foreign key is to enforce referential integrity."
    },
    {
        "id": 162,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a foreign key constraint?",
        "Options": [
            "a) NO ACTION",
            "b) CASCADE",
            "c) SET NULL",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Foreign key Constraints are the built-in mechanism for enforcing data integrity."
    },
    {
        "id": 163,
        "Question": "Which of the following foreign key constraint specifies that the deletion fails with an error?",
        "Options": [
            "a) NO ACTION",
            "b) CASCADE",
            "c) SET NULL",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ON UPDATE clause defines the actions that are taken if you try to update a candidate key value to which existing foreign keys point."
    },
    {
        "id": 164,
        "Question": "How many types of constraints are present in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 5",
            "c) 6",
            "d) 7"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Constraints are Primary key, Foreign Key, Unique Key, Not Null, Check, Default."
    },
    {
        "id": 165,
        "Question": "Which of the constraint can be enforced one per table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Primary key constraint",
            "b) Not Null constraint",
            "c) Foreign Key constraint",
            "d) Check constraint"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Each table is having only one primary key constraint and it contains only unique values."
    },
    {
        "id": 166,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) HierarchyID data type maps the data as a hashmap, so when traversing the binary tree structure",
            "b) In real scenarios, you always need to create indexes using Hierarchy ID data type",
            "c) In HierarchyID, we create indexes in order to make the traversal efficient",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In order to make the query execution efficient, we create indexes."
    },
    {
        "id": 167,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The Depth column comes in handy for performing the indent by using the Space() function",
            "b) Stored procedures are the easiest way to extract hierarchical data",
            "c) Inside SQL Server 2008, Microsoft introduces a new data type  Index on HierarchyID to handle such type of data and reduce the complexity",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: HierarchyID data type provides 2 types of methods – Depth First and Breadth First."
    },
    {
        "id": 168,
        "Question": "6. What is purpose of GetDescendant method in the following code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">DECLARE</span> @parent HierarchyId <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> HierarchyId::GetRoot<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">INSERT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">INTO</span> H <span class=\"br0\">(</span>Node<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>ID<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>Name<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"kw1\">VALUES</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>@parent<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>GetDescendant<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw1\">NULL</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"kw1\">NULL</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"st0\">'Johnny'</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Takes 2 arguments",
            "b) Takes 3 arguments",
            "c) Takes 4 arguments",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Common Table Expressions can be a great way to extract hierarchical data."
    },
    {
        "id": 169,
        "Question": "7. Which of the following function returns true in the following code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">DECLARE</span> @parent HierarchyId <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> Node <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> H <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> Name <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'Thuru'</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">DECLARE</span> @parentNodeLevel <span class=\"kw1\">INT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> NodeLevel <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> h <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> name <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'Thuru'</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> Node<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>ToString<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"kw1\">AS</span> NodeText<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>  <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> H <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> Node<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>IsDescendantOf<span class=\"br0\">(</span>@parent<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'TRUE'</span> \n<span class=\"kw1\">AND</span> Node !<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> @parent <span class=\"kw1\">AND</span> \nNodeLevel <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> @parentNodeLevel <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) IsDescendantOf",
            "b) DescendantOf",
            "c) IsDescendant",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: GetDescendant method takes 2 arguments indicating the left and right nodes on the child level respectively."
    },
    {
        "id": 170,
        "Question": "Which of the code deletes node H using hierarchical data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DELETE FROM H WHERE Name = ‘Steve’",
            "b) DROP FROM H WHERE Name = ‘Steve’",
            "c) DELETE H WHERE Name = ‘Steve’",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the above query,immediate children is returned using the NodeLevel column (@parentNodeLevel + 1). And also notice that I have opted out the parent node because IsDescendantOf function includes the parent node as well in the result."
    },
    {
        "id": 171,
        "Question": "9. Which of the following function will be used in the following code for moving nodes?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">DECLARE</span> @newParent HierarchyId <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> Node <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> H <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> name <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'Johnny'</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">UPDATE</span> H <span class=\"kw1\">SET</span> Node <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> Node<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>__________<span class=\"br0\">(</span>Node<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>GetAncestor<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>@newParent<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> Name <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'S1'</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) GetReparentedVal",
            "b) GetReparentedValue",
            "c) GetValue",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  Deleting a node does not automatically delete the child nodes, this would result in orphaned children."
    },
    {
        "id": 172,
        "Question": "Which of the reasons will force you to use XML data model in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Your data is sparse or you do not know the structure of the data",
            "b) Your data represents containment hierarchy",
            "c) Order is inherent in your data",
            "d) All of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: XML is a good choice if you want a platform-independent model in order to ensure the portability of the data by using structural and semantic markup."
    },
    {
        "id": 173,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a XML storage option?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Native storage as XML data type",
            "b) Mapping between XML and relational storage",
            "c) Small object storage",
            "d) None of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: XML uses large object storage which uses varchar(max) and varbinary(max)."
    },
    {
        "id": 174,
        "Question": "The choice of XML technology, native XML versus XML view, generally depends upon the following factors?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Storage options",
            "b) Query capabilities",
            "c) Indexing",
            "d) All of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Different XML choices may also have different performance characteristics."
    },
    {
        "id": 175,
        "Question": "In which of the following scenario, using XML native storage would be inappropriate?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Fixed schema",
            "b) You want to query and modify your XML data",
            "c) You want to index the XML data for faster query processing",
            "d) Your application needs system catalog views to administer your XML data and XML schema"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: XML is appropriate when we may or may not have a schema for your XML data."
    },
    {
        "id": 176,
        "Question": "XML View Technology is useful in the following situations?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Your application needs system catalog views to administer your XML data and XML schema",
            "b) Indexing Capabilities",
            "c) You want to bulk load XML data and decompose them into the underlying tables by using the XML view",
            "d) None of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: XML bulk load can be used to populate the underlying tables by using the XML view."
    },
    {
        "id": 177,
        "Question": "What is the hybrid model in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Combination of relational and XML data type columns",
            "b) Combination of relational and non relational data type columns",
            "c) Using XML with views",
            "d) Using XML with triggers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  Hybrid model may yield better performance in that you have more control over the indexes created on the relational columns and locking characteristics."
    },
    {
        "id": 178,
        "Question": "Reasons to use native XML features in SQL Server instead of managing your XML data in the file system would be:",
        "Options": [
            "a) You need language support for query and data modification for cross-domain applications",
            "b) You want the server to guarantee that the data is well formed and also optionally validate your data according to XML schema",
            "c) You want indexing of XML data for efficient query processing and good scalability, and the use of a first-rate query optimizer",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: If none of these conditions is satisfied, it may be better to store your data as a non-XML, large object type, such as varchar(max) or varbinary(max)."
    },
    {
        "id": 179,
        "Question": "Which of the following part of the XML data stored in an XML column is very important for locking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Granularity",
            "b) Degree of Structure",
            "c) Hierarchy",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When the granularity is large, locking large XML instances for updates causes throughput to decline in a multi user scenario."
    },
    {
        "id": 180,
        "Question": "XML datatype was introduced in which of the following versions of SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server 2000",
            "b) SQL Server 2005",
            "c) SQL Server 2008",
            "d) SQL Server 2012"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: XML data type allows variables and columns to be created to specifically hold xml data, whether it be an entire XML document or just some XML content."
    },
    {
        "id": 181,
        "Question": "Which of the following feature of SQL Server was used before XML technology for semi structured data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stored Procedure",
            "b) Dynamic management views",
            "c) In memory database",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You need to create a stored procedure to process incoming XML from a partner before SQL Server 2005."
    },
    {
        "id": 182,
        "Question": "What are Catalog Views for XML?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Schema collections",
            "b) View Collections",
            "c) Unstructured data",
            "d) None of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Catalog views exist to provide metadata information about XML use."
    },
    {
        "id": 183,
        "Question": "Which of the following following is used for retrieving XML Schema Collections?",
        "Options": [
            "a) XML_SCHEMA_SPACE",
            "b) XML_SCHEMA_NAMESPACE",
            "c) XML_SCHEMA_NAMES",
            "d) None of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Built-in function XML_SCHEMA_NAMESPACE yields an xml data type instance."
    },
    {
        "id": 184,
        "Question": "What is index type for XML index entries?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 6"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: XML index entries appear in the catalog view, sys.indexes, with the index “type” 3."
    },
    {
        "id": 185,
        "Question": "The space use of XML indexes can be found in the table-valued function named?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sys.dm_db_index_physical_stats",
            "b) sys.dm_db_index_phy_stats",
            "c) sys.dm_db_index_plan_stats",
            "d) sys.dm_db_index_table_stats"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: sys.dm_db_index_physical_stats provides information, such as the number of disk pages occupied, average row size in bytes, and number of records, for all index types."
    },
    {
        "id": 186,
        "Question": "Contents of sys.xml_schema_collections are _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Number of disk pages occupied",
            "b) Indexing Capabilities",
            "c) Predefined namespaces",
            "d) None of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: sys.xml_schema_collections contains the namespaces for xml, xs, xsi, fn, and xdt."
    },
    {
        "id": 187,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement would import additional schema or schema components into an existing collection object?",
        "Options": [
            "a) IMPORT XML SCHEMA COLLECTION",
            "b) ALTER XML SCHEMA COLLECTION",
            "c) UPDATE XML SCHEMA COLLECTION",
            "d) ADD XML SCHEMA COLLECTION"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ALTER XML SCHEMA COLLECTION adds new schema components to an existing XML schema collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 188,
        "Question": "Which operation cannot be performed on XML schema collection?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP",
            "b) DELETE",
            "c) CREATE",
            "d) UPDATE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: XML schema collection is a metadata entity like a table in the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 189,
        "Question": "Can we use untyped XML data type in the following situations?",
        "Options": [
            "a) You have schema for your XML data and you want the server to validate your XML data according to the XML schema",
            "b) You want to take advantage of storage and query optimizations based on type information",
            "c) You want to take better advantage of type information during compilation of your queries",
            "d) You do not have a schema for your XML data"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  Untyped XML type does not have schema."
    },
    {
        "id": 190,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Typed XML type and Untyped XML both have XML schema to validate the Data",
            "b) Typed XML type has advantage of storage and query optimizations where as Untyped XML type does not have this advantage",
            "c) Typed XML types can be validated at both client side and Server side where as Untyped XML types does not have option to validate on server side as they do not have any schema",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Untyped XML type is preferred in scenario when you have schema, but you do not want the server to validate the data."
    },
    {
        "id": 191,
        "Question": "SQL Server 2008 has made several extensions to the XML Schema support which includes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Support for lax validation",
            "b) Added support for list and union types",
            "c) Improved handling of xs:time",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Upgrade steps automatically occurs when you attach your SQL Server 2005 database to SQL Server 2008 for XML extension feature support."
    },
    {
        "id": 192,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a xml data type method?",
        "Options": [
            "a) query()",
            "b) value()",
            "c) nodes()",
            "d) none of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The XML data type comes with four methods that assist with querying and manipulating the XML data stored in the column or variable. Those methods are query(), value(), nodes() and modify()."
    },
    {
        "id": 193,
        "Question": "Which of the following indexes can be created on XML columns?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Primary",
            "b) Secondary",
            "c) Full-text",
            "d) All of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: You can also create full-text indexes on XML columns. However, the indexes ignore the XML markup and include only element content."
    },
    {
        "id": 194,
        "Question": "SQL Server lets you define how many types of secondary XML indexes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 6"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Secondary indexes are PATH, VALUE, and PROPERTY."
    },
    {
        "id": 195,
        "Question": "What is the purpose of the primary XML index?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Persisted representation of data",
            "b) Shredded representation of data",
            "c) Structured representation of data",
            "d) None of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Primary indexes all tags, paths, and values, along with such details as node type and document order information."
    },
    {
        "id": 196,
        "Question": "Statement for dropping XML index is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP INDEX",
            "b) DELETE INDEX",
            "c) REMOVE INDEX",
            "d) None of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The DROP INDEX (Transact-SQL) Transact-SQL statement can be used to drop existing primary or secondary XML and non-XML indexes."
    },
    {
        "id": 197,
        "Question": "Different xml modes available for xml clauses are __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) RAW",
            "b) AUTO",
            "c) PATH",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Within the FOR XML clause,we specify an XML mode: RAW, AUTO, EXPLICIT or PATH."
    },
    {
        "id": 198,
        "Question": "Sample applications to illustrate XML functionality in SQL Server are _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Implementing XML in SQL Server",
            "b) XmlOnlineCatalog",
            "c) XmlSurvey",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Sample application are mostly written in Production.ProductModel table."
    },
    {
        "id": 199,
        "Question": "Following content of XML elements are indexed in full text?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Content of the XML value",
            "b) Non numerical value in content of XML attributes",
            "c) The content of XML elements.",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The content of XML attributes of the top-level element only, unless those values are numeric values are indexed only."
    },
    {
        "id": 200,
        "Question": "Which of the following function is contained by both full text search and Xquery?",
        "Options": [
            "a) search()",
            "b) contain()",
            "c) contains()",
            "d) query()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A full-text search that uses contains() and XQuery contains() has different semantics."
    },
    {
        "id": 201,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) If ALTER INDEX ALL is specified, it applies to both non-XML and XML indexes",
            "b) The rebuild and set option IGNORE_DUP_KEY is not valid for XML indexes",
            "c) The option DROP_EXISTING is permitted in the ALTER INDEX statement",
            "d) The modifications of the primary key constraint in the user table are not automatically propagated to XML indexes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The user must drop the XML indexes first and then re-create them."
    },
    {
        "id": 202,
        "Question": "Which of the following function returns an instance of the XML data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) query()",
            "b) value()",
            "c) nodes()",
            "d) none of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: xml.query() method takes an XQuery statement and returns an instance of the XML data type."
    },
    {
        "id": 203,
        "Question": "SQL Server provides how many Xquery methods?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 6"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SQL Server provides five xquery methods to query xml file or xml data."
    },
    {
        "id": 204,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) XQuery statements are case sensitive and xml is case sensitive",
            "b) XQuery statements are case insensitive and  xml is case insensitive",
            "c) XQuery statements are case sensitive and xml is case insensitive",
            "d) XQuery statements are case insensitive since xml is case sensitive"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In Sql Server XQuery statements are case sensitive since xml is case sensitive. Hence while query to xml data remember this thing."
    },
    {
        "id": 205,
        "Question": "What is every identifier in an XQuery called?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Name",
            "b) QName",
            "c) Qidt",
            "d) Qnam"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A QName is made up of a namespace prefix and a local name. In this implementation, the variable names in XQuery are QNames and they cannot have prefixes."
    },
    {
        "id": 206,
        "Question": "Every database you create has which collection by default?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sys",
            "b) sym",
            "c) syx",
            "d) none of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: sys stands for system and it reserves these schemas so they can be accessed from any user-created XML schema collection."
    },
    {
        "id": 207,
        "Question": "Different types of errors raised during Xquery operation are ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Static",
            "b) Dynamic",
            "c) Type",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The W3C specification allows type errors to be raised statically or dynamically, and defines static, dynamic, and type errors."
    },
    {
        "id": 208,
        "Question": "Functions on numerical values in Xquery are ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ceiling",
            "b) concat",
            "c) contains",
            "d) number"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Ceiling function returns the smallest number without a fractional part and that is not less than the value of its argument."
    },
    {
        "id": 209,
        "Question": "Atomization is process of extracting ________ value of an item.",
        "Options": [
            "a) XML value",
            "b) Non numerical value",
            "c) Typed",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Some of the XQuery operators, such as arithmetic and comparison operators, depend on atomization."
    },
    {
        "id": 210,
        "Question": "With XML DML, which of the operations can be performed on nodes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Insert nodes",
            "b) Change nodes",
            "c) Delete nodes",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To change or remove a portion of the content in an XML variable or column, the modify() method can be used."
    },
    {
        "id": 211,
        "Question": "Why do we use exist methods in Xquery?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To determine if the XML data contains a certain node",
            "b) To examine the XML and return back a scalar value",
            "c) To Shred the XML nodes of the XML data into relational columns",
            "d) To search inside xml data types"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: exist() method is used to determine whether a query returns a nonempty result or not."
    },
    {
        "id": 212,
        "Question": "Full-Text Search in SQL Server lets users and applications run _________ queries.",
        "Options": [
            "a) simple queries",
            "b) full-text",
            "c) scalar",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Before you can run full-text queries on a table, the database administrator must create a full-text index on the table."
    },
    {
        "id": 213,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The full-text index includes only one character-based column in the table",
            "b) The full-text index includes more than one character-based columns in the table",
            "c) The full-text index includes one or more character-based columns in the table",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Each full-text index indexes one or more columns from the table, and each column can use a specific language."
    },
    {
        "id": 214,
        "Question": "Full-text search is an ________ component of the SQL Server Database Engine.",
        "Options": [
            "a) slower",
            "b) optimal",
            "c) faster",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Full-text queries perform linguistic searches against text data in full-text indexes."
    },
    {
        "id": 215,
        "Question": "We can create a full-text index on _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) table",
            "b) view",
            "c) indexed view",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  Full text index can contain up to 1024 columns."
    },
    {
        "id": 216,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) To define full-text searches, SQL Server full-text queries use the full-text predicates",
            "b) Full-text queries perform linguistic searches against text data",
            "c) Before you can run full-text queries on a table, the database administrator must create a full-text index on the table",
            "d) Full-text search is applicable to a shorter range of business scenarios"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Full-text search is applicable to a wide range of business scenarios such as e-businesses—searching for items on a web site; law firms—searching for case histories in a legal-data repository; or human resources departments—matching job descriptions with stored resumes."
    },
    {
        "id": 217,
        "Question": "Full text indexing is a great feature that solves a database problem, the searching of _________ columns for specific words and phrases in SQL Server databases.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Textual data",
            "b) Character data",
            "c) String",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Full Text Index can be used to search words, phrases and multiple forms of word or phrase."
    },
    {
        "id": 218,
        "Question": "Which of the following predicates is used for full text search?",
        "Options": [
            "a) TEXT()",
            "b) FREETEXT()",
            "c) TEXT()",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Full Text Index can be used to search words, phrases and multiple forms of word or phrase using FREETEXT() and CANTAINS() with “and” or “or” operators."
    },
    {
        "id": 219,
        "Question": "FREETEXTTABLE is a full text _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Predicate",
            "b) Function",
            "c) Procedure",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  FREETEXTTABLE functions are referenced like a regular table name in the FROM clause of a SELECT statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 220,
        "Question": "The CONTAINS and FREETEXT predicates return a _________  value.",
        "Options": [
            "a) TRUE or FALSE",
            "b) Scalar",
            "c) One",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The CONTAINS and FREETEXT predicates return a TRUE or FALSE value. They can be used only to specify selection criteria for determining whether a given row matches the full-text query."
    },
    {
        "id": 221,
        "Question": "CONTAINS and CONTAINSTABLE look for a _______ match for the phrase.",
        "Options": [
            "a) exact",
            "b) similar",
            "c) different",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In full-text search, a word (or token) is a string whose boundaries are identified by appropriate word breakers, following the linguistic rules of the specified language."
    },
    {
        "id": 222,
        "Question": "What options did ALTER DATABASE statement add?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DATABASE SNAPSHOT syntax",
            "b) ATTACH_REBUILD_LOG clause",
            "c) DB_CHAINING option",
            "d) READ_COMMITTED_SNAPSHOT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ALTER DATABASE is used for instant file initialization when adding or growing data files."
    },
    {
        "id": 223,
        "Question": "Which of the following item is provided by CREATE DATABASE statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Service Broker options",
            "b) ALLOW_SNAPSHOT_ISOLATION",
            "c) DB_CHAINING",
            "d) Database mirroring"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: CREATE DATABASE is used mainly for creating new database."
    },
    {
        "id": 224,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement removes database including its related components?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP DATABASE",
            "b) DELETE DATABASE",
            "c) REMOVE DATABASE",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: DROP statement adds support for dropping database snapshots."
    },
    {
        "id": 225,
        "Question": "Which of the following database cannot be dropped?",
        "Options": [
            "a) TEMPDB",
            "b) Master",
            "c) MSDB",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: System databases cannot be dropped."
    },
    {
        "id": 226,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) When a database is dropped, the master database should be backed up",
            "b) You can drop a database currently being used",
            "c) Dropping a database snapshot does not delete the database snapshot from an instance of SQL Server",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Master database records all of the system level information for a SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 227,
        "Question": "Which is the minimal permission that a user must have to drop the database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) READ",
            "b) WRITE",
            "c) VIEW",
            "d) CONTROL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: To execute DROP DATABASE, at a minimum, a user must have CONTROL permission on the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 228,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement removes sales and suppliers database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP DATABASE Sales, NewSales",
            "b) DROP DATABASE Sales, suppliers",
            "c) DROP DATABASE Sales and suppliers",
            "d) DROP DATABASE Sales-suppliers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: DROP DATABASE can be used for removing multiple databases in one statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 229,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is used to create database snapshot?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE DATABASE",
            "b) CREATE SNAPSHOT",
            "c) CREATE SNAPDB",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: CREATE DATABASE statement creates a new database and the files used to store the database, creates a database snapshot, or attaches a database from the detached files of a previously created database."
    },
    {
        "id": 230,
        "Question": "Syntax for dropping a database snapshot named “Sushant” would be ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP DATABASE Sushant",
            "b) DROP DATABASE SNAP Sushant",
            "c) DROP SNAPSHOT Sushant",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: DROP command removes database snapshot without affecting the source database."
    },
    {
        "id": 231,
        "Question": "View used used for displaying current status of database is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) system.databases",
            "b) current.databases",
            "c) sys.databases",
            "d) status.databases"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: sys.databases catalog view is used for displaying the present status of the system."
    },
    {
        "id": 232,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) You cannot drop a database currently being used",
            "b) A database cannot be dropped regardless of its state",
            "c) Any database snapshots on a database must be dropped before the database can be dropped",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A database can be dropped regardless of its state: offline, read-only, suspect, and so on."
    },
    {
        "id": 233,
        "Question": "Which of the following database should be backed up regularly?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Adventure Works",
            "b) Pub",
            "c) TEMPDB",
            "d) Master"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: When a database is dropped, the master database should be backed up."
    },
    {
        "id": 234,
        "Question": "The DROP DATABASE statement must run in ________ mode.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Autocommit",
            "b) Commit",
            "c) Readcommit",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Autocommit mode is the default transaction management mode."
    },
    {
        "id": 235,
        "Question": "Features provided by ALTER DATABASE statement do not include ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Deletes database",
            "b) Modifies file",
            "c) Changes the attributes of a database",
            "d) Changes the database collation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ALTER DATABASE is used to modify the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 236,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Database snapshots cannot be modified",
            "b) Database snapshots can be modified",
            "c) A collation name can be specified with the FOR ATTACH or FOR ATTACH_REBUILD_LOG clauses",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A database snapshot is a read-only, static view of a SQL Server database."
    },
    {
        "id": 237,
        "Question": "Command used to shrink the size of the database is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) DBCC SHRINK",
            "b) SHRINKDATABASE",
            "c) DBCC SHRINKDATABASE",
            "d) DBCC SHRINKDB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To decrease the size of a database, use DBCC SHRINKDATABASE."
    },
    {
        "id": 238,
        "Question": "Maximum number of filegroups specified for each database is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 32, 667",
            "b) 32, 777",
            "c) 32, 766",
            "d) 32, 767"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: A maximum of 32, 767 files and 32, 767 file groups can be specified for each database."
    },
    {
        "id": 239,
        "Question": "When does most ALTER DATABASE statements fail?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Database is in the RESTORING state",
            "b) Database is in the STORING state",
            "c) Database is in the RESTORE state",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When a database is in RESTORING state then it means one or more files of the primary filegroup is been restored or one or more secondary files are being resotored offline."
    },
    {
        "id": 240,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement modifies view index?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER INDEX",
            "b) ALTER VIEW INDEX",
            "c) ALTER INDEX_VIEW",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ALTER INDEX modifies an existing table or view index (relational or XML) by disabling, rebuilding, or reorganizing the index; or by setting options on the index."
    },
    {
        "id": 241,
        "Question": "Which of the following index options are added by the CREATE INDEX statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) XML INDEX",
            "b) INCLUDED (column)",
            "c) PARTITION SCHEME",
            "d) ONLINE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: CREATE INDEX includes the following new syntax elements:XML INDEX, INCLUDED and PARTITION SCHEME."
    },
    {
        "id": 242,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement with respect to ALTER INDEX statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Adds new format for specifying index and table names",
            "b) Adds the index option:MAXDOP",
            "c) Adds the index option:ONLINE",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Options provided are features of DROP index and CREATE index statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 243,
        "Question": "Which of the following adds MOVE TO clause?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP INDEX",
            "b) ALTER INDEX",
            "c) UPDATE INDEX",
            "d) CREATE INDEX"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: DROP INDEX statement enables moving data from a clustered index to another filegroup or partition scheme."
    },
    {
        "id": 244,
        "Question": "Which is a new DDL statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP ROLES",
            "b) CREATE APPLICATION ROLE",
            "c) CREATE USERS",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Application role creation changes the properties of an application role."
    },
    {
        "id": 245,
        "Question": "Which of the following creates a new Microsoft Windows or SQL Server login account?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE LOGIN",
            "b) DROP LOGIN",
            "c) UPDATE LOGIN",
            "d) REMOVE LOGIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: CREATE login generates a new SQL Server login."
    },
    {
        "id": 246,
        "Question": "Statement used to remove a user from the current database is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP ROLE",
            "b) DROP USER",
            "c) DROP LOGIN",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: DROP USER is used to delete the user account from the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 247,
        "Question": "Command used to modify the schema is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER SCHEMA",
            "b) ALTER STRUCTURE",
            "c) ALTER VIEW",
            "d) DBCC SHRINKDB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ALTER SCHEMA changes the owner of a schema."
    },
    {
        "id": 248,
        "Question": "Creation of  new database role in the current database is made by __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE APPLICATION ROLE",
            "b) CREATE ROLE",
            "c) CREATE USER",
            "d) CREATE LOGIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: CREATE ROLE generates a new role in the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 249,
        "Question": "Purpose of ALTER CERTIFICATE is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Adds a private key to a certificate",
            "b) Changes the public key of a certificate",
            "c) Removes the certificate from the database",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ALTER CERTIFICATE changes the private key used to encrypt a certificate."
    },
    {
        "id": 250,
        "Question": "DDL statements not used for Synonym is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE SYNONYM",
            "b) DROP SYNONYM",
            "c) ALTER SYNONYM",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Synonyms allow client applications to use the single-part name of a synonym to reference a base object."
    },
    {
        "id": 251,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement drops the synonym?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DELETE SYNONYM",
            "b) DROP SYNONYM",
            "c) REMOVE SYNONYM",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: DROP SYNONYM deletes an existing synonym."
    },
    {
        "id": 252,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a proprietary extension of SQL for Microsoft SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) PL-SQL",
            "b) T-SQL",
            "c) PG-SQL",
            "d) P-SQL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Transact-SQL (T-SQL) is Microsoft’s and Sybase’s proprietary extension to SQL."
    },
    {
        "id": 253,
        "Question": "Applications that can generate Transact-SQL can be ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) General office productivity applications",
            "b) Applications that use a graphical user interface (GUI) to let users select the tables and columns from which they want to see data",
            "c) Applications that use general language sentences to determine what data a user wants to see",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Transact-SQL is central to using SQL Server. All applications that communicate with an instance of SQL Server do so by sending Transact-SQL statements to the server, regardless of the user interface of the application."
    },
    {
        "id": 254,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a SERVICE BROKER statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) BEGIN CONVERSATION TIMER",
            "b) END CONVERSATION",
            "c) CREATE USERS",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SQL Server Service Broker provides native support for messaging and queuing applications in the SQL Server Database Engine."
    },
    {
        "id": 255,
        "Question": "RECEIVE service broker statement applies to which of the versions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2000",
            "b) 2005",
            "c) 2008",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: RECEIVE retrieves one or more messages from a queue. Depending on the retention setting for the queue, either remove the message from the queue or updates the status of the message in the queue."
    },
    {
        "id": 256,
        "Question": "Which of the following Statement ends one side of an existing conversation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) BEGIN CONVERSATION TIMER",
            "b) END CONVERSATION TIMER",
            "c) END CONVERSATION",
            "d) GET CONVERSATION GROUP"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Service broker is designed for dialogs, not monolog conversations."
    },
    {
        "id": 257,
        "Question": "Purpose of GET_TRANSMISSION_STATUS is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Returns the status for the first transmission for end side of a conversation",
            "b) Returns the status for the first transmission for one side of a conversation",
            "c) Returns the status for the last transmission for end side of a conversation",
            "d) Returns the status for the last transmission for one side of a conversation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: GET_TRANSMISSION_STATUS returns a string describing the status of the last transmission attempt for the specified conversation."
    },
    {
        "id": 258,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) T-SQL is SQL language for SYBASE",
            "b) GET_TRANSMISSION_STATUS does provide information for messages that do not have a conversation endpoint in the current instance",
            "c) CREATE USER transfers a securable between schemas",
            "d) CREATE LOGIN modifies the login details"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Prior to version 7.0 the code base for MS SQL Server was sold by Sybase SQL. Microsoft SQL and Sybase both support T-SQL statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 259,
        "Question": "Which of the following is- a security statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ADD SIGNATURE",
            "b) EXECUTE AS",
            "c) SETUSER",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SQL Server provides many security statements for a secure database."
    },
    {
        "id": 260,
        "Question": "Purpose of CLOSE MASTER KEY is _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Deletes the master key of the current database",
            "b) Closes the private key of the current database",
            "c) Closes the public key of the current database",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: CLOSE MASTER KEY statement closes the master key of the current database."
    },
    {
        "id": 261,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement decrypts a symmetric key?",
        "Options": [
            "a) OPEN SYMMETRIC KEY",
            "b) DECRYPT SYMMETRIC KEY",
            "c) CLOSE SYMMETRIC KEY",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: OPEN SYMMETRIC KEY decrypts a symmetric key and makes it available for use."
    },
    {
        "id": 262,
        "Question": "Which of the following language is used for procedural flow in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Flow language",
            "b) Control language",
            "c) Control-of-flow language",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Transact-SQL provides special words called control-of-flow language that control the flow of execution of Transact-SQL statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 263,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Control-of-flow language permits statements to be connected, related to each other, and made interdependent using programming-like constructs",
            "b) Control-of-flow statements cannot span multiple batches, user-defined functions, or stored procedures",
            "c) Control-of-flow words are useful when you need to direct Transact-SQL to take some kind of action",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Without control-of-flow language, separate Transact-SQL statements are performed sequentially, as they occur."
    },
    {
        "id": 264,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a control flow keyword?",
        "Options": [
            "a) IF",
            "b) GO",
            "c) GOTO",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The Transact-SQL statement or statements that follow GOTO are skipped and processing continues at the label."
    },
    {
        "id": 265,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) GOTO can exist within conditional control-of-flow statements, statement blocks, or procedures",
            "b) GOTO permissions need not be granted to any user",
            "c) GOTO statements can be nested",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When the IF test evaluates to false, the optional ELSE portion of the statement lets an alternative T-SQL statement execute."
    },
    {
        "id": 266,
        "Question": "Which of the following two Transact-SQL statements are commonly used with WHILE?",
        "Options": [
            "a) BREAK and CONTINUE",
            "b) BREAK and IF",
            "c) IF and ELSE",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: GOTO permissions default to any valid user."
    },
    {
        "id": 267,
        "Question": "Which of the following scenario makes use of BEGIN..END keyword redundant?",
        "Options": [
            "a) when an IF statement controls the execution of multiple Transact-SQL statement",
            "b) when an IF statement controls the execution of only one Transact-SQL statement",
            "c) when an IF statement controls the execution of one or more Transact-SQL statement",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The BREAK statement exits the innermost WHILE loop and the CONTINUE statement restarts a WHILE loop."
    },
    {
        "id": 268,
        "Question": "The BEGIN and END statements are used when ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) A WHILE loop needs to include a block of statements",
            "b) An element of a CASE expression needs to include a block of statements",
            "c) An IF or ELSE clause needs to include a block of statements",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Use the BEGIN and END statements anywhere a control-of-flow statement must execute a block of two or more Transact-SQL statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 269,
        "Question": "Which of the following components constitutes use CASE expression?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The primary key name to transform",
            "b) The BEGIN keyword",
            "c) The CASE keyword",
            "d) Where clause defining an alias for the CASE expression"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: A BEGIN and END statement block must contain at least one Transact-SQL statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 270,
        "Question": "10. The following code snippet uses the DELAY keyword to wait for ______ seconds.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">WAITFOR DELAY <span class=\"st0\">'00:00:02'</span>;\n<span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> BusinessEntityID <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> \nAdventureWorks2008R2<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>HumanResources<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>Employee;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A common use of the CASE expression is to replace codes or abbreviations with more readable values."
    },
    {
        "id": 271,
        "Question": "Variables was added newly to SQL Server version _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2005",
            "b) 2008",
            "c) 2012",
            "d) 2014"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Variable feature was introduced in SQL Server 2008."
    },
    {
        "id": 272,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) All the global variables represent information specific to the server or a current user session",
            "b) SQL Server provides only three global variables",
            "c) Global variables represent a special type of variable",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQL Server provides a massive number of global variables, which are very effective to use in our regular Transact-SQL."
    },
    {
        "id": 273,
        "Question": "Which of the following keyword is not associated with initialization of variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DECLARE",
            "b) SET",
            "c) SELECT",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Variables are declared in the body of a batch or procedure with the DECLARE statement and are assigned values by using either a SET or SELECT statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 274,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a global variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) @@CPU_BUSY",
            "b) @@CPU_IO",
            "c) @@CPU",
            "d) @@I_BUSY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: @@CPU_BUSY denotes the amount of time, in ticks, that the CPU has spent doing SQL Server work since the last time SQL Server was started."
    },
    {
        "id": 275,
        "Question": "Point out the right statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The server always maintain the values of local variable",
            "b) Local variable names begin with a @@ prefix",
            "c) T-SQL restricts the use of variables in ways that aren’t common in other development environments",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: T-SQL supports variables, as do most other development environments."
    },
    {
        "id": 276,
        "Question": "Which of the following global has return type ‘numeric’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) @@ERROR",
            "b) @@MAX_CONNECTIONS",
            "c) @@CPU_BUSY",
            "d) @@IDENTITY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: @@identity retains the last value inserted into an IDENTITY column, even if the statement that inserted it fails to commit."
    },
    {
        "id": 277,
        "Question": "7. Value of the @techonthenet variable can be changed using the SET statement, as follows __________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">DECLARE</span> @techonthenet <span class=\"kw1\">VARCHAR</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">50</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) SET @techonthenet = ‘Example showing how to declare variable’;",
            "b) SELECT @techonthenet = ‘Example showing how to declare variable’;",
            "c) SET @techonthenet == ‘Example showing how to declare variable’;",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SET keyword sets the specified local variable, previously created by using the DECLARE."
    },
    {
        "id": 278,
        "Question": "_________ gives amount of time, in ticks, that SQL Server has been idle since it was last started.",
        "Options": [
            "a) @@ERROR",
            "b) @@IDLE",
            "c) @@LANGID",
            "d) @@LANGUAGE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Return type of @@IDLE is int."
    },
    {
        "id": 279,
        "Question": "@@LANGUAGE variable whose return type nvarchar is specified in _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) sys.name",
            "b) syslang.name",
            "c) syslanguages.name",
            "d) syslanguages.id"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The name of the language currently in use is specified in syslanguages.name."
    },
    {
        "id": 280,
        "Question": "Life cycle of typical cursor involves ______ steps in SQL Server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The five steps are Declare Cursor,Open,fetch,CLose and Deallocate."
    },
    {
        "id": 281,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) A Cursor is opened and populated by executing the SQL statement defined by the cursor",
            "b) After data manipulation, we should close the cursor explicitly",
            "c) A cursor is declared by defining the SQL statement that returns a result set",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: We use cursor when we need to update records in a database table in singleton fashion means row by row."
    },
    {
        "id": 282,
        "Question": "How many type of cursor is present in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 6"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQL Server supports four types of cursor."
    },
    {
        "id": 283,
        "Question": "Various alternatives to cursor in SQL Server are ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) FOR",
            "b) IF..ELSE",
            "c) WHILE",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Cursor alternatives are WHILE loop, subqueries, Temporary tables and Table variables."
    },
    {
        "id": 284,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) We should use cursor in all cases",
            "b) A static cursor can move forward and backward direction",
            "c) A forward only cursor is the fastest cursor",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: We should use cursor in that case when there is no option except cursor."
    },
    {
        "id": 285,
        "Question": "A dynamic cursor in SQL Server allows you to see __________ data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Updated",
            "b) Inserted",
            "c) Deleted",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: A dynamic cursor allows you to see the data updation, deletion and insertion in the data source while the cursor is open."
    },
    {
        "id": 286,
        "Question": "Which of the cursors further have their subtypes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Static Cursors",
            "b) Dynamic Cursors",
            "c) Keyset Driven Cursors",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: There are three more types of Forward Only Cursors in SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 287,
        "Question": "Which of the following FORWARD ONLY Cursor is populated at the time of creation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) KEYSET",
            "b) FORWARD_ONLY STATIC",
            "c) FAST_FORWARD",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A FORWARD_ONLY STATIC Cursor is populated at the time of creation and cached the data to the cursor lifetime. It is not sensitive to any changes to the data source."
    },
    {
        "id": 288,
        "Question": "____________ cursor is sensitive to any changes to the data source.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Static Cursors",
            "b) Dynamic Cursors",
            "c) Keyset Driven Cursors",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A keyset driven cursor is sensitive to any changes to the data source and supports update, delete operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 289,
        "Question": "SQL Server static cursors are always ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Read-only",
            "b) Write-only",
            "c) Read, Write",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A static cursor populates the result set at the time of cursor creation and query result is cached for the lifetime of the cursor."
    },
    {
        "id": 290,
        "Question": "Which of the following blocks are used for error handling in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) TRY…CATCH",
            "b) TRY…FINAL",
            "c) TRY…END",
            "d) CATCH…TRY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server 2005 introduced TRY…CATCH statement which helps us to handle the errors effectively in the back end."
    },
    {
        "id": 291,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) While executing some DML Statement like INSERT, DELETE, UPDATE we can handle the error for checking proper output",
            "b) If transaction fails, then we need to commit – This can be done by error handling",
            "c) If transaction succeeds, then we need to rollback – This can be done by error handling",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server also has an exception model to handle exceptions and errors that occurs in T-SQL statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 292,
        "Question": "Which of the following statements can be checked for Errors?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE",
            "b) DROP",
            "c) DELETE",
            "d) INSERT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: DML statements can be checked for handling errors."
    },
    {
        "id": 293,
        "Question": "Purpose of TRY…CATCH block in SQL Server is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error handling",
            "b) Stored Procedure handling",
            "c) Message handling",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: TRY… CATCH implements error handling for Transact-SQL that is similar to the exception handling in the Microsoft Visual C#."
    },
    {
        "id": 294,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a)  If an error occurs in the TRY block, control is not passed to another group of statements that is enclosed in a CATCH block",
            "b) If an error occurs in the TRY block, control is passed to another group of statements that is enclosed in a CATCH block",
            "c)  If an error does not occur in the TRY block, control is passed to another group of statements that is enclosed in a CATCH block",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  A TRY…CATCH construct catches all execution errors that have a severity higher than 10 that do not close the database connection."
    },
    {
        "id": 295,
        "Question": "Which of the following benefit does Exception handling with the TRY and CATCH blocks provide?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Exceptions provide a mechanism to signal errors directly rather than using some side effects",
            "b) Exceptions can be seen by the programmer and checked during the compilation process",
            "c) Exceptions provide a clean way to check for errors without cluttering code",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Exception handling using the TRY and CATCH statements is the common way that modern programming languages like C# and Java treat errors."
    },
    {
        "id": 296,
        "Question": "Exception handling is possible in SQL Server using _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) THROW",
            "b) FINAL",
            "c) FINALLY",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Generates an error message and initiates error processing for the session."
    },
    {
        "id": 297,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an Error function used within CATCH block?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ERROR_STATE()",
            "b) ERROR_STATUS()",
            "c) ERROR_MSG()",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ERROR_STATE() returns the state number of the error."
    },
    {
        "id": 298,
        "Question": "ERROR_SEVERITY() returns the ________level of the error.",
        "Options": [
            "a) State number",
            "b) Full text",
            "c) Severity",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ERROR_SEVERITY() returns the severity level of the error."
    },
    {
        "id": 299,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a global variable for error handling?",
        "Options": [
            "a) @@ERRORS",
            "b) @@ERROR",
            "c) @@ERR",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: @@ERROR is one of the basic error handling mechanisms in SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 300,
        "Question": "How many ways of returning data is present in SQL Server 2000?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 6"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Microsoft® SQL Server™ 2000 stored procedures return data in four ways."
    },
    {
        "id": 301,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stored procedures assist in achieving consistent implementation of logic across applications",
            "b) A stored procedure is a group of Transact-SQL statements compiled into a single execution plan",
            "c) Stored procedures can also improve performance",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The SQL statements and logic needed to perform a commonly performed task can be designed, coded, and tested once in a stored procedure."
    },
    {
        "id": 302,
        "Question": "Data return using output parameter is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Return codes, which are always an integer value",
            "b) A global cursor that can be referenced outside the stored procedure",
            "c) A single cursor that can be referenced inside the stored procedure",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Output parameters, which can return either data (such as an integer or character value) or a cursor variable (cursors are result sets that can be retrieved one row at a time)."
    },
    {
        "id": 303,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a system procedure?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_changeowner",
            "b) sp_owner",
            "c) sp_change",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: sp_changeowner is used to change the owner of an database object."
    },
    {
        "id": 304,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_depends provide the details of all database objects that depend on the specific database object",
            "b) sp_helpdb provides the text of a stored procedure reside in Sql Server",
            "c) Extended procedures provide an interface to external programs for various maintenance activities",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sp_helptext provides the text of a stored procedure reside in SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 305,
        "Question": "__________ provides details on any database object.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_changeowner",
            "b) sp_owner",
            "c) sp_change",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: sp_help provides details on any database object such as tables,views and so on."
    },
    {
        "id": 306,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an extended procedure?",
        "Options": [
            "a) xp_change",
            "b) sp_owner",
            "c) sp_change",
            "d) xp_logininfo"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: xp_logininfo procedure will display details about the BUILTIN\\Administrators Windows group."
    },
    {
        "id": 307,
        "Question": "_____________ procedure cannot be created in Resource database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) System",
            "b) User defined",
            "c) Extended",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: User defined procedure can be created in all system databases except the Resource database or in a user-defined database."
    },
    {
        "id": 308,
        "Question": "Nesting level of stored procedure is applicable for ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Triggers",
            "b) Views",
            "c) Functions",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: We can nest stored procedures and managed code references in Sql Server up to 32 levels only."
    },
    {
        "id": 309,
        "Question": "Nesting level of a stored procedure’s execution is stored in the _________ function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) @@NEST",
            "b) @@NESTLEVEL",
            "c) @@LEVEL",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When @@NESTLEVEL is executed within a Transact-SQL string, the value returned is 1 + the current nesting level."
    },
    {
        "id": 310,
        "Question": "Reasons for consideration of the stored procedure can be?",
        "Options": [
            "a) With which tables will you have to work? Does it make sense to create a VIEW first?",
            "b) How often will this procedure actually be used?",
            "c) Do you want to view data in the database (SELECT), insert new records (INSERT INTO), or do I want to change an existing record (UPDATE)?",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: A stored procedure is an already written SQL statement that is saved in the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 311,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Conditional logic applied to the results of the first SQL statements determines which subsequent SQL statements are executed",
            "b) A stored procedure is a group of Transact-SQL statements pre compiled into a single execution plan",
            "c) Stored procedures cannot improve performance",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Stored procedures assist in achieving consistent implementation of logic across applications."
    },
    {
        "id": 312,
        "Question": "__________ takes no parameters and returns all kinds of interesting information.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_monitor",
            "b) sp_on",
            "c) sp_status",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: sp_monitor displays statistics about the instance of SQL Server in which it runs."
    },
    {
        "id": 313,
        "Question": "Which of the following has support for transaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_monitor",
            "b) sp_bindsession",
            "c) sp_status",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sp_getbindtoken also can be used for transactions."
    },
    {
        "id": 314,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Support for transactions is one of the most important reasons to use database engines such as SQL Server",
            "b) BASE support",
            "c) ACID support",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Stored procedures don’t have support for BASE."
    },
    {
        "id": 315,
        "Question": "__________create the removable database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_certify_removable",
            "b) sp_certify",
            "c) sp_removable",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can’t use CREATE DATABASE or Enterprise Manager to create the removable database. You’ll need to run sp_create_removable with sysadmin privileges."
    },
    {
        "id": 316,
        "Question": "Which of the following stored procedure is used for error messages?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_addmessage",
            "b) sp_dropmessage",
            "c) sp_altermessage",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Calling sp_addmessage is easy for raising errors."
    },
    {
        "id": 317,
        "Question": "_____________ sets procedure options in SQL Server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_procoption",
            "b) sp_dropmessage",
            "c) sp_altermessage",
            "d) sp_executesql"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: sp_procoption sets exactly one option to configure a stored procedure for auto execution when SQL Server starts up."
    },
    {
        "id": 318,
        "Question": "__________ is used to build the code dynamically and execute it.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_addmessage",
            "b) sp_dropmessage",
            "c) sp_altermessage",
            "d) sp_executesql"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: You can execute SQL dynamically using either the EXECUTE T-SQL statement or the sp_executesql stored procedure. sp_executesql is the more flexible of the two though because it supports using parameters."
    },
    {
        "id": 319,
        "Question": "Stored procedure used to remember the exact number of bytes is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_datatype",
            "b) sp_datatype_info",
            "c) sp_info",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sp_datatype_info returns just about everything you need to know about the datatypes available in any SQL Server database."
    },
    {
        "id": 320,
        "Question": "Stored procedure is a __________ set of one or more SQL statements.",
        "Options": [
            "a) interpreted",
            "b) compiled",
            "c) pre compiled",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Stored procedure is a precompiled set of one or more SQL statements that is stored on Sql Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 321,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stored procedure can accepts input and output parameters",
            "b) Stored procedure can returns multiple values using input parameters",
            "c) Using stored procedure, we can Select,Insert,Update,Delete data in database",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Stored procedure can returns multiple values using output parameters."
    },
    {
        "id": 322,
        "Question": "How many types of stored procedures are present in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQL Server is packed full of useful system stored procedures there for its own use that you can use as well."
    },
    {
        "id": 323,
        "Question": "Which of the following procedures are created by user for own actions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) User Defined Stored Procedure",
            "b) Extended Procedure",
            "c) CLR Stored Procedure",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: User Defined Stored Procedure can be created in all system databases except the Resource database or in a user-defined database."
    },
    {
        "id": 324,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) A stored procedure is nothing more than prepared SQL code",
            "b) We can create a Stored Procedure using the Create proc statement",
            "c) We can create a Stored Procedure using the Create stor_proc statement",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  Benefit of Stored Procedures is that they are executed on the server side and perform a set of actions, before returning the results to the client side."
    },
    {
        "id": 325,
        "Question": "Which of the following stored procedure is already defined in Sql Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) User Defined Stored Procedure",
            "b) Extended Procedure",
            "c) CLR Stored Procedure",
            "d) System defined Procedure"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: System defined Procedure procedure starts with the sp_ prefix."
    },
    {
        "id": 326,
        "Question": "System defined Procedure logically appear in ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) sys schema",
            "b) stor schema",
            "c) proc schema",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: System defined Procedure are physically stored in hidden Sql Server Resource Database and logically appear in the sys schema of each user defined and system defined database."
    },
    {
        "id": 327,
        "Question": "Extended procedures starts with the __________ prefix.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_",
            "b) xp_",
            "c) clr_",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Extended procedures provide an interface to external programs for various maintenance activities."
    },
    {
        "id": 328,
        "Question": "Type of procedure that are based on the CLR (Common Language Runtime) is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) User Defined Stored Procedure",
            "b) Extended Procedure",
            "c) CLR Stored Procedure",
            "d) System defined Procedure"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: CLR integration of procedure was introduced with SQL Server 2008 and allow for procedure to be coded in one of .NET languages like C#, Visual Basic and F#."
    },
    {
        "id": 329,
        "Question": "Nesting limit OF stored procedure is up to ________level.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 30",
            "b) 32",
            "c) 34",
            "d) 36"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In Sql Server stored procedure nesting limit is up to 32 levels, but there is no limit on the number of stored procedures that can be invoked with in a store."
    },
    {
        "id": 330,
        "Question": "User defined function in SQL Server can return ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Scalar value",
            "b) Set of values",
            "c) Result set",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SQL Server user-defined functions are routines that accept parameters, perform an action, such as a complex calculation, and return the result of that action as a value."
    },
    {
        "id": 331,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) You can create the function once, store it in the database",
            "b) CLR functions offer significant performance advantage over Transact-SQL functions for computational task",
            "c) Function is a database object in Sql Server",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Function is a set of sql statements that accepts only input parameters, perform actions and return the result."
    },
    {
        "id": 332,
        "Question": "Function cannot be used for __________ statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Create",
            "b) Drop",
            "c) Select",
            "d) Insert"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: We can’t use function to Insert, Update, Delete records in the database table(s)."
    },
    {
        "id": 333,
        "Question": "The benefit of using user-defined functions in SQL Server are ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) They allow modular programming",
            "b) They can increase network traffic",
            "c) They allow slower execution",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: User-defined functions can be modified independently of the program source code."
    },
    {
        "id": 334,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Transact-SQL user-defined functions in queries can only be executed on a multiple thread",
            "b) User-defined scalar functions return a single data value of the type defined in the RETURNS clause",
            "c) User-defined table-valued functions return a table data type",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Transact-SQL user-defined functions in queries can only be executed on a single thread (serial execution plan)."
    },
    {
        "id": 335,
        "Question": "Syntax for creation of user defined function is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE FUNCTIONS",
            "b) CREATE FUNCTION",
            "c) CREATE FUNC",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If a CREATE FUNCTION statement produces side effects against resources that do not exist when the CREATE FUNCTION statement is issued."
    },
    {
        "id": 336,
        "Question": "How many types of user defined function is provided by SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: User Defined functions are created by the user in the system database or in the user-defined database and there are three types of user-defined functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 337,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a User defined function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Max()",
            "b) Scalar Function",
            "c) Inline Table-Valued Function",
            "d) Multi-Statement Table-Valued Function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: max() is system defined aggregate function."
    },
    {
        "id": 338,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not return a table variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) System-defined function",
            "b) Scalar Function",
            "c) Inline Table-Valued Function",
            "d) Multi-Statement Table-Valued Function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: User-defined multi-statement table-valued function returns a table variable as a result of actions performed by the function."
    },
    {
        "id": 339,
        "Question": "User defined scalar function can return only __________ data type values.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Numerical",
            "b) String",
            "c) Float",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: We return any data type value from function."
    },
    {
        "id": 340,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a limitation of user defined function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) User-defined functions cannot call a stored procedure, but can call an extended stored procedure",
            "b) User-defined functions cannot make use of dynamic SQL or temp tables. Table variables are allowed",
            "c) SET statements are allowed in a user-defined function",
            "d) The FOR XML clause is not allowed"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SET statements are allowed in a user-defined function."
    },
    {
        "id": 341,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) User-defined functions cannot be used to perform actions that modify the database state",
            "b) User-defined functions cannot contain an OUTPUT INTO clause that has a table as its target",
            "c) User-defined functions can not return multiple result sets. Use a stored procedure if you need to return multiple result sets",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Transact-SQL errors that cause a statement to be canceled and continue with the next statement in the module (such as triggers or stored procedures) are treated differently inside a function."
    },
    {
        "id": 342,
        "Question": "Which of the following statements cannot be included in the definition of a Transact-SQL user-defined function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) GET CONVERSATION GROUP",
            "b) MOVE CONVERSATION",
            "c) RECEIVE",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Most of the Service broker statements cannot be included in the definition of a Transact-SQL user-defined function."
    },
    {
        "id": 343,
        "Question": "CREATE FUNCTION requires __________ permission in the database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER",
            "b) DROP",
            "c) DELETE",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ALTER permission is required on the schema in which the function is being created."
    },
    {
        "id": 344,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) If the function specifies a user-defined type, requires EXECUTE permission on the type",
            "b) If the function specifies a user-defined type, requires READ permission on the type",
            "c) If the function specifies a user-defined type, requires ALTER permission on the type",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Function creation requires ALTER and EXECUTE permission."
    },
    {
        "id": 345,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the most visible benefit of user-defined function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Slow performance",
            "b) Bad optimized queries",
            "c) Faster performance",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: T-SQL functions are great at processing data. When it comes to business logic and custom algorithms, UDFs can do a much better job. UDFs work was akin to stored procedures."
    },
    {
        "id": 346,
        "Question": "UDFs in SQL Server is composed of _______ parts.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: UDFs are composed of two parts:Header and Function body."
    },
    {
        "id": 347,
        "Question": "When to choose scalar function over inline table valued function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) You want a single value as the result",
            "b) One or more row’s worth of data is expected",
            "c) You want multiple values as  result",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For an inline scalar function, there is no function body; the scalar value is the result of a single statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 348,
        "Question": "Which of the user defined function will be preferred for adding two numbers?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Scalar",
            "b) Inline table valued",
            "c) Max()",
            "d) Min()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: We are can create a Scalar UDF AddTwoNumbers which accepts two input parameters @a and @b and returns output as the sum of the two input parameters."
    },
    {
        "id": 349,
        "Question": "The ability to create a user-defined function (UDF) is a new feature added to ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server 6.5",
            "b) SQL Server 7.0",
            "c) SQL Server 2000",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A user-defined function is a database object that encapsulates one or more Transact-SQL statements for reuse. Developers have been asking Microsoft to add this feature for several versions of the product."
    },
    {
        "id": 350,
        "Question": "Trigger is special type of __________ procedure.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stored",
            "b) Function",
            "c) View",
            "d) Table"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Triggers are used to assess/evaluate data before or after data modification using DDL and DML statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 351,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Triggers are database object",
            "b) Three types of triggers are present in SQL Server",
            "c) A DDL trigger is an action programmed to execute when a data manipulation language (DML) event occurs in the database server",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Triggers are special type of stored procedure that automatically executes when a DDL or DML statement associated with the trigger is executed."
    },
    {
        "id": 352,
        "Question": "How many types of triggers are present in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 5",
            "c) 8",
            "d) 9"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In Sql Server we can create four types of triggers Data Definition Language (DDL) triggers, Data Manipulation Language (DML) triggers, CLR triggers and Logon triggers."
    },
    {
        "id": 353,
        "Question": "How many types of DML triggers are present in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 5",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: We have two types of DML triggers-AFTER and INSTEAD OF."
    },
    {
        "id": 354,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) We can have an INSTEAD OF insert/update/delete trigger on a table that successfully executed",
            "b) DML Triggers are used to evaluate data after data manipulation using DML statements",
            "c) INSTEAD OF triggers cause their source DML operation to skip",
            "d) AFTER triggers cause their source DML operation to skip"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer:d\nExplanation: INSTEAD OF triggers cause their source DML operation to skip and they just execute the code provided inside them."
    },
    {
        "id": 355,
        "Question": "AFTER trigger in SQL Server can be applied to _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Table",
            "b) Views",
            "c) Table and Views",
            "d) Function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: AFTER trigger fires after SQL Server completes the execution of the action successfully that fired it."
    },
    {
        "id": 356,
        "Question": "DML triggers in SQL Server is applicable to _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Insert",
            "b) Update",
            "c) Delete",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In SQL Server we can create triggers on DML statements (like INSERT, UPDATE, and DELETE) and stored procedures that perform DML-like operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 357,
        "Question": "Triggers created with FOR or AFTER keywords is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) AFTER",
            "b) INSTEAD OF",
            "c) CLR",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: AFTER triggers do not work for views."
    },
    {
        "id": 358,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a typical trigger action?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Insert",
            "b) Select",
            "c) Delete",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Valid trigger actions are INSERT, UPDATE and DELETE, or a combination of several, separated by commas."
    },
    {
        "id": 359,
        "Question": "Triggers can be enabled or disabled with the ________ statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER TABLE statement",
            "b) DROP TABLE statement",
            "c) DELETE TABLE statement",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can also use the ALL keyword instead of a trigger name to enable/disable all of the triggers on a table in question."
    },
    {
        "id": 360,
        "Question": "_____________ is special type of trigger based on CLR environment.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DML",
            "b) DDL",
            "c) LOGON",
            "d) CLR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: CLR integration of triggers has been introduced with SQL Server 2008 and allows for triggers to be coded in one of .NET languages like C#, Visual Basic and F#."
    },
    {
        "id": 361,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Logon triggers are special type of trigger that fire when LOGON event of Sql Server is raised",
            "b) DDL triggers are special type of trigger that fire when LOGON event of Sql Server is raised",
            "c) DML triggers are special type of trigger that fire when LOGON event of Sql Server is raised",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Logon event is raised when a user session is being established with Sql Server that is made after the authentication phase finishes."
    },
    {
        "id": 362,
        "Question": "DDL triggers can be applied to __________ statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE",
            "b) UPDATE",
            "c) DELETE",
            "d) INSERT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In SQL Server we can create triggers on DDL statements (like CREATE, ALTER, and DROP)."
    },
    {
        "id": 363,
        "Question": "INSTEAD of clause cannot be used for ____________ trigger.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DML",
            "b) DDL",
            "c) LOGON",
            "d) CLR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: We can use only FOR/AFTER clause in DDL triggers not INSTEAD OF clause means we can make only After Trigger on DDL statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 364,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DDL trigger can be used to observe and control actions performed on the server, and to audit these operations",
            "b) DML trigger can be used to observe and control actions performed on the server, and to audit these operations",
            "c) DDL triggers can be used to manage administrator tasks such as auditing and regulating database operations",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: DDL triggers are a special kind of trigger that fire in response to Data Definition Language (DDL) statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 365,
        "Question": "Purpose of DDL Trigger is to _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Perform administrative tasks",
            "b) Audit",
            "c) Regulating database operations",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: DDL triggers fire in response to a variety of Data Definition Language (DDL) events."
    },
    {
        "id": 366,
        "Question": "DDL triggers can only fire after the ______ statement has occurred.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DML",
            "b) CLR",
            "c) DDL",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: DDL Triggers can be set with either a Server scope or database scope."
    },
    {
        "id": 367,
        "Question": "How many types of DDL Trigger is present in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Transact-SQL DDL Trigger and CLR DDL Trigger are two types of DDL Trigger."
    },
    {
        "id": 368,
        "Question": "____________ triggers do not create the special inserted and deleted tables.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DML",
            "b) CLR",
            "c) DDL",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: DDL triggers do not fire in response to events that affect local or global temporary tables and stored procedures."
    },
    {
        "id": 369,
        "Question": "Scope of DDL triggers in SQL Server can be _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Server",
            "b) Client",
            "c) Views",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: DDL triggers can be server-scoped or database-scoped. A database-scoped DDL trigger is simply called a database trigger."
    },
    {
        "id": 370,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a way to build dynamic sql statements?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Writing a query with parameters",
            "b) Using sp_executesql",
            "c) Using EXEC",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SQL Server offer three ways of running a dynamically built SQL statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 371,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ODBC has the call ExecDirect",
            "b) Few database systems provide the facilities for running SQL code directly against the database engine",
            "c) The SQL code is not stored in the source program, but rather it is generated based on user input",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The SQL code can include determining not only what objects are involved, but also the filter criteria and other qualifiers that define the set of data being acted on."
    },
    {
        "id": 372,
        "Question": "Dynamic SQL Statements in SQL Server can be easily built using ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Cursor",
            "b) Stored procedure",
            "c) Function",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Dynamic SQL is a term used to mean SQL code that is generated programmatically (in part or fully) by your program before it is executed."
    },
    {
        "id": 373,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a calling syntax for sp_executesql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_execute <@stmt> [<@param1 data_type>,<@param2 data_type>, …] ",
            "b) sp_sql <@stmt> [<@param1 data_type>,<@param2 data_type>, …] ",
            "c) sp_executesql <@stmt> [<@param1 data_type>,<@param2 data_type>, …] ",
            "d) sp_executesql [<@param1 data_type>,<@param2 data_type>, …]"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Using sp_executesql to run dynamic statements gives us a couple advantages over EXEC that are worth noting."
    },
    {
        "id": 374,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The @stmt parameter in sp_executesql is a Unicode string containing valid SQL commands",
            "b) The input type @Type is passed as the first parameter to sp_executesql",
            "c) We can specify the parameters for both input and output in sp_executesql",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The output type @retType is passed as the second parameter to sp_executesql."
    },
    {
        "id": 375,
        "Question": "6. Below Code is procedure for dynamic SQL using ___________ parameter.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">PROCEDURE</span> GetArticle \n               @ArticleID <span class=\"kw1\">INT</span> \n        <span class=\"kw1\">AS</span> \n        <span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> ArticleTitle<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ArticleBody <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> \n        Articles\n        <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> ArticleID <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> @ArticleID <span class=\"kw1\">GO</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) input and output",
            "b) input",
            "c) output",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The output of an SP could also be returned in an output parameter."
    },
    {
        "id": 376,
        "Question": "The Dynamic SQL Queries in a variable are __________ until they are executed.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compiled",
            "b) Parsed",
            "c) Checked for errors",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: A Dynamic SQL is needed when we need to retrieve a set of records based on different search parameters."
    },
    {
        "id": 377,
        "Question": "The basic syntax for using EXECUTE command is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SP_EXECUTE(@SQLStatement)",
            "b) EXEC_SQL(@SQLStatement)",
            "c) EXECUTE(@SQLStatement)",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  EXECUTE command is demonstrated using :\n\n\nSET @SQLQuery = 'SELECT * FROM tblEmployees\nWHERE EmployeeID = ' + CAST(@EmpID AS NVARCHAR(10))\nEXECUTE(@SQLQuery)\n\n\n."
    },
    {
        "id": 378,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a disadvantage of dynamic SQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stored procedure can not cache the execution plan for this dynamic query",
            "b) Stored procedure can cache the execution plan for this dynamic query",
            "c) Flexibility in your code that you can not get with standard SQL",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Stored procedure can not cache the execution plan for this dynamic query. So, for complex queries you will lose the performance boost that you usually gain with stored procedures."
    },
    {
        "id": 379,
        "Question": "Which of the stored procedure used for dynamic SQL is prone to attacks?",
        "Options": [
            "a) xp_executesql",
            "b) executesql",
            "c) sp_execute",
            "d) sp_executesql"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: sp_executesql executes a Transact-SQL statement or batch that can be reused many times or one that has been built dynamically. Run time-compiled Transact-SQL statements can expose applications to malicious attacks."
    },
    {
        "id": 380,
        "Question": "SQL injection is an attack in which _________ code is inserted into strings that are later passed to an instance of SQL Server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) malicious",
            "b) redundant",
            "c) clean",
            "d) non malicious"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL injection is a code injection technique, used to attack data-driven applications."
    },
    {
        "id": 381,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Parameterized data cannot be manipulated by a skilled and determined attacker",
            "b) Procedure that constructs SQL statements should be reviewed for injection vulnerabilities",
            "c) The primary form of SQL injection consists of indirect insertion of code",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Any procedure that constructs SQL statements should be reviewed for injection vulnerabilities because SQL Server will execute all syntactically valid queries that it receives."
    },
    {
        "id": 382,
        "Question": "Any user-controlled parameter that gets processed by the application includes vulnerabilities like ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Host-related information",
            "b) Browser-related information",
            "c) Application parameters included as part of the body of a POST request",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The script builds an SQL query by concatenating hard-coded strings together with a string entered by the user."
    },
    {
        "id": 383,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL injection vulnerabilities occur whenever input is used in the construction of an SQL query without being adequately constrained or sanitized",
            "b) SQL injection allows an attacker to access the SQL servers and execute SQL code under the privileges of the user used to connect to the database",
            "c) The use of PL-SQL opens the door to these vulnerabilities",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SQL-injection exploit requires two things: an entry point and an exploit to enter."
    },
    {
        "id": 384,
        "Question": "Which of the stored procedure is used to test the SQL injection attack?",
        "Options": [
            "a) xp_write",
            "b) xp_regwrite",
            "c) xp_reg",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Dynamic SQL (the construction of SQL queries by concatenation of strings) opens the door to many vulnerabilities."
    },
    {
        "id": 385,
        "Question": "If xp_cmdshell has been disabled with sp_dropextendedproc, we can simply inject the following code?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_addextendedproc ‘xp_cmdshell’,’xp_log70.dll’",
            "b) sp_addproc ‘xp_cmdshell’,’xp_log70.dll’",
            "c) sp_addextendedproc ‘xp_cmdshell’,’log70.dll’",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: xp_regwrite writes an arbitrary value into the Registry (undocumented extended procedure)."
    },
    {
        "id": 386,
        "Question": "Which of the following script is an example of Quick detection in the SQL injection attack?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT loginame FROM master..sysprocesses WHERE spid = @@SPID",
            "b) For integer inputs : convert(int,@@version)",
            "c) IF condition true-part ELSE false-part (S)",
            "d) SELECT header, txt FROM news UNION ALL SELECT name, pass FROM members"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: By default xp_cmdshell and couple of other potentially dangerous stored procedures are disabled in SQL Server 2005."
    },
    {
        "id": 387,
        "Question": "_______________ is time based SQL injection attack.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quick detection",
            "b) Initial Exploitation",
            "c) Blind SQL Injection",
            "d) Inline Comments"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Quick detection attacks should throw conversion errors."
    },
    {
        "id": 388,
        "Question": "Which of the following operation cannot be performed in bulk?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Copy",
            "b) Insert",
            "c) Import",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SQL Server supports bulk exporting data from a SQL Server table and for bulk importing data into a SQL Server table or non partitioned view."
    },
    {
        "id": 389,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Bulk Copy is mainly used to transfer the data from outside world to SQL Server",
            "b) Bulk Insert is mainly used to transfer the data from outside world to SQL Server",
            "c) Bulk Import is mainly to transfer the data from outside world to SYBASE",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The bulk insert command can be used within T-SQL script or in a stored procedure to import data into SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 390,
        "Question": "Under the _______ recovery model, all bulk operations are fully logged.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Simple",
            "b) Partial",
            "c) Full",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You can minimize logging for a set of bulk operations by switching the database to the bulk-logged recovery model temporarily for bulk operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 391,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a bulk import operation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) BULK INSERT",
            "b) INSERT..SELECT",
            "c) bcp",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SQL Server bulk-import operations do not support importing data from comma-separated value (CSV) files."
    },
    {
        "id": 392,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) In Bulk-logged recovery model, few transactions are completely logged",
            "b) The operations that are minimally logged in this recovery model are bulk insert, create index,  “bcp” commands, insertion of text , image column and select into query",
            "c) Backups under BULK_LOGGED recovery model will include log records and the data pages changed by bulk operations",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In Bulk-logged recovery model, all most all the transaction are completely logged except Bulk operation."
    },
    {
        "id": 393,
        "Question": "Which of the following utility supports bulk exports and bulk imports data and generates format files?",
        "Options": [
            "a) icp utility",
            "b) bcp utility",
            "c) dcp utility",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: bcp is a command line utility for bulk import and export."
    },
    {
        "id": 394,
        "Question": "___________ does not allow bulk export operation  in SQL Server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) INSERT … SELECT",
            "b) DELETE",
            "c) UPDATE",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: INSERT … SELECT is a Transact-SQL statement that uses the OPENROWSET bulk rowset provider to bulk import data into a SQL Server table by specifying the OPENROWSET(BULK…) function to select data in an INSERT statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 395,
        "Question": "Which of the following performance considerations are regarding bulk operations?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Column locking",
            "b) Batch switches",
            "c) Constraint checking of NULL constraints",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Performance considerations can also be significant when large amounts of data are being imported."
    },
    {
        "id": 396,
        "Question": "________  parameter specifies the number of rows in a batch in bulk insert script.",
        "Options": [
            "a) KEEPNULLS",
            "b) KEEPIDENTITY",
            "c) FIRE_TRIGGERS",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: BATCHSIZE =batch_size specifies the number of rows in a batch. Each batch is copied to the server as one transaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 397,
        "Question": "Which is the default field terminator for bulk insert in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Comma",
            "b) Full stop",
            "c) Parenthesis",
            "d) Brackets"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Field Terminator is used to delimit columns in the source file. There are some cases where I have seen “|” also. “,” can be part of Name. So in that case the bulk insert may fail."
    },
    {
        "id": 398,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) To access a mirrored database, a connection string must contain the database name",
            "b) When the linked server is defined against an instance of SQL Server, catalog refers to the default database to which the linked server is mapped",
            "c) [ @location= ] ‘location’ is the location of the database as interpreted by the OLE DB provider in sp_addlinkedserver",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Location parameter is passed as the DBPROP_INIT_LOCATION property to initialize the OLE DB provider."
    },
    {
        "id": 399,
        "Question": "3. sp_addlinkedserver command creates a distributed server entry called _________ in the following code.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">sp_addlinkedserver\n        @server <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Northwinds\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n        @srvproduct <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Access 97\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n        @Provider <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>\n                <span class=\"st0\">\"Microsoft.Jet.OLEDB.3.51\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n                @datasrc <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>\n                <span class=\"st0\">\"c:<span class=\"es0\">\\b</span>rian<span class=\"es0\">\\w</span>riting<span class=\"es0\">\\s</span>qlservermag<span class=\"es0\">\\n</span>ov98<span class=\"es0\">\\n</span>wind.mdb\"</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Access 97",
            "b) Microsoft.Jet.OLEDB.3.51",
            "c) nwind",
            "d) Northwinds"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: After a linked server is created by using sp_addlinkedserver, distributed queries can be run against this server."
    },
    {
        "id": 400,
        "Question": "4. Which of the following command tells that all local users are logged in as “sa” in the following code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">EXEC</span> sp_addlinkedsrvlogin\n@rmtsrvname <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Northwinds\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n@useself <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"false\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n@locallogin <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"sa\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n@rmtuser <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Admin\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n@rmtpassword <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw1\">NULL</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_addlinkedsrv",
            "b) sp_addlinkedserver",
            "c) sp_addlinkedsrvlogin",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  The command uses the Microsoft.Jet.OLEDB.3.51 OLE DB provider linking to an Access database located at c:\\brian\\writing\\sqlservermag\\nov98\\nwind.mdb."
    },
    {
        "id": 401,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server cannot use execution strategies that involve using the procedures of the Table provider to evaluate predicates",
            "b) For a distributed query, the comparison semantics for all character data is defined by the character se",
            "c) SQL Server can delegate comparisons and ORDER BY operations on character columns to a provide",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: sp_addlinkedsrvlogin creates or updates a mapping between a login on the local instance of SQL Server and a security account on a remote server."
    },
    {
        "id": 402,
        "Question": "6. Which of the following function mainly used for bulk load data is referenced in the following code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span>\nRemoteOrders<span class=\"sy0\">.*</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span>\nOpenRowset<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Microsoft.Jet.OLEDB.3.51\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n<span class=\"st0\">\"c:<span class=\"es0\">\\b</span>rian<span class=\"es0\">\\w</span>riting<span class=\"es0\">\\s</span>qlservermag<span class=\"es0\">\\n</span>ov98<span class=\"es0\">\\n</span>wind.mdb\"</span>; <span class=\"st0\">\"admin\"</span>; <span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n<span class=\"st0\">\"select * from orders\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> RemoteOrders\n<span class=\"kw1\">LEFT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">JOIN</span> MasterOrders <span class=\"kw1\">ON</span>\nRemoteOrders<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>OrderId <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> MasterOrders<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>OrderId\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span>\nMasterOrders<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>OrderID <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw1\">NULL</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) OpenRowset",
            "b) Microsoft.Jet.OLEDB",
            "c) admin",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server can use execution strategies that involve using the indexes of the Index provider to evaluate predicates and perform sorting operations against remote tables. To enable indexed access against a provider, set the IndexAsAccessPath provider option."
    },
    {
        "id": 403,
        "Question": "Which of the following SQL syntax elements is dictated by the SQL dialect levels?",
        "Options": [
            "a) LIKE support",
            "b) Parameter marker support",
            "c) Nested query support",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The OPENROWSET function can be referenced in the FROM clause of a query as if it were a table name."
    },
    {
        "id": 404,
        "Question": "8. Which of the following function will be preferred for faster execution in following code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span>\nRemoteOrders<span class=\"sy0\">.*</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span>\n________<span class=\"br0\">(</span>Northwinds<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"select * from orders\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\nRemoteOrders <span class=\"kw1\">LEFT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">JOIN</span> MasterOrders <span class=\"kw1\">ON</span>\nRemoteOrders<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>OrderId <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> MasterOrders<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>OrderId\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span>\nMasterOrders<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>OrderID <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw1\">NULL</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) OpenRow",
            "b) OpenSQL",
            "c) OpenQuery",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: System administrator should set the NestedQueries provider option to indicate to SQL Server that the provider supports nested queries."
    },
    {
        "id": 405,
        "Question": "The easiest way to start is to create a linked server ‘localhost’ by using _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_addlinkedserv ‘localhost’",
            "b) sp_addlinkedsrvlogin ‘localhost’",
            "c) sp_addlinkedserverlogin ‘localhost’",
            "d) sp_addlinkedserver ‘localhost’"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  OpenQuery runs a little faster because you’re using the connection information that you already supplied using sp_addlinkedserver."
    },
    {
        "id": 406,
        "Question": "To use the .NET Framework Data Provider for SQL Server, an application must reference the _____________ namespace.",
        "Options": [
            "a) System.Data.Client",
            "b) System.Data.SqlClient",
            "c) System.Data.Sql",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: System.Data.SqlClient provides access to versions of SQL Server, which encapsulates database-specific protocols."
    },
    {
        "id": 407,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Using the System.Data.SqlClient, you can fill a memory-resident DataSet that you can use to query and update the database",
            "b) System.Data.SqlClient includes a tabular data stream (TDS) parser to communicate directly with SQL Server",
            "c) SqlBulkCopyColumnMapping lets you efficiently bulk load a SQL Server table with data from another source",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The.NET Framework Data Provider for SQL Server describes a collection of classes used to access a SQL Server database in the managed space."
    },
    {
        "id": 408,
        "Question": "Code snippet for having a named instance of SQL Server would be ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) “Server=localhost\\sqlexpress”",
            "b) “Server=local\\sqlexpress”",
            "c) “Server=host\\sqlexpress”",
            "d) “Ser=localhost\\sqlexpress”"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A SqlConnection is an object, just like any other C# object. The SqlConnection object instantiated above uses a constructor with a single argument of type string."
    },
    {
        "id": 409,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The goal of dotConnect for SQL Server is to enable developers to maintain database applications",
            "b) dotConnect for SQL Server combines connected and disconnected data access models in single SqlDataTable component",
            "c) dotConnect for SQL Server supports new ADO.NET features and technologies as soon as they are released",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: An instance of the SqlConnection class in .NET Framework is supported by the Data Provider for SQL Server Database."
    },
    {
        "id": 410,
        "Question": "Which of the following is enumeration for ADO.net with SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SqlInfo",
            "b) SqlBulkCopyOptions",
            "c) SqlNotification",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The goal of dotConnect for SQL Server is to enable developers to write efficient and flexible database applications. The dotConnect for SQL Server assemblies are implemented using optimized code and advanced data access algorithms."
    },
    {
        "id": 411,
        "Question": "Syntax for closing and opening the connection in ADO.net is _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) sqlConn.Open() and sqlConn.close()",
            "b) sqlConn.open() and sqlConn.Close()",
            "c) sqlConn.Open() and sqlConn.Close()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Bitwise flag that specifies one or more options to use with an instance of SqlBulkCopy."
    },
    {
        "id": 412,
        "Question": "The main features of dotConnect for SQL Server includes ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Extra data binding capabilities",
            "b) Ability of monitoring query execution",
            "c) Supports the latest versions of SQL Server",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  Code snippet will work only on CE device."
    },
    {
        "id": 413,
        "Question": "__________object is used to fill a DataSet/DataTable with query results in ADO.net.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DataReader",
            "b) Dataset",
            "c) DataAdapter",
            "d) DataTables"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: dotConnect for SQL Server includes base-class-based provider model, provider factories, connection string builder, metadata schemas, asynchronous commands, pooling enhancements, batch update support, provider-specific types, server enumeration, database change notification support and so on."
    },
    {
        "id": 414,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) LINQ supports flat outer joins",
            "b) LINQ’s parameterization is inline, typesafe, and highly readable",
            "c) LINQ queries are composable",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: We can add predicates conditionally in LINQ."
    },
    {
        "id": 415,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compared to SQL, LINQ is complex, tidier, and lower-level",
            "b) LINQ supports ad hoc join",
            "c) Another benefit of LINQ is that you can query across relationships without having to join",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SQL will require querying across four tables (Purchase, Customer, Address and PurchaseItem)."
    },
    {
        "id": 416,
        "Question": "6. The following code is used will perform _________ operation in LINQ.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">public bool IsValidUser<span class=\"br0\">(</span>string userName<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> string passWord<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n       DBNameDataContext myDB <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw1\">NEW</span> DBNameDataContext<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>;\n       List<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span>User<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> users <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> myDB<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>Users<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>Where<span class=\"br0\">(</span>u <span class=\"sy0\">=&gt;</span> u<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>Username <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> userName &amp;&amp; u<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>Password<span class=\"sy0\">==</span>passWord<span class=\"br0\">)</span>;\n       <span class=\"kw1\">IF</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>users<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>Count<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n       <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n             <span class=\"kw1\">RETURN</span> <span class=\"kw1\">TRUE</span>;\n       <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n       <span class=\"kw1\">RETURN</span> <span class=\"kw1\">FALSE</span>;\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) update",
            "b) select",
            "c) insert",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  LINQ is simpler, tidier, and higher-level"
    },
    {
        "id": 417,
        "Question": "LINQ to SQL is considered to be one of Microsoft’s _______ products.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ORM",
            "b) ODBC",
            "c) JDBC",
            "d) SQLLIB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: First, when you create a new dbml file with name ‘DBName.dbml’,a corresponding DataContext class in .net is created and named something like ‘DBNameDataContext’."
    },
    {
        "id": 418,
        "Question": "LINQ to SQL in SQL Server fully supports ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Transactions",
            "b) Functions",
            "c) Stored Procedures",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: LINQ provides an easy way to integrate data validation and business logic rules into your data model, and supports single table inheritance in the object model."
    },
    {
        "id": 419,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) LINQ to SQL is translated to SQL by way of Binary Trees",
            "b) LINQ to SQL is translated to SQL calls and executed on the specified database while LINQ to Objects is executed in the local machine memory",
            "c) LINQ to SQL is translated to SQL calls and executed on the specified database while LINQ to Objects is executed in the local machine memory",
            "d) LINQ to SQL needs a Data Context object"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer:a\nExplanation: LINQ to SQL is translated to SQL by way of Expression Trees,which allow them to be evaluated as a single unit and translated to the appropriate and optimal SQL statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 420,
        "Question": "LINQ to Entities applications requires __________ mapping provider.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DataClient",
            "b) EntityClient",
            "c) SqlClient",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A new data-access provider, EntityClient is created for LINQ to SQL for .net framework."
    },
    {
        "id": 421,
        "Question": "The ______ pre-compiler translates embedded SQL into calls to the Oracle runtime library.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Pro*C",
            "b) ORM",
            "c) ApexSQL",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Oracle Pro*C is a set of APIs supplied by Oracle to query, insert, update, or delete records in an Oracle database from C applications."
    },
    {
        "id": 422,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compared to LINQ to Entities, LINQ to SQL has more limitations",
            "b) MSL stands for Map Schema Language",
            "c) If you want to work against a conceptual data model, use LINQ to Entities",
            "d) Conceptual Data Model feature is present in LINQ to SQL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  For direct mapping to the database from your programming languages, use LINQ to SQL."
    },
    {
        "id": 423,
        "Question": "DataContext object is constructed in LINQ to SQL using _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) NorthwindDataContext db = new malloc NorthwindDataContext();",
            "b) NorthwindDataContext db = new NorthwindDataContext();",
            "c) NorthwindDataContext db = new NorthwindData();",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To query a database using LINQ to SQL, we first need to construct a DataContext object."
    },
    {
        "id": 424,
        "Question": "Which of the following method is used to delete records in LINQ?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DeleteOn",
            "b) Delete",
            "c) DeleteOnSubmit",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: LINQ provides much more flexibility of select single item/row from database table like ‘DBNameDataContext’."
    },
    {
        "id": 425,
        "Question": "Service broker was added to SQL Server ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2000",
            "b) 2005",
            "c) 2008",
            "d) 2012"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Service Broker in Microsoft SQL Server 2005 is a new technology that provides messaging and queuing functions between instances."
    },
    {
        "id": 426,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Loosely coupled applications are supported by the Service broker",
            "b) Each Service Broker conversation is considered to be a dialog where only participants are involved",
            "c) Service broker find applications when a single SQL server instance is used",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Programs that exchange messages independently) are supported by the Service broker."
    },
    {
        "id": 427,
        "Question": "There are _________ components of the Service broker in SQL Server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The three components of the Service broker are as follows: conversation components, service definition components and networking and security components."
    },
    {
        "id": 428,
        "Question": "Which of the following service broker component defines the infrastructure used for exchanging messages between instances?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Conversation",
            "b) Service definition",
            "c) Security",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Networking and security components defines the infrastructure used for exchanging messages between instances."
    },
    {
        "id": 429,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The developers can design applications from independent components known as “services”",
            "b) The maintenance of the Service Broker is difficult",
            "c) Maintenance of Service Broker is a part of the routine database",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The maintenance of Service Broker is easy because it forms a part of the Database Engine."
    },
    {
        "id": 430,
        "Question": "Service Broker also provides security by preventing __________ access from networks and by message encryption.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Authorized",
            "b) Read",
            "c) Unauthorized",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Service broker is essential component for security of database."
    },
    {
        "id": 431,
        "Question": "(SSBS) is a new architecture which allows you to write ____________ message based application.",
        "Options": [
            "a) asynchronous",
            "b) decoupled",
            "c) distributed",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SQL Server Service Broker (SSBS), introduced with SQL Server 2005 allows you to write queuing/message based applications within the database itself."
    },
    {
        "id": 432,
        "Question": "Which of the following change was introduced in SQL Server 2012 related to Service Broker?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Less support for Service Broker",
            "b) Queues do not expose the message enqueued time",
            "c) Messages can be sent to multiple target services (multicast)",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Queues have a new column, message_enqueue_time, that shows how long a message has been in the queue."
    },
    {
        "id": 433,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a Service Broker Related Dynamic Management View?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sys.dm_broker_activated",
            "b) sys.dm_broker_activated_tasks",
            "c) sys.dm_broker_tasks",
            "d) dm_broker_activated_tasks"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sys.dm_broker_activated_tasks returns a row for each stored procedure activated by Service Broker."
    },
    {
        "id": 434,
        "Question": "Which of the utility is used for reporting the issue in Service Broker?",
        "Options": [
            "a) diagnose",
            "b) ssiagnose",
            "c) ssbdiagnose",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The ssbdiagnose utility reports issues in Service Broker conversations or the configuration of Service Broker services."
    },
    {
        "id": 435,
        "Question": "___________ is a set of technologies for copying and distributing data and database objects from one database to another.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Replication",
            "b) Database Mirroring",
            "c) Log Shipping",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  Using replication, you can distribute data to different locations and to remote or mobile users over local and wide area networks."
    },
    {
        "id": 436,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Transactional replication is typically used in server-to-server",
            "b) Transactional replication is typically used in client-to-server",
            "c) Transactional replication is typically used in client-to-client",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  Transactional replication is used in scenarios that require high throughput, including improving scalability and availability."
    },
    {
        "id": 437,
        "Question": "How many types of replication is provided by SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Microsoft SQL Server provides three types of replication for use in distributed applications."
    },
    {
        "id": 438,
        "Question": "Replication in SQL Server is used to overcome ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Performance problems",
            "b) Availability problems",
            "c) Maintenance problems",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Replication allows us to maintain the same database multiple copies at different locations."
    },
    {
        "id": 439,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Log shipping and mirroring allows to maintain complete database redundancy",
            "b) Replication allows to maintain some part of the database (a set of required objects) at users location",
            "c) Replication is object level low availability feature",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Replicate doesn’t distribute entire database, but only distributes some part of database like tables or views ensuring high availability feature."
    },
    {
        "id": 440,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a disadvantage of replication?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Improved performance",
            "b) To move data closer to the user",
            "c) Easy maintenance",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In SQL Server 2005, replication had to be stopped in order to perform some actions like adding nodes, making schema changes, etc. But in 2008, these can be done online."
    },
    {
        "id": 441,
        "Question": "Which of the following stored procedure provide replication support for AlwaysOn?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_validate_replica_publishers",
            "b) sp_validate_hosts_as_publishers",
            "c) sp_validate_replica_hosts_as_publishers",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Four new stored procedures provide replication support for AlwaysOn."
    },
    {
        "id": 442,
        "Question": "How many types of replication components are present in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6",
            "b) 7",
            "c) 8",
            "d) 9"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SQL Server replication is based on the “Publish and Subscribe” metaphor."
    },
    {
        "id": 443,
        "Question": "Which of the following makes data available for replication?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Article",
            "b) Publisher",
            "c) Distributor",
            "d) Subscription"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Publisher is a source database where replication starts."
    },
    {
        "id": 444,
        "Question": "Two types of subscriptions present for replication is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) push and pull",
            "b) throw and pull",
            "c) push and throw",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Push subscriptions are created at the Publisher server and pull subscriptions initiates the replication instead of the publisher."
    },
    {
        "id": 445,
        "Question": "SSMS provides different options to develop your SSIS package starting with ___________ wizard.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Import and Export",
            "b) Copy and Import",
            "c) Export and BulkInsert",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: With SSIS wizards, we can create a structure on how the data flow should happen and make a package and deploy it based on our needs to execute in any environment."
    },
    {
        "id": 446,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Prior to SSIS, Data Transformation Services (DTS) in SQL Server 2000 performs the tasks with fewer features",
            "b) SSIS is used to perform operations like loading the data based on the need, performing different transformations on the data like doing calculations",
            "c) Business Intelligence Development Studio (BIDS) is a tool which can be used to develop only SSIS packages",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  BIDS is available with SQL Server as an interface that provides the developers to work on the workflow of the process that can be made step by step."
    },
    {
        "id": 447,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the best practice related to SSIS?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Plan for capacity by understanding resource utilization",
            "b) SSIS is an in-memory pipeline, so ensure that all transformations occur in memory",
            "c) Baseline source system extract speed",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server Integration Services is designed to process large amounts of data row by row in memory with high speed. Because of this, it is important to understand resource utilization, i.e., the CPU, memory, I/O, and network utilization of your packages."
    },
    {
        "id": 448,
        "Question": "If SSIS is not able to drive close to 100% CPU load, this may be indicative of ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Software Contention",
            "b) Application contention",
            "c) Processor contention",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In Application contention, SQL Server is taking on more processor resources, making them unavailable to SSIS."
    },
    {
        "id": 449,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SSIS moves data as fast as your network is able to handle it",
            "b) It is important to understand your network topology and ensure that the path between your source and target have both low latency and high throughput",
            "c) Integration Services can be tuned beyond the speed of your source",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You cannot transform data faster than you can read it in SSIS."
    },
    {
        "id": 450,
        "Question": "The key counters for Integration Services and SQL Server are _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process Bytes",
            "b) Public Bytes",
            "c) Private Set",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Process byte is the amount of memory currently in use by Integration Services. This memory cannot be shared with other processes."
    },
    {
        "id": 451,
        "Question": "_________ represents to total memory pressure on the system in SSIS.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Page sec",
            "b) Page Reads",
            "c) Memory reads",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: If page reads consistently goes above 500, the system is under memory pressure."
    },
    {
        "id": 452,
        "Question": "The following Network perfom counters can help you tune your topology?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Total Bandwidth",
            "b) Current Bandwidth",
            "c) Bandwidth bound",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Current Bandwidth counter provides an estimate of current bandwidth."
    },
    {
        "id": 453,
        "Question": "What do you understand by design limitation in SSIS package?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Making use of parallelism",
            "b) Not making use of parallelism",
            "c) Package uses few single-threaded tasks",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  The design limitation of SSIS package is not making use of parallelism."
    },
    {
        "id": 454,
        "Question": "___________ represents how many network transfers per second are occurring.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Network Bytes",
            "b) Network Transfers",
            "c) Memory reads",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If Network Transfers/sec is approaching 40,000 IOPs, then get another NIC card and use teaming between the NIC cards."
    },
    {
        "id": 455,
        "Question": "Which of the following will increase the Rows/sec calculation in SSIS?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Improve drivers and driver configurations",
            "b) Start single connections",
            "c) Use single NIC cards",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Make sure you are using the most up-to-date driver configurations for your network, data source, and disk I/O."
    },
    {
        "id": 456,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) If the network is your bottleneck, then a potential solution is to use a single NIC card per server",
            "b) To overcome the limitations of drivers, you can try to start multiple connections to your data source",
            "c) For 64-bit systems, at design time you may be loading 32-bit drivers; ensure that at run time you are using 32-bit drivers",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: As long as the source can handle many concurrent connections, you may see an increase in throughput if you start several extracts at once."
    },
    {
        "id": 457,
        "Question": "When you execute SQL statements within Integration Services, the following optimization can be made?",
        "Options": [
            "a) If Integration Services and SQL Server run on the different server, use the SQL Server destination instead of the OLE DB destination to improve performance",
            "b) In SQL Server 2008 Integration Services, there is a new feature of the shared lookup cache",
            "c) If you cannot use commit size 1, use the highest possible value of commit size to reduce the overhead of multiple-batch writing",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When using parallel pipelines (see points #8 and #10 below), it provides a high-speed, shared cache."
    },
    {
        "id": 458,
        "Question": "Which of the following steps should be carried out using data types in SSIS for efficient results?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Make data types as wide as possible so you will allocate more memory for your transformation",
            "b) Do not perform excessive casting of data types",
            "c) Do not watch precision issues when using the money, float, and decimal types",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Excessive casting of data types it will only degrade performance. Match your data types to the source or destination and explicitly specify the necessary data type casting."
    },
    {
        "id": 459,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Heap inserts are typically slower than using a clustered index",
            "b) Use partitions and partition SWITCH command; i.e., load a work table that contains a single partition and SWITCH it into the main table after you build the indexes and put the constraints on",
            "c) Use the NOLOCK or TABLOCK hints to remove locking overhead",
            "d) Use a commit size of <5000 to avoid lock escalation when inserting; note that in SQL Server 2008 you can now enable/disable lock escalation at the object level, but use this wisely"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For using Heap inserts, you may want to drop indexes and rebuild if you are changing a large part of the destination table; you will want to test your inserts both by keeping indexes in place and by dropping all indexes and rebuilding to validate."
    },
    {
        "id": 460,
        "Question": "Which of the following error message indicates that the package cannot run in SSIS?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DTS_E_CANTINSERTCOLUMNTYPE",
            "b) DTS_E_CACHELOADEDFROMFILE",
            "c) DTS_E_CANNOTCONVERTBETWEENUNICODEANDNONUNICODESTRINGCOLUMN",
            "d) DTS_E_CONNECTIONREQUIREDFORMETADATA"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Cache Transform transformation is trying to write data to the in-memory cache."
    },
    {
        "id": 461,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the event logged by the Integration Services?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQLISService_255",
            "b) SQLISService_256",
            "c) SQLISService_155",
            "d) SQLISService_156"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQLISService_256 event indicates that the service is about to start."
    },
    {
        "id": 462,
        "Question": "Purpose of SQLISPackage_12546 event in SQLIS package is to _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Indicate that a package started",
            "b) Indicate that a task or other executable in a package has finished its work",
            "c) Indicate that a warning message was raised in a package",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQLISPackage_12288 indicates that a package started."
    },
    {
        "id": 463,
        "Question": "A basic package in SSIS includes the following elements?",
        "Options": [
            "a) T-SQL flow elements",
            "b) Control flow elements",
            "c) DataSet flow statements",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Control flow elements perform various functions, provide structure and control the order in which elements run."
    },
    {
        "id": 464,
        "Question": "Which of the following evaluation operation is provided in SSIS?",
        "Options": [
            "a) A constraint that uses only the execution result of the precedence executable to determine whether the constrained executable runs",
            "b) An expression that is evaluated to determine whether the constrained executable runs",
            "c) An expression and a constraint that combines the requirements of execution results of the precedence executable",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The expression must be a valid SSIS expression, and it can include functions, operators, and system and custom variables."
    },
    {
        "id": 465,
        "Question": "The __________ is an Access add-in program that provides data analysis tools for financial analysis.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Analysis ToolPak",
            "b) Analysis Tool",
            "c) Analysis ToolSQL",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Analysis ToolPak is used for complex, statistical analyses."
    },
    {
        "id": 466,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SSMS for Access converts Access database objects to SQL Server or SQL Azure database object",
            "b) Use the CONVERSION page of the Project Settings dialog box to specify how much data appears on the Data tab",
            "c) SSMA for Access converts Access database objects to SQL Server or SQL Azure database object",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SSMA loads those objects into SQL Server or SQL Azure, and then migrates data from Access to SQL Server or SQL Azure. "
    },
    {
        "id": 467,
        "Question": "When you _______ an Access table from a SQL Server, SSMA restores the original Access table and its data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) link",
            "b) unlink",
            "c) import",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If you have linked the Access tables to one SQL Server instance, and then you want to change the links to another instance, you must relink the tables."
    },
    {
        "id": 468,
        "Question": "__________ is a tool for migrating databases from Microsoft Access versions 97 through 2010 to Microsoft SQL Server 2005.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SSAM",
            "b) SSMA",
            "c) SSMS",
            "d) SSAS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SSMA stands for Microsoft SQL Server Migration Assistant for Access. "
    },
    {
        "id": 469,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server Migration Assistant is an environment that helps you quickly migrate Access databases to SQL Server or SQL Azure",
            "b) By using SSMA, you can review Access and SQL Server or SQL Azure database objects",
            "c) When you link an Access table to a SQL Server, SQL Server database engine stores connection information and table metadata",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Jet database engine stores connection information and table metadata."
    },
    {
        "id": 470,
        "Question": "Which is the most serious issue after migration of access database to SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Auto-increment columns are not updated until the record is updated",
            "b) Slow performance with linked tables",
            "c) New records are not available",
            "d) You cannot modify a linked table schema with Access"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  Some queries might be slow after upsizing."
    },
    {
        "id": 471,
        "Question": "Which of the following option is used to find database objects by using filter criteria?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Advanced Object Select dialog box",
            "b) Advanced find Select dialog box",
            "c) Advanced filter Select dialog box",
            "d) Advanced Object and filter Select dialog box"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Advanced Object Select dialog box first uses filter criteria to search for objects."
    },
    {
        "id": 472,
        "Question": "Which of the following change took place in JULY 2014 release of SSMA?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Added support of MS SQL Server 2014",
            "b) Set cascade actions for circular references to No Action",
            "c) Fixed bugs regarding invisible report pages in IE 10",
            "d) Highlighting of “well known” LOB schemas"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: This change was done so that they can be ignored in conversion."
    },
    {
        "id": 473,
        "Question": "_________ shows information about Access databases that have been added to the project.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server Metadata Explorer",
            "b) Access Metadata Explorer",
            "c) Access Metadata Expl",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SSMA contains two metadata explorers to browse and perform actions on Access and SQL Server or Azure SQL DB databases."
    },
    {
        "id": 474,
        "Question": "Which of the following network protocol should be selected to enable IP address?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Udp",
            "b) Named pipes",
            "c) Tcp",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You must restart the SQL Server service after making changes to network protocols."
    },
    {
        "id": 475,
        "Question": "Which of the following tools is used for enterprise information management?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SSAS",
            "b) SSIS",
            "c) SSRS",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SSAS, SSIS and SSRS are part of SQL Server Business Intelligence flagship product."
    },
    {
        "id": 476,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SSIS provides a powerful, extensible platform for integrating data from various sources",
            "b) DQS provides a central data hub that ensures that the integrity of information and consistency of data is constant across different applications",
            "c) MDS enables you to cleanse, match, standardize, and enrich data, so you can deliver trusted information for business intelligence, a data warehouse, and transaction processing workloads",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS) is a component of the Microsoft SQL Server database software that can be used to perform a broad range of data migration tasks."
    },
    {
        "id": 477,
        "Question": "Which of the following SQL Server tools is used to enhance data management and governance?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SSIT",
            "b) SSDT",
            "c) OBEII",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SSDT stands for SQL Server Data Tools and is available for data management and quality."
    },
    {
        "id": 478,
        "Question": "Which is the more preferred way tool of effective data management strategy and decision making?",
        "Options": [
            "a) BIDS",
            "b) SSMS",
            "c) Excel",
            "d) SSRS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer:  a\nExplanation: Business Intelligence Development Studio (BIDS) is the former IDE from Microsoft, and was used to develop data analysis and Business Intelligence solutions."
    },
    {
        "id": 479,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Spotlight is quality tool for SQL Server Enterprise",
            "b) The BIDS paradigm for developing reports is based on the concept of distributed queries",
            "c) GeoFlow is data management tool for SQL Server",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The BIDS paradigm for developing reports is based on the concept of projects and solutions."
    },
    {
        "id": 480,
        "Question": "Key component that help you build an EIM solution is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SSRS",
            "b) SSAS",
            "c) SSIS",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS) is a component of the Microsoft SQL Server database software that can be used to perform a broad range of data migration task."
    },
    {
        "id": 481,
        "Question": "Which of the following data tools comes installed with SQL Server 2012?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SSAS",
            "b) SSRS",
            "c) DQS",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  SQL Server data tools includes SSAS and SSRS."
    },
    {
        "id": 482,
        "Question": "Which of the following action cannot be performed with MDS?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Create entities",
            "b) Create attributes for your entities",
            "c) Export members for your supporting entities",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Begin populating your master data by using the staging process. You may want to start by importing the members for your supporting entities."
    },
    {
        "id": 483,
        "Question": "Creation of  a Derived Hierarchy requires permission to ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) System Administration",
            "b) DQS",
            "c) syschema",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In Master Data Services, create a derived hierarchy when you want a level-based hierarchy that ensures that members exist at the correct level."
    },
    {
        "id": 484,
        "Question": "Users need _________ permission to create collection model object in MDS.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Delete",
            "b) Create",
            "c) Update",
            "d) Read"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Users can create collections in Master Data Manager if they have a minimum of Update permission to the collection model object and access to the Explorer functional area."
    },
    {
        "id": 485,
        "Question": "Policy based management views are present in _________ database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Master",
            "b) Msdb",
            "c) Tempdb",
            "d) Model"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Policy-Based Management has views for displaying information about Policy-Based Management policies."
    },
    {
        "id": 486,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement related to database configuration.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Enable Data File Growth for all the Databases Using Policy Based Management",
            "b) Monitor Your SQL Server Linked Server Configurations with Policy Based Management",
            "c) Configuring Alerts for SQL Server Policy Based Management",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Data File Growth is related to database configuration."
    },
    {
        "id": 487,
        "Question": "Which of the following is policy based management tip related to administration?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Evaluate and Implement Policies in Multiple SQL Server Instances",
            "b) Identify SQL Server Databases Not in Full Recovery Model",
            "c) SQL Server Policy Based Management Has Clustered Index Condition",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Policy-Based Management is a system for managing one or more instances of SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 488,
        "Question": "Which of the following is Policy-based management view?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sys_policies",
            "b) syspolicy_policies",
            "c) syspolicy",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: syspolicy_policies displays one row for each Policy-Based Management policy in the instance of SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 489,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) When SQL Server policy administrators use Policy-Based Management, they use SQL Server Management Studio",
            "b) SQL server has introduced policy management framework in 2005",
            "c) SQL policy administrator uses SQL Server Management Studio to create policies that can handle entities on the server side like the SQL Server objects",
            "d) MS SQL Server 2008 provides a very important feature for policy based administration"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQL server 2008 has introduced policy management framework, which is the latest technique for SQL server database engine."
    },
    {
        "id": 490,
        "Question": "Policy based management view is owned by _______ schema.",
        "Options": [
            "a) dbo",
            "b) db",
            "c) dbos",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: All policy based views are owned by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 491,
        "Question": "Which of the following column is a part of syspolicy_policies result?",
        "Options": [
            "a) name",
            "b) root_condition_id",
            "c) date_created",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: root_condition_id gives the ID of the condition enforced or tested by this policy."
    },
    {
        "id": 492,
        "Question": "How many types of execution mode are present in syspolicy_policies?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  Various execution modes are 0, 1, 2 and 4."
    },
    {
        "id": 493,
        "Question": "____________ displays the condition expressions that were executed.",
        "Options": [
            "a) syspolicy_policy_execution",
            "b) syspolicy_policy_execution_history_details",
            "c) syspolicy_policy_execution_history",
            "d) syspolicy_policy_group_subscriptions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: syspolicy_policy_execution_history_details displays the condition expressions that were executed, the targets of the expressions, the result of each execution, and details about errors if any occurred. "
    },
    {
        "id": 494,
        "Question": "Purpose of syspolicy_system_health_state in policy based management is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Displays one row for each Policy-Based Management policy",
            "b) Organize policies when you have many policies",
            "c) Displays the time when policies were executed, the result of each execution, and details about errors if any occurred",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Use the syspolicy_system_health_state view to programmatically check the policy health of the server."
    },
    {
        "id": 495,
        "Question": "SQL Server backup and restore operations occur within the context of the _______ model of the database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) backup",
            "b) recovery",
            "c) restore",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  A recovery model is a database property that controls how transactions are logged."
    },
    {
        "id": 496,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Backup models are designed to control transaction log maintenance",
            "b) Restore models are designed to control transaction log maintenance",
            "c) Recovery models are designed to control transaction log maintenance",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Recovery Model is one of the mechanisms which controls and manages the growth of the transaction log file."
    },
    {
        "id": 497,
        "Question": "How many types of recovery model is provided by SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Three recovery models exist: simple, full, and bulk-logged."
    },
    {
        "id": 498,
        "Question": "No log backups is a feature of __________ recovery model.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Simple",
            "b) Full",
            "c) Bulk-logged",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Simple recovery model is the simplest of all and maintains only a minimum amount of information in the SQL Server transaction log file."
    },
    {
        "id": 499,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Managing databases with simple recovery model is much easier",
            "b) Managing databases with full recovery model is much easier",
            "c) Managing databases with bulk-logged recovery model is much easier",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Manageability with Simple recovery model is much easier–no need to take transactional backups."
    },
    {
        "id": 500,
        "Question": "Which of the following feature cannot be used in simple recovery mode?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Media recovery without data loss",
            "b) Log shipping",
            "c) Database mirroring",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Operations that require transaction log backups are not supported by the simple recovery model."
    },
    {
        "id": 501,
        "Question": "Which of the following recovery models requires log backups?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Simple",
            "b) Full",
            "c) Bulk",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In full recovery model, no work is lost due to a lost or damaged data file and it can even recover to an arbitrary point in time."
    },
    {
        "id": 502,
        "Question": "How many types of backups you can run when the data is in the “Full” recovery model?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) 6",
            "c) 7",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Six backups if full recovery model are Complete backup, Differential backup, File and/or Filegroup backup, Partial backup, Copy-Only backup, Transaction log backup."
    },
    {
        "id": 503,
        "Question": "The _______ recovery model is a special-purpose model that works in a similar manner to the full recovery model.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Simple",
            "b) Full",
            "c) bulk-logged",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Full Recovery and Bulk-Logged Recovery models provide the greatest protection for data."
    },
    {
        "id": 504,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is used for changing Recovery Model with T-SQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER DATABASE",
            "b) ALTER TABLE",
            "c) ALTER COLUMN",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can use ALTER DATABASE command with the SET RECOVERY option to change the recovery model of a database."
    },
    {
        "id": 505,
        "Question": "Backing up your SQL Server database is essential for _______ your data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) protecting",
            "b) preventing",
            "c) replication",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server offers many options for creating backups."
    },
    {
        "id": 506,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Using differential backups can save available space",
            "b) Using full backups can save available space",
            "c) Using partial backups can save available space",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Using differential backups can save available space and speed up the process of making frequent backups to decrease the risk of data loss."
    },
    {
        "id": 507,
        "Question": "How many types of backups are provided by SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) 6",
            "c) 7",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: DatabaseBackup is the SQL Server Maintenance Solution’s stored procedure for backing up databases."
    },
    {
        "id": 508,
        "Question": "Features provided by SQL Server backups include ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Wire compression of data for optimal backup and restore time",
            "b) Supports full and transaction log style backups",
            "c) Backup of MS SQL Server databases without interrupting running MS SQL Server services",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Secure and automated backup of your company’s databases with no downtime; easy to deploy and administer."
    },
    {
        "id": 509,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server 2003 Enterprise and later versions support compressing backups",
            "b) SQL Server 2008 Enterprise and later versions support compressing backups",
            "c) SQL Server 2000 Enterprise and later versions support compressing backups",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  DatabaseBackup is supported on SQL Server 2005, SQL Server 2008, SQL Server 2008 R2, SQL Server 2012, and SQL Server 2014."
    },
    {
        "id": 510,
        "Question": "Backup can occur while the database is in ___________ state.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Online",
            "b) Offline",
            "c) Restoring",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Offline Data Cannot Be Backed Up."
    },
    {
        "id": 511,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a type of backup?",
        "Options": [
            "a) database backup",
            "b) data backup",
            "c) table backup",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In order to select a proper SQL Server backup type, a SQL Server administrator needs to understand the difference between the major backup."
    },
    {
        "id": 512,
        "Question": "_________ backups represent the whole database at the time the backup finished.",
        "Options": [
            "a) copy-only backup",
            "b) database backup",
            "c) data backup",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  Differential database backups contain only changes made to the database since its most recent full database backup."
    },
    {
        "id": 513,
        "Question": "Which of the following backups contain transaction logs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) copy-only backup",
            "b) database backup",
            "c) data backup",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Log backup includes backup of transaction logs that includes all log records that were not backed up in a previous log backup."
    },
    {
        "id": 514,
        "Question": "____________ contains data from only some of the filegroups in a database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) copy-only backup",
            "b) database backup",
            "c) data backup",
            "d) partial"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Partial backups consist of data in the primary filegroup, every read/write filegroup and any optionally-specified read-only files."
    },
    {
        "id": 515,
        "Question": "The SQL Server Maintenance Solution comprises scripts for running __________ maintenance on all editions of Microsoft SQL Server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) backups",
            "b) integrity checks",
            "c) index",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The solution is based on stored procedures, the sqlcmd utility, and SQL Server Agent jobs."
    },
    {
        "id": 516,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement related to database maintenance.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Performing SQL Server Maintenance with Maintenance Window",
            "b) Performing SQL Server Maintenance with No Maintenance Window",
            "c) Performing SQL Server Maintenance with Scrip Maintenance Window",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When the production SQL Server is running on a 24X7 basis or the maintenance window is not long enough to support the maintenance."
    },
    {
        "id": 517,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used to determine the fragmentation for tables and indexes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DBCC SHOWCONTIG",
            "b) DBCC CHECKDB",
            "c) DBCC CHECKCATALOG",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In SQL Server 2005 DBCC SHOWCONTIG remains a viable short term option to determine the database fragmentation."
    },
    {
        "id": 518,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used to Validate the database objects?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DBCC SHOWCONTIG",
            "b) DBCC CHECKDB",
            "c) DBCC CATALOG",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: DBCC CHECKDB is supported on databases that contain memory-optimized tables but validation only occurs on disk-based tables."
    },
    {
        "id": 519,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The command DBCC CHECKDB checks the logical and physical integrity of all the objects in the specified database",
            "b) The command DBCC CHECK checks the logical and physical integrity of all the objects in the specified database",
            "c) The command CHECKDB checks the logical and physical integrity of all the objects in the specified database",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  DBCC CHECKDB has some performance quirks based on the schema of the database being checked."
    },
    {
        "id": 520,
        "Question": "Which of the following command defragments clustered and secondary indexes of the specified table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DBCC SHOWCONTIG",
            "b) DBCC CHECKDB",
            "c) DBCC CATALOG",
            "d) DBCC INDEXDEFRAG"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: DBCC INDEXDEFRAG is an online operation, so it does not hold long-term locks that can block running queries or updates."
    },
    {
        "id": 521,
        "Question": "______________ runs UPDATE STATISTICS against all user-defined tables in the current database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_updatestats",
            "b) DBCC CHECKDB",
            "c) DBCC CATALOG",
            "d) DBCC INDEXDEFRAG"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: sp_updatestats updates all statistics for all tables in the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 522,
        "Question": "Purpose of DBCC DBREINDEX command is to ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Rebuilds one or more indexes for a table in the specified database",
            "b) Rebuilds only one index for a table in the specified database",
            "c) Displays fragmentation information for the data and indexes of the specified table",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The DBCC DBREINDEX command will not automatically rebuild all of the indexes on all the tables in a database; it can only work on one table at a time."
    },
    {
        "id": 523,
        "Question": "What types of database maintenance should be executed?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Update SQL Server’s usage",
            "b) Validate the database objects and system catalogs are free of corruption",
            "c) Determine the fragmentation for tables and indexes",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The SQL Server Maintenance Solution comprises scripts for running backups, integrity checks, and index and statistics maintenance on all editions of Microsoft SQL Server 2005, SQL Server 2008, SQL Server 2008 R2, SQL Server 2012, and SQL Server 2014."
    },
    {
        "id": 524,
        "Question": "Create a Database Maintenance Plan that creates a ________ backup within SQL Server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Partial",
            "b) Snapshot",
            "c) Full",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Creating a full backup is a minimum recommendation for good database maintenance."
    },
    {
        "id": 525,
        "Question": "__________ is a Microsoft Windows service that executes scheduled administrative tasks, which are called jobs in SQL Server 2014.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Log shipping",
            "b) Task",
            "c) Agent",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The SQL Server Agent is a service that lets you configure scheduled tasks and system alerts."
    },
    {
        "id": 526,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server Agent uses SQL Server to store job information",
            "b) SQL Server Agent can run a job on a schedule",
            "c) By default, the SQL Server Agent service is disabled when SQL Server 2014 is installed",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SQL Server Agent runs continuously in the background as a Windows Service."
    },
    {
        "id": 527,
        "Question": "SQL Server Agent consist of _____ component.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  SQL Server Agent consist of jobs,alerts and operators."
    },
    {
        "id": 528,
        "Question": "SQL Agent Job definitions are specified in which database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) msdb",
            "b) master",
            "c) tempdb",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: msdb is a system database that is created when you first install SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 529,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server Log shipping allows you to automate a variety of administrative task",
            "b) SQL Server task manager allows you to automate a variety of administrative task",
            "c) SQL Server Agent allows you to automate a variety of administrative task",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SQL Server Agent is used to create and schedule a job that automates database administration."
    },
    {
        "id": 530,
        "Question": "_________start and stop the SQL Server Agent Service .",
        "Options": [
            "a) SSMS",
            "b) Windows Services console",
            "c) QL Server Service Manager",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Open up Microsoft SQL Server Configuration Manager and locate the SQL Server Agent service. If the status of that service is “RUNNING”, you do not need to do anything."
    },
    {
        "id": 531,
        "Question": "Which of the following condition is considered for schedule?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Whenever SQL Server Agent starts",
            "b) On a recurring schedule",
            "c) SQL Server performance conditions",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: A schedule specifies when a job runs."
    },
    {
        "id": 532,
        "Question": "An alert can respond to one of the following conditions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Whenever SQL Server Agent starts",
            "b) On a recurring schedule",
            "c) SQL Server performance conditions",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: An alert is an automatic response to a specific event. For example, an event can be a job that starts or system resources that reach a specific threshold."
    },
    {
        "id": 533,
        "Question": "SQL Server can notify operators of alerts through ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) E-mail",
            "b) Net send",
            "c) Pager",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: An operator defines contact information for an individual responsible for the maintenance of one or more instances of SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 534,
        "Question": "Which of the following members has access to SQL Server Agent?",
        "Options": [
            "a) members of the systemadmin",
            "b) members of the sysadmin",
            "c) members of the sysadministraion",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Members of the SQLAgentUserRole, SQLAgentReaderRole, and SQLAgentOperatorRole fixed database roles in msdb, and members of the sysadmin fixed server role have access to SQL Server Agent."
    },
    {
        "id": 535,
        "Question": "Which of the following wizard provides creation logins on the destination server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Copy Database",
            "b) Move Database",
            "c) Detach database",
            "d) Attach database"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The Copy Database Wizard lets you move or copy databases and their objects easily from one server to another."
    },
    {
        "id": 536,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) After a database has been upgraded, it cannot be downgraded to a previous version",
            "b) The Copy Database Wizard is available in the Express edition",
            "c) The Copy Database Wizard cannot be used to copy  System databases",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  System databases cannot be transferred using Copy database wizard."
    },
    {
        "id": 537,
        "Question": "How many ways are provided by SQL Server to copy a database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  SQL Server provides mainly three ways to copy a database."
    },
    {
        "id": 538,
        "Question": "Which is not the preferred way of copying a database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Using the Copy Database Wizard",
            "b) Restoring a database backup",
            "c) Using the Generate Scripts Wizard to publish databases",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Generate script wizard produces unnecessary computation internally to copy a database."
    },
    {
        "id": 539,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement related to the use of Copy database wizard.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Pick a source and destination server",
            "b) System stored procedures",
            "c) Schedule when to move or copy the databases",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Copy database wizard copies additional supporting objects, jobs, user-defined stored procedures, and error messages."
    },
    {
        "id": 540,
        "Question": "Which of the following returns a list of the database and log files?",
        "Options": [
            "a) RESTORE FILELISTON",
            "b) RESTORE FILELIST",
            "c) RESTORE FILELISTONLY",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A client can use RESTORE FILELISTONLY to obtain a list of the files contained in a backup set. This information is returned as a result set containing one row for each file."
    },
    {
        "id": 541,
        "Question": "Which of the following transfer method makes the database unavailable to users during the transfer?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Detach and attach method",
            "b) SQL Management Object method",
            "c) Restore method",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Detach the database from the source server, copy the database files to the destination server, and attach the database at the destination server."
    },
    {
        "id": 542,
        "Question": "Which of the following stored procedure is used for detachment of database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_replicationdboption",
            "b) sp_replicationdb",
            "c) sp_replicationoption",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If you cannot use sp_replicationdboption, you can remove replication by running sp_removedbreplication."
    },
    {
        "id": 543,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Snapshots can be used in conjunction with database mirroring for reporting purposes",
            "b) A snapshot is write-only, static view of a database",
            "c) A snapshot is read-only, dynamic view of a database",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Creating a snapshot requires specifying the logical name of every database file of the source database."
    },
    {
        "id": 544,
        "Question": "Which of the following scenario prefers not to use database snapshots?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Database Snapshots should be seen as high availability option",
            "b) Database Snapshots should not be seen as an alternative to regular backups of your data",
            "c) Snapshots can be created very quickly",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can create a database snapshots on the mirror database and direct client connection requests to the most recent snapshot."
    },
    {
        "id": 545,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) You cannot used SQL Server Management Studio for creating a database snapshots",
            "b) Snapshots have to be created using T-SQL",
            "c) All recovery models support database snapshot",
            "d) A database can have one and only one snapshot"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A snapshot database always have an entry in sys.databases.source_database_id."
    },
    {
        "id": 546,
        "Question": "To revert the database, which of the following Transact-SQL statement is used?",
        "Options": [
            "a) RESTORE Snapshot <database_name> FROM DATABASE_SNAPSHOT = <database_snapshot_name>",
            "b) RESTORE DATABASE <database_name> FROM DATABASE_SNAPSHOT = <database_snapshot_name>",
            "c) REST DATABASE <database_name> FROM DATABASE_SNAPSHOT = <database_snapshot_name>",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Snapshot of master database should be created explicitly using SSMS."
    },
    {
        "id": 547,
        "Question": "Which of the following message comes when you try to update or delete the data snapshot?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Row Deletion",
            "b) The row was committed",
            "c) Row has been updated",
            "d) Failed to update the database"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Back up the reverted database, especially if it uses the full (or bulk-logged) recovery model."
    },
    {
        "id": 548,
        "Question": "Syntax for creating database snapshot in SQL Server is _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP DATABASE [snapshottest];",
            "b) DELETE DATABASE [snapshottest];",
            "c) DROP Snapshot [snapshottest];",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You will receive a read only message because snapshots have read-only tables."
    },
    {
        "id": 549,
        "Question": "What should be done to check to see if data still exists in the Snapshot?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Run Delete on Database Snapshot",
            "b) Run Update on Database Snapshot",
            "c) Run Select on Database Snapshot",
            "d) Run Insert on Database Snapshot"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: We drop the snapshot database like any other database using drop database command."
    },
    {
        "id": 550,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the instance of SQL Server that is your production server in log shipping?",
        "Options": [
            "a) secondary database",
            "b) primary database",
            "c) secondary server",
            "d) primary server"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Once the monitor server has been configured, it cannot be changed without removing log shipping first."
    },
    {
        "id": 551,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The restore job can be delayed until all users disconnect themselves",
            "b) Log shipping cannot be combined with other disaster recovery options such as AlwaysOn Availability Groups",
            "c) SQL Server log shipping has high cost in human",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The database is not available only while the restore process is running."
    },
    {
        "id": 552,
        "Question": "In which of the following modes, the database is read-only?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stand by",
            "b) Read only",
            "c) Restore mode",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are two available modes and they are related to the state in which the secondary, log shipped."
    },
    {
        "id": 553,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The principal database in a mirroring session can also act as the primary database in a log shipping",
            "b) Log Shipping is comparatively tougher than database mirroring for setup",
            "c) The database log shipping setup needs to be initiated from the principal server using the SQL Server Management Studio wizard",
            "d) A given database can be mirrored or log shipped; it can also be simultaneously mirrored and log shipped"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Make sure your database is in full or bulk-logged recovery model."
    },
    {
        "id": 554,
        "Question": "Which of the following stored procedure is used to add a primary database on primary server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_add_log_shipping_primary_database",
            "b) sp_add_primary_database",
            "c) sp_add_log_shipping",
            "d) sp_add_log_shipping_primary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Log Shipping is a pretty simple process to setup."
    },
    {
        "id": 555,
        "Question": "Execute sp_add_jobschedule to add a schedule for the backup job on _________ server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) primary",
            "b) secondary",
            "c) primary and secondary",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  sp_add_log_shipping_primary_database stored procedure returns the backup job ID and primary ID."
    },
    {
        "id": 556,
        "Question": "Which of the following table stores history detail for log shipping jobs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) log_shipping_monitor_alert",
            "b) log_shipping_monitor_primary",
            "c) log_shipping_monitor_history_detail",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sp_add_log_shipping_secondary_primary sets up the primary information, adds local and remote monitor links, and creates copy and restore jobs on the secondary server for the specified primary database."
    },
    {
        "id": 557,
        "Question": "_____________  maps primary databases to secondary databases in log shipping.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_change_log_shipping_primary_database",
            "b) log_shipping_primary_databases",
            "c) log_shipping_primary_secondaries",
            "d) sp_help_log_shipping_primary_database"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: log_shipping_monitor_alert stores alert job ID."
    },
    {
        "id": 558,
        "Question": "___________ feature will be removed in a future version of Microsoft SQL Server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Log shipping",
            "b) Database snapshots",
            "c) Database mirroring",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Use AlwaysOn Availability Groups instead of database mirroring."
    },
    {
        "id": 559,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Database mirroring is a solution for lowering the availability of a SQL Server database",
            "b) Log shipping is a solution for increasing the availability of a SQL Server database",
            "c) Mirroring is implemented on a per-database basis",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer:c\nExplanation: Mirroring works only with databases that use the full recovery model."
    },
    {
        "id": 560,
        "Question": "Which of the following benefit is provided by database mirroring?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increases data protection",
            "b) Improves the availability of the production database",
            "c) Increases availability of a database",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: To minimize downtime for a mirrored database, you can sequentially upgrade the instances of SQL Server that are hosting the failover partners."
    },
    {
        "id": 561,
        "Question": "Database mirroring operates in how many modes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Database mirroring operates in three different modes: high-availability mode, high-protection mode, and high-performance mode."
    },
    {
        "id": 562,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Mirror database is the copy of the database that is typically fully synchronized with the principal database",
            "b) Redo queue is received transaction log records that are waiting on the disk of a mirror server",
            "c) Database mirroring provides less redundancy of the data",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Database mirroring provides complete or almost complete redundancy of the data depending on whether the operating mode is high-safety or high-performance."
    },
    {
        "id": 563,
        "Question": "Which of the following modes writes the data on the principal and mirror databases synchronously?",
        "Options": [
            "a) High safety with automatic cluster",
            "b) High safety",
            "c) High safety with automatic failover",
            "d) High performance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In high safety with automatic cluster, Data is written and must be committed synchronously both on the principal and mirror databases."
    },
    {
        "id": 564,
        "Question": "The high performance mode is only available in the __________ edition of SQL Server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Enterprise",
            "b) Express",
            "c) Compact",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In high performance mode, the asynchronous communication, data is written and committed on the principal server, and later sent and committed to the mirror server."
    },
    {
        "id": 565,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an upgrade step to database mirroring?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Switch to high performance (sync)",
            "b) Perform a rolling upgrade",
            "c) Switch back to high performance (sync)",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: You have to backup the database and transaction on the principal server for database mirroring."
    },
    {
        "id": 566,
        "Question": "Which of the following pair of technology is supported in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Mirroring and Replication",
            "b) Mirroring and Clustering",
            "c) Mirroring and Log Shipping",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Upgrade mirror, manual failover to mirror, upgrade original principal, manual failover to original principal."
    },
    {
        "id": 567,
        "Question": "Which of the following scenario prefers failover cluster instance over stand alone instance in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) High Confidentiality",
            "b) High Availability",
            "c) High Integrity",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: High availability of the SQL Server instance is protected by the presence of redundant nodes in the FCI."
    },
    {
        "id": 568,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The detailed component diagnostics makes it possible to configure a more flexible failover policy",
            "b) The diagnostic information is stored to database",
            "c) The detailed component diagnostics disables better troubleshooting of automatic failovers retroactively",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can choose what failure conditions trigger failovers and which failure conditions do not in configuration options."
    },
    {
        "id": 569,
        "Question": "Benefits that SQL Server failover cluster instances provide ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Protection at the instance level through redundancy",
            "b) Disaster recovery solution using a multi-subnet FCI",
            "c) Zero reconfiguration of applications and clients during failovers",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: You can even run an FCI-hosted database inside an AlwaysOn availability group."
    },
    {
        "id": 570,
        "Question": "The resources owned by WSFC node include ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Destination address",
            "b) SQL Server Browser",
            "c) One file share resource, if the FILESTREAM feature is installed",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: One file share resource is included only if the FILESTREAM feature is installed."
    },
    {
        "id": 571,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The System Configuration Checker will verify the system state of your computer before Setup continues",
            "b) Microsoft Lync Server 2010 supports clustering for Microsoft SQL Server 2005 only",
            "c) The System Configuration Checker will run one more set of rules to validate your computer configuration with the SQL Server features you have specified",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Microsoft Lync Server 2010 supports clustering for Microsoft SQL Server 2008, Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2, and Microsoft SQL Server 2005 in an active/passive configuration. For details about SQL Server clustering."
    },
    {
        "id": 572,
        "Question": "Which of the following element is installed locally on each node of the FCI?",
        "Options": [
            "a) WSFC Resource Group",
            "b) SQL Server Binaries",
            "c) Network Name",
            "d) Storage"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: However, during startup, SQL Server binaries are not started automatically, but managed by WSFC."
    },
    {
        "id": 573,
        "Question": "Which of the following operation requires to run SQL Server Setup on the node?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Add",
            "b) Remove",
            "c) Update",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: To update or remove a SQL Server failover cluster, you must be a local administrator with permission to login as a service on all nodes of the failover cluster."
    },
    {
        "id": 574,
        "Question": "A Windows Failover Cluster can support up to _______ nodes.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 12",
            "b) 14",
            "c) 16",
            "d) 18"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A single SQL Server 2012 instance can run on only a single node at a time; and should a failover occur, the failed instance can failover to another node."
    },
    {
        "id": 575,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a Windows Failover Cluster quorum mode?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Node Majority",
            "b) No Majority: Read Only",
            "c) File Read Majority",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In Node majority, each node that is available and in communication can vote. The cluster functions only with a majority of the votes."
    },
    {
        "id": 576,
        "Question": "An exciting new feature in SQL Server 2014 is the support for the deployment of a Failover Cluster Instance (FCI) with ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Cluster Shared Volumes (CSV)",
            "b) In memory database",
            "c) Column oriented database",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A SQL 2014 deployment with Cluster Shared Volumes provides several advantages over a deployment on “traditional” cluster storage."
    },
    {
        "id": 577,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server 2008 offers three authentication mode options",
            "b) Microsoft’s best practice recommendation is that you use Windows authentication mode whenever possible",
            "c) If you use mixed authentication mode, you should enable the DBA’s Windows account",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SSMS can also be used to enable the sa login."
    },
    {
        "id": 578,
        "Question": "Which of the following feature prefers SQL Server authentication mode over windows authentication?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Backward compatibility",
            "b) Forward compatibility",
            "c) Security",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Windows authentication mode allows you to centralize account administration for your entire enterprise in a single place."
    },
    {
        "id": 579,
        "Question": "Windows Authentication Mode is not available when an instance of SQL Server is running on ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Windows 98",
            "b) Windows 7",
            "c) Windows 95",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server Authentication is provided for backward compatibility. For example, if you create a single Windows 2000 group and add all necessary users to that group you will need to grant the Windows 2000 group login rights to SQL Server and access to any necessary databases."
    },
    {
        "id": 580,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Windows authentication mode dramatically reduces the chances of error or oversight",
            "b) Account administration details in windows mode is stored in passive directory",
            "c) The sa account is a well-known SQL Server account and it is often targeted by malicious users",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Windows Authentication Mode is also unavailable on Microsoft Windows Millennium Edition."
    },
    {
        "id": 581,
        "Question": "Which of the following authentication modes is more secure?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server Authentication",
            "b) Windows Authentication",
            "c) Mixed Mode",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Account administration details in windows authentication mode are stored in single place:Active directory."
    },
    {
        "id": 582,
        "Question": "By using Windows Authentication, Windows groups can be created at the _________ level.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Login",
            "b) Domain",
            "c) User",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Windows Authentication uses Kerberos security protocol, provides password policy enforcement with regard to complexity validation for strong passwords."
    },
    {
        "id": 583,
        "Question": "________ optional password policies are available for SQL Server logins.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 5",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Managing access from the domain level can simplify account administration."
    },
    {
        "id": 584,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the biggest disadvantage of SQL Server Authentication mode?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server Authentication cannot use Kerberos security protocol",
            "b) Allows SQL Server to support Web-based applications where users create their own identities",
            "c) Allows SQL Server to support older applications and applications provided by third parties that require SQL Server Authentication",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When using SQL Server Authentication, logins are created in SQL Server that are not based on Windows user accounts."
    },
    {
        "id": 585,
        "Question": "The Windows password policies enforced for SQL Server logins depends upon _____________________ API.",
        "Options": [
            "a) NetValidate",
            "b) NetValidatePasswordPolicy",
            "c) NetValidatePolicy",
            "d) ValidatePasswordPolicy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Windows Authentication uses Kerberos security protocol."
    },
    {
        "id": 586,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) In versions of SQL Server through SQL Server 2014, sub-securables cannot use brackets in the form ‘[sub name]’. Use ‘sub name’ instead",
            "b) HAS_PERMS_BY_NAME returns NULL when the query fails",
            "c) In ADO.net, the sub-securable_class argument is valid only if the securable_class argument is set to OBJECT",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  Use ‘sub name’ instead of ‘[sub name]’."
    },
    {
        "id": 587,
        "Question": "_________ returns a list of the permissions effectively granted to the principal on a securable.",
        "Options": [
            "a) HAS_PERMS_BY_NAME",
            "b) sys.fn_my_permissions",
            "c) sys.fn_permissions",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Related function is HAS_PERMS_BY_NAME."
    },
    {
        "id": 588,
        "Question": "What is the syntax for fn_my_permissions function in SQL Server 2014?",
        "Options": [
            "a) fn_my_permissions ( securable , securable_class )",
            "b) fn_my_permissions ( securable , ‘securable_class’ )",
            "c) fn_my_permissions ( ‘securable’ , securable_class)",
            "d) fn_my_permissions ( ‘securable’ , ‘securable_class’ )"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Securable is the name of the securable. If the securable is the server or a database, this value should be set to NULL. securable is a scalar expression of type sysname. securable can be a multipart name."
    },
    {
        "id": 589,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The entity that receives permission to a securable is called a principal",
            "b) The SCHEMA securable scope contains the USER securables",
            "c) A table is a securable",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The database securable scope contains the user securables."
    },
    {
        "id": 590,
        "Question": "The schema securable scope contains the following securable is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Contract",
            "b) Asymmetric key",
            "c) Schema",
            "d) Object"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The object class has the following members: Aggregate, Function and Procedure."
    },
    {
        "id": 591,
        "Question": "Which of the following returns a row for each security principal in a SQL Server database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sys.database_role_members",
            "b) sys.sql_logins",
            "c) sys.database_principals",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The permissions of fixed database roles do not appear in sys.database_permissions."
    },
    {
        "id": 592,
        "Question": "Any SQL Server authentication login can see ________ login name.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Own and sa",
            "b) sa",
            "c) Own",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To see other logins, requires ALTER ANY LOGIN, or permission on the login."
    },
    {
        "id": 593,
        "Question": "To add or remove server role membership use ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER ROLE",
            "b) ALTER ANY LOGIN",
            "c) ALTER SERVER ROLE",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ALTER SERVER ROLE changes the membership of a server role or changes name of a user-defined server role. Fixed server roles cannot be renamed."
    },
    {
        "id": 594,
        "Question": "10. What is the role of WITH NAME in the following code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">ALTER</span> SERVER <span class=\"kw1\">ROLE</span> server_role_name \n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"br0\">[</span> <span class=\"kw1\">ADD</span> MEMBER server_principal <span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n  <span class=\"sy0\">|</span> <span class=\"br0\">[</span> <span class=\"kw1\">DROP</span> MEMBER server_principal <span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n  <span class=\"sy0\">|</span> <span class=\"br0\">[</span> <span class=\"kw1\">WITH</span> NAME <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> new_server_role_name <span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span> <span class=\"br0\">[</span> ; <span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Removes the specified server principal from the server role",
            "b) Adds the specified server principal to the server role",
            "c) Specifies the new name of the user-defined server role",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: HAS_PERMS_BY_NAME evaluates the effective permission of the current user on a securable."
    },
    {
        "id": 595,
        "Question": "1. Which of the field must be 1 using an authenticator in the following code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">EncryptByKey <span class=\"br0\">(</span> key_GUID <span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span> <span class=\"st0\">'cleartext'</span> <span class=\"sy0\">|</span> @cleartext <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n    <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span> add_authenticator <span class=\"sy0\">|</span> @add_authenticator <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n     <span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span> authenticator <span class=\"sy0\">|</span> @authenticator <span class=\"br0\">}</span> <span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) @add_authenticator",
            "b) @cleartext",
            "c) key_GUID",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  add_authenticator indicates whether an authenticator will be encrypted together with the cleartext."
    },
    {
        "id": 596,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) EncryptByKey uses a symmetric key",
            "b) EncryptByKey returns NULL if the key is not open",
            "c) You can use encryption in SQL Server for connections, data, and stored procedures",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  If the symmetric key is already open in the current session, you do not have to open it again in the context of the query."
    },
    {
        "id": 597,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Encryption should be considered for all data or connections",
            "b) Any use of encryption should also include a maintenance strategy for passwords, keys, and certificates",
            "c) TDE is essentially an enterprise-oriented feature and is available only in the following editions of SQL Server",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The CREATE CERTIFICATE statement is used to create a new certificate named MySQLCert."
    },
    {
        "id": 598,
        "Question": "Like data compression, TDE database encryption is performed at the ______ level.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Page",
            "b) Domain",
            "c) Column",
            "d) Row"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: encryption is a valuable tool to help ensure security, it should not be considered for all data or connections."
    },
    {
        "id": 599,
        "Question": "Which of the following catalog view is used to monitor TDE?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sys.certificates",
            "b) sys.certificate",
            "c) DMVs",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Backing up the certificate is extremely important because the encrypted data can’t be accessed or restored without the certificate."
    },
    {
        "id": 600,
        "Question": "___________ encryption was introduced in SQL Server 2005 and is available in all editions of SQL Server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Column-level Encryption",
            "b) Transparent Data Encryption",
            "c) BitLocker",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  To find out what is signed by the certificate, you can use the sys.certificates."
    },
    {
        "id": 601,
        "Question": "Which of the following functions decrypts data by using a symmetric key?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DECRYPTBYSYMKEY",
            "b) DECRYPTBYKEYAUTOASYMKEY",
            "c) DECRYPTBYASYMKEY",
            "d) DECRYPTBYKEYAUTOCERT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To use cell-level encryption, the schema must be changed to varbinary, then reconverted to the desired data type."
    },
    {
        "id": 602,
        "Question": "Which of the following condition in the where clause will return the login identification name of the user?",
        "Options": [
            "a) UserName = SUSER_NAME()",
            "b) UserName = SUSER_SNAME()",
            "c) UserName = CURRENT_USER()",
            "d) UserName = USER()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  USER_NAME or CURRENT_USER Return the database user name."
    },
    {
        "id": 603,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Implementing row level security based on security labels is possible in SQL Server 2008",
            "b) A security label is a marking that describes the securable content of an item",
            "c) Row-level permissions are used for applications that store information in a single table",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SQL Server does not have support for implementing row-level security. You must create additional columns in your tables that define row filtering mechanisms."
    },
    {
        "id": 604,
        "Question": "View that contains the list of all the security labels present in the database are __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) vwVisibleLabels",
            "b) VisibleLabels",
            "c) vwVisibleLabel",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The purpose of vwVisibleLabels view is to enforce the row security by joining it with the base table."
    },
    {
        "id": 605,
        "Question": "Which of the following retrieves a SecurityLabel instance describing the subject label of the current database user?",
        "Options": [
            "a) fn_Dominates",
            "b) usp_GetUserLabel",
            "c) usp_GetCurrentUserLabel",
            "d) usp_GetSecLabelDetails"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: usp_GetSecLabelDetails generates the security label identifier and encryption objects for the specified label."
    },
    {
        "id": 606,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) usp_EnableCellVisibility opens all the symmetric keys that are mapped to security labels",
            "b) usp_DisableCellVisibility opens all the symmetric keys that were previously opened",
            "c) On SQL Server 2012 you can use the Contained Database feature to create a user without a login",
            "d) No arguments are available for usp_EnableCellVisibility"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: usp_DisableCellVisibility (Stored Procedure) closes all the symmetric keys that were previously opened by calling usp_EnableCellVisibility."
    },
    {
        "id": 607,
        "Question": "What will the fn_Dominates return if A dominates B where A and B both are security label?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) NULL",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: fn_Dominates (Function) compares two labels and determines whether label A dominates label B."
    },
    {
        "id": 608,
        "Question": "The major components of the Label Security Toolkit are _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Documentation",
            "b) The Label Policy Designer application",
            "c) Examples showing the implementation of row- and cell-level security in different scenarios",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The Label Security Toolkit provides tools and techniques for using Microsoft® SQL Server (versions 2005 through 2012) to implement row-level security (RLS) and cell-level security (CLS) based on security labels."
    },
    {
        "id": 609,
        "Question": "Return type of CertName field in vwVisibleLabels is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) XML",
            "b) INT",
            "c) NVARCHAR(256)",
            "d) VARCHAR(256)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: CertName field describes the security certificate name, to implement Cell Level Security."
    },
    {
        "id": 610,
        "Question": "Which of the following will not return user name of the current session?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CUURENT_USER()",
            "b) USER_NAME()",
            "c) CUSER_NAME()",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: All of the specified functions will return user name."
    },
    {
        "id": 611,
        "Question": "Grant ________ permission on the stored procedures to database roles for implementing call level security.",
        "Options": [
            "a) EXECUTE",
            "b) EXEC",
            "c) READ",
            "d) WRITE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Users can only access data through the stored procedures provided."
    },
    {
        "id": 612,
        "Question": "Which of the following tool is used for purpose of data auditing for SQL Server only?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ApexSQL",
            "b) SQL Ninja",
            "c) SQL Audit",
            "d) Idera"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ApexSQL Audit is a tool for auditing SQL Server data changes specifically for Microsoft SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 613,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The CREATE SERVER AUDIT statement is in a transaction scope",
            "b) An audit must exist before deleting a server audit specification for it",
            "c) To insert a server audit, principles require the ALTER ANY SERVER AUDIT or the CONTROL SERVER permission",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If the transaction is rolled back, the statement is also rolled back."
    },
    {
        "id": 614,
        "Question": "Which of the following object is only available for audit actions in  Create Server Audit Specification?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Audit Action Type",
            "b) Object Name",
            "c) Audit Name",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Object Name is the name of the object to audit.It does not apply to audit groups."
    },
    {
        "id": 615,
        "Question": "Selecting the _________ option can allow unaudited activity which could violate your security policies.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Fail",
            "b) Shut down",
            "c) Continue",
            "d) Break"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  Select Continue option when continuing the operation of the Database Engine is more important than maintaining a complete audit. This is the default selection."
    },
    {
        "id": 616,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Users with the ALTER ROLE permission can create server audit specifications and bind them to any audit",
            "b) SQL Server audit uses Extended Events to help create an audit",
            "c) You can have multiple audits per SQL Server instance",
            "d) You can create one server audit specification per audit"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Users with the ALTER ANY SERVER AUDIT permission can create server audit specifications and bind them to any audit."
    },
    {
        "id": 617,
        "Question": "Which of the following views log from a file that is named \\\\serverName\\Audit\\HIPPA_AUDIT.sqlaudit?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT * FROM sys.fn_audit_file (‘\\\\serverName\\Audit\\HIPPA_AUDIT.sqlaudit’, default,default);",
            "b) SELECT * FROM sys.fn_get_audit_file (‘\\\\serverName\\Audit\\HIPPA_AUDIT.sqlaudit’, default,default);",
            "c) SELECT * FROM sys.fn_get_audit(‘\\\\serverName\\Audit\\HIPPA_AUDIT.sqlaudit’, default,default);",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The following code creates a database audit specification called Audit_Pay_Tables that audits SELECT and INSERT statements by the dbo user, for the HumanResources.EmployeePayHistory table."
    },
    {
        "id": 618,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is used to enable auditing from SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) auditpol /set /subcategory:”application generated” /success:enable /failure:enable",
            "b) polaudit /set /subcategory:”application generated” /success:enable /failure:enable",
            "c) auditpolenable /set /subcategory:”application generated” /success:enable /failure:enable",
            "d) auditenable /set /subcategory:”application generated” /success:enable /failure:enable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sys.fn_audit_file returns information from an audit file created by a server audit in SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 619,
        "Question": "How many ways of auditing the schema is available in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer:  a\nExplanation: There are mainly two ways to audit:Using backups and Scripts in SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 620,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) You can use Source control to audit schema changes",
            "b) The SQL Server Audit feature enables you to audit column level groups of events and individual events",
            "c) Audit level actions encompass data manipulation languages (DML) and data definition language (DDL) operations",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Whether you do or not, this code in source control will need to be stored separately from your development code in order to isolate keeping track of production changes from your development processor."
    },
    {
        "id": 621,
        "Question": "Which of the following event is not intrinsically audited?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER DATABASE AUDIT SPECIFICATION",
            "b) CREATE SERVER AUDIT SPECIFICATION",
            "c) DROP SERVER AUDIT SPECIFICATION",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: All audits are disabled when initially created."
    },
    {
        "id": 622,
        "Question": "Which of the following is server-level audit action group?",
        "Options": [
            "a) BACK_RESTORE_GROUP",
            "b) BACKUP_RESTORE_GROUP",
            "c) DB_LOGOUT_GROUP",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: BACKUP_RESTORE_GROUP  event is raised whenever a backup or restore command is issued."
    },
    {
        "id": 623,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) When the query processor parameterize the query, the parameter can appear in the audit event log instead of the column values of the query",
            "b) To access the triggering event we can use the EventData function in our DDL trigger",
            "c) AUDIT_DATABASE_CHANGE_GROUP event is raised whenever CREATE DATABASE AUDIT is issued",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: AUDIT_ CHANGE_GROUP event is raised whenever CREATE SERVER AUDIT is issued."
    },
    {
        "id": 624,
        "Question": "AUDIT_CHANGE_GROUP event is raised whenever any audit is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Created",
            "b) Modified",
            "c) Delete",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Any change to an audit is audited in that audit.Equivalent to the Audit Change Audit Event Class."
    },
    {
        "id": 625,
        "Question": "__________ could potentially lead to large audit records.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DATABASE_OBJECT_ACCESS_GROUP",
            "b) DATABASE_MIRRORING_LOGIN_GROUP",
            "c) DATABASE_OBJECT_OWNERSHIP_CHANGE_GROUP",
            "d) DATABASE_OBJECT_PERMISSION_CHANGE_GROUP"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: DATABASE_OBJECT_ACCESS_GROUP event is raised for any access to any database."
    },
    {
        "id": 626,
        "Question": "You can use the handy event name of __________ to make sure your trigger covers all DDL events.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DDL_DATABASE_EVENTS",
            "b) DDL_DATABASE_LEVEL_EVENTS",
            "c) DDL_DATABASE_LEVEL",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: DDL_DATABASE_LEVEL_EVENTS is used for auditing database objects in SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 627,
        "Question": "DDL Trigger can capture the information about the EVENT that fired it by using __________ function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) EVENTDATA()",
            "b) EVENT()",
            "c) EVENTS()",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The EventData xml value includes the triggering SQL statement, the event time, the type of event and depending on what type of event was called, extra information such as the database name."
    },
    {
        "id": 628,
        "Question": "Which of the following database level event si raised whenever a REFERENCES permission is checked.",
        "Options": [
            "a) EXECUTE",
            "b) REFERENCES",
            "c) UPDATE",
            "d) SELECT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Database-level audit actions do not apply to Columns."
    },
    {
        "id": 629,
        "Question": "Which of the following option can be used to launch Perfmon?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Type “start perfmon” at the command prompt",
            "b) Go to Start | Programs | Administrative Tools | Performance Monitor",
            "c) Go to Start | Run | Perfmon",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: There are three ways to launch Perfmon which is performance monitoring tool for SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 630,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) There are hundreds of Performance Counters",
            "b) Performance Counters are very important to evaluate",
            "c) SQL Server provides several tools for monitoring events in SQL Server and for tuning the physical database design",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are more than thousands of Performance Counters."
    },
    {
        "id": 631,
        "Question": "Which of the following is one of the most crucial performance counters for monitoring?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Disk Write Bytes/sec",
            "b) Memory Queue Length",
            "c) Virtual Memory",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Disk Write Bytes/sec report the number of bytes written to the disk."
    },
    {
        "id": 632,
        "Question": "_________ reports the total processor time with respect to the available capacity of the server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Disk Read Bytes/sec",
            "b) Avg.Disk Queue Length",
            "c) Processor time",
            "d) Response time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If counter is between 50 to 70 % consistently, investigate the process which is taking long time."
    },
    {
        "id": 633,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Slow SELECT queries with high physical reads and low queue lengths demonstrates under performance of Disk read and write",
            "b) If many simultaneous requests are waiting, investigate the process which is taking less time",
            "c) SQL Server 2008 R2 Data Collection provides information about SQL Server processes and how these processes affect the current instance of SQL Server",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  Index optimization can reduce this problem."
    },
    {
        "id": 634,
        "Question": "Which of the following stored procedure reports snapshot information about current SQL Server user?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_lock",
            "b) sp_who",
            "c) sp_monitor",
            "d) sp_user"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sp_who reports snapshot information about current SQL Server users and processes, including the currently executing statement and whether the statement is blocked."
    },
    {
        "id": 635,
        "Question": "_____________ displays an estimate of the current amount of disk space used by a table.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_lock",
            "b) sp_who",
            "c) sp_monitor",
            "d) sp_spaceused"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: sp_spaceused displays the number of rows, disk space reserved, and disk space used by a table, indexed view, or Service Broker queue in the current database, or displays the disk space reserved and used by the whole database."
    },
    {
        "id": 636,
        "Question": "8. Which of the following field in the following code is qualified name?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">sp_spaceused <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span> @objname <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"st0\">'objname'</span> <span class=\"br0\">]</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span> @updateusage <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"st0\">'updateusage'</span> <span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) updateusage",
            "b) @objname",
            "c) @updateusage",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: @objname is the qualified or nonqualified name of the table, indexed view, or queue for which space usage information is requested."
    },
    {
        "id": 637,
        "Question": "Which of the following determines type or resource to which the lock applies?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_lock",
            "b) sp_who",
            "c) sp_monitor",
            "d) sp_spaceused"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: sp_lock reports information about locks.use the sys.dm_tran_locks dynamic management view in future versions."
    },
    {
        "id": 638,
        "Question": "The Activity Monitor in SQL Server Management Studio graphically displays information about ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) User activity",
            "b) Blocked processes",
            "c) Locks",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: These parameters are useful for ad hoc views of current activity."
    },
    {
        "id": 639,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the benefit of SQL Server Profiler?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Capturing the series of Transact-SQL statements that lead to a problem",
            "b) Finding and diagnosing slow-running queries",
            "c) Correlating performance counters to diagnose problems",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Microsoft SQL Server Profiler is a graphical user interface to SQL Trace for monitoring an instance of the Database Engine or Analysis Services."
    },
    {
        "id": 640,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server Profiler also supports auditing the actions performed on instances of SQL Server",
            "b) A profiler class is a type of event that can be traced",
            "c) A profile category defines the way events are grouped within SQL Server Profiler",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server Profiler is a rich interface to create and manage traces and analyze and replay trace results."
    },
    {
        "id": 641,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an event class?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL:BatchCompleted",
            "b) Audit Password",
            "c) Lock:Blocked",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The event class contains all of the data that can be reported by an event. "
    },
    {
        "id": 642,
        "Question": "Which of the following stored procedure will stop the trace?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_trace_create.",
            "b) sp_trace_setfilter",
            "c) sp_trace_setstatus",
            "d) sp_stop_status"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Stop and Close the the trace with sp_trace_setstatus."
    },
    {
        "id": 643,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) If a filter is set, all events of the selected event classes are returned in the trace output",
            "b) A trace captures data based on selected event classes, data columns, and filters. For example, you can create a trace to monitor exception errors",
            "c) A data column is an attribute of event classes captured in the trace",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When you create a trace or template, you can define criteria to filter the data collected by the event. To keep traces from becoming too large, you can filter them so that only a subset of the event data is collected."
    },
    {
        "id": 644,
        "Question": "Which of the following argument has option value 2 in sp_trace_create procedure?",
        "Options": [
            "a) TRACE_PRODUCE_BLACKBOX",
            "b) SHUTDOWN_ON_ERROR",
            "c) TRACE_FILE_ROLLOVER",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Adds or removes an event or event column to a trace. sp_trace_setevent may be executed only on existing traces that are stopped."
    },
    {
        "id": 645,
        "Question": "Which of the following events and their columns are contained in the trace?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Attention",
            "b) Batch starting",
            "c) Exception",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: As more rollover trace files are created, the integer value appended to the file name increases sequentially."
    },
    {
        "id": 646,
        "Question": "TRACE_PRODUCE_BLACKBOX file can be saved in the following location?",
        "Options": [
            "a) N’%SQLDIR%\\MSSQL\\DATA\\blackbox.trc",
            "b) N’%SQLDIR%\\MSSQL\\DATA\\black.trc",
            "c) N’%SQLDIR%\\MSSQL\\DATA\\box.trc",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Events or columns cannot be added or removed from this trace."
    },
    {
        "id": 647,
        "Question": "Which of the following event has event number 15 in the trace?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DTCTransaction",
            "b) ErrorLog",
            "c) SQL:BatchStarting",
            "d) Lock:Cancel"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  The default file_count is 2 but can be overridden by the user using filecount option."
    },
    {
        "id": 648,
        "Question": "Which of the following requires VIEW SERVER STATE permission on the server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sys.dm_os_states",
            "b) sys.dm_os_wait_stats",
            "c) sys.dm_os_wait_states",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sys.dm_os_wait_stats returns information about all the waits encountered by threads that executed. "
    },
    {
        "id": 649,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 510: CXPACKET indicates parallelism",
            "b) SQL Server does not always waits for something, a disk io, a place in the processor queue, a lock",
            "c) Few variations of PAGEIOLATCH waits usually indicate a problem with the disk subsystem",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The coordinator thread in a parallel query always accumulates these waits."
    },
    {
        "id": 650,
        "Question": "How many types of wait occur in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQL Server mainly supports three types of waits: Resource waits, Queue waits and External waits "
    },
    {
        "id": 651,
        "Question": "The contents of sys.dm_os_wait_stats can be reset by running which of the following command?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DBCC PERF (‘sys.dm_os_wait_stats’, CLEAR);",
            "b) DBCC SQLP (‘sys.dm_os_wait_stats’, CLEAR);",
            "c) DBCC SQLPERF (‘sys.dm_os_wait_stats’, CLEAR);",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: DBCC SQLPERFcommand resets all counters to 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 652,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) LCK_M_XX wait is often a symptom of blocking",
            "b) PAGELATCH_XX wait occurs when SQL Server is attempting to latch a page in memory",
            "c) Few variations of PAGEIOLATCH waits usually indicate a problem with the disk subsystem",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: All variations of PAGEIOLATCH waits usually indicate a problem with the disk subsystem. "
    },
    {
        "id": 653,
        "Question": "______ waits occur when a worker requests access to a resource that is not available because the resource is being used by some other worker or is not yet available.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Resource",
            "b) Queue",
            "c) Lock",
            "d) External"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Examples of resource waits are locks, latches, network and disk I/O waits. Lock and latch waits are waits on synchronization objects."
    },
    {
        "id": 654,
        "Question": "Which of the following wait occurs when a task is waiting for I/Os to finish?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ASYNC_NETWORK_IO",
            "b) AUDIT_LOGINCACHE_LOCK",
            "c) AUDIT_ON_DEMAND_TARGET_LOCK",
            "d) AUDIT_XE_SESSION_MGR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: AUDIT_XE_SESSION_MGR occurs when there is a wait on a lock that is used to synchronize the starting and stopping of audit related Extended Events sessions."
    },
    {
        "id": 655,
        "Question": "When does BROKER_TO_FLUSH wait type event occur?",
        "Options": [
            "a) When the Service Broker queue task handler tries to shut down the task",
            "b) When the Service Broker transmitter is waiting for work",
            "c) When the Service Broker lazy flusher flushes the in-memory transmission objects to a work table",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: BROKER_SHUTDOWN tries to shut down the task."
    },
    {
        "id": 656,
        "Question": "Which of the following wait type is for internal use only?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ASYNC_NETWORK_IO",
            "b) AUDIT_LOGINCACHE_LOCK",
            "c) HADR_DBR_SUBSCRIBER_FILTER_LIST",
            "d) AUDIT_XE_SESSION_MGR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The publisher for an availability replica event (such as a state change or configuration change) is waiting for exclusive read/write access to the list of event subscribers that correspond to availability databases."
    },
    {
        "id": 657,
        "Question": "_____________ wait type applies to SQL Server 2014 only.",
        "Options": [
            "a) LCK_M_U_ABORT_BLOCKERS",
            "b) HADR_WORK_QUEUE",
            "c) HADR_XRF_STACK_ACCESS",
            "d) HADR_WORK_POOL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: LCK_M_U_ABORT_BLOCKERS occurs when a task is waiting to acquire an Update lock with Abort Blockers."
    },
    {
        "id": 658,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an extended event task?",
        "Options": [
            "a) create an Extended Events session",
            "b) alter an Extended Events session",
            "c) find out what events are available in the registered packages",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Using Management Studio or Transact-SQL to execute Transact-SQL Data Definition Language statements, dynamic management views and functions, or catalog views, you can create simple or complex SQL Server Extended Events troubleshooting solutions for your SQL Server environment."
    },
    {
        "id": 659,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The SQL Server Extended Events engine is a collection of services and objects",
            "b) Buffers are attached to sessions to handle buffering and dispatch, and causality tracking",
            "c) Policy tracking provides the ability to track work across multiple tasks",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The Extended Events engine itself does not provide any events or actions to take when an event fires."
    },
    {
        "id": 660,
        "Question": "SQL Server Extended Events Packages consist of _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Events",
            "b) Predicates",
            "c) Types",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Packages are identified by a name, a GUID, and the binary module that contains the package."
    },
    {
        "id": 661,
        "Question": "Which of the DDL statement creates a session object that contains the metadata?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE EVENT SESSION",
            "b) CREATE SESSION",
            "c) CREATE EVENT SESSION METADATA",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: CREATE EVENT SESSION creates an Extended Events session that identifies the source of the events, the event session targets, and the event session options."
    },
    {
        "id": 662,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Actions and predicates are bound to events on a per-session basis",
            "b) Extended Event sessions have implied boundaries in that the configuration of one session does change the configuration of another session",
            "c) The mapping between package objects and sessions is many to many",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Boundaries do not prevent an event or target from being used in more than one session."
    },
    {
        "id": 663,
        "Question": "_________ can be applied to the metadata or to an active session and the metadata.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP EVENT SESSION",
            "b) ALTER EVENT SESSION,STATE=STOP",
            "c) ALTER EVENT SESSION,STATE=START",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Both ALTER EVENT SESSION and DROP EVENT SESSION can be applied to the metadata or to an active session and the metadata."
    },
    {
        "id": 664,
        "Question": "Which of the following catalog view is used for SQL Server Extended Events?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sys.server_sessions",
            "b) sys.server_event_sess",
            "c) sys.server_event_session_actions",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: sys.server_event_session_actions returns a row for each action on each event of an event session."
    },
    {
        "id": 665,
        "Question": "_________ returns a row for each customizable column that was explicitly set on events and targets.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sys.server_event_session_targets",
            "b) sys.server_event_session_fields",
            "c) Returns a row for each event in an event session",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sys.server_event_session_fields requires VIEW SERVER STATE permission on the server."
    },
    {
        "id": 666,
        "Question": "Which of the following pair of views has one to many relationship?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sys.server_event_session_actions.event_session_id, sys.sys.server_event_sessions.event",
            "b) sys.server_event_session_actions, sys.sys.server_event_sessions.event_session_id",
            "c) sys.server_event_session_actions.event_session_id,sys.sys.server_event_sessions.event _session_id",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Almost all the extended event views has one to many cardinality."
    },
    {
        "id": 667,
        "Question": "Which of the following format output events in an Event Tracing for Windows?",
        "Options": [
            "a) event_file",
            "b) ring_buffer",
            "c) histogram",
            "d) etw_classic_sync_target"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: histogram outputs events to memory in order to group and count events based on fields or actions."
    },
    {
        "id": 668,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a change tracking function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) WITH CHANGE_TRACK_CONTEXT",
            "b) CHANGE_TRACKING_MAX_VALID_VERSION()",
            "c) CHANGE_TRACKING_CURRENT_VERSION",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  You can use this version the next time you enumerate changes by using CHANGETABLE."
    },
    {
        "id": 669,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) A good example of one-way synchronization application is an occasionally connected application",
            "b) Change tracking is a lightweight solution that provides an efficient change tracking mechanism for applications",
            "c) After change tracking is configured for a table, any DDL statement that affects rows in the table will cause change tracking",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Change tracking is used to enable applications to query for changes to data in a database and access information that is related to the changes, application developers had to implement custom change tracking mechanisms."
    },
    {
        "id": 670,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the biggest disadvantage of change tracking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Schema changes are required in the server database",
            "b) Triggers are fired for each change that has been made to a row",
            "c) Logic for maintaining the correct row versions and deletions is easy",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Triggers for each change has performance implications."
    },
    {
        "id": 671,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Change tracking is used for one way synchronization applications only",
            "b) Applications that have to synchronize data with an instance of the SQL Server Database Engine must be able to query for changes",
            "c) Two-way synchronization applications can also be built that use change tracking",
            "d) The two-way synchronization applications must be able to detect conflicts"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: After change tracking is enabled, Sync Framework applications use change tracking functions and anchors to determine which inserts, updates, and deletes to download. An anchor is just a point in time that is used to define a set of changes to synchronize."
    },
    {
        "id": 672,
        "Question": "Which of the following code snippet returns a version integer that is associated with the last committed transaction that was tracked by change tracking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT @sync_new_received_anchor = change_tracking_cur_version()",
            "b) SELECT @sync_new_received_anchor = change_tracking_current_ver()",
            "c) SELECT @sync_new_received_anchor = change_tracking_current_version()",
            "d) SELECT @sync_new_received_anchor = change_track_current_version()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Change tracking is used for one way and two way synchronization applications."
    },
    {
        "id": 673,
        "Question": "_____________ obtains tracking information for all changes to a table that have occurred since a specific version.",
        "Options": [
            "a) CHANGETABLE_CONTEXT",
            "b) CHANGETABLE",
            "c) CHANGE_TRACKING_IS_COLUMN_IN_MASK",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To track which client made a data change that is applied at the server, use the WITH CHANGE_TRACKING_CONTEXT clause."
    },
    {
        "id": 674,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a catalog view used for change tracking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sys.change_tracking_tables",
            "b) sys.change_tracking_views",
            "c) sys.change_tracking_columns",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: CHANGETABLE obtains latest change tracking information for a specified row."
    },
    {
        "id": 675,
        "Question": "Which of the following feature distinguishes change data capture from change tracking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Historical data",
            "b) DML",
            "c) DML type",
            "d) Whether a column was changed"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: sys.change_tracking_tables returns one row for each database in the instance of SQL Server that has change tracking enabled."
    },
    {
        "id": 676,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) To determine if a database is already enabled, query the is_cdc_enabled column in the sys.database catalog view",
            "b) Change data capture requires exclusive use of the cdc schema and cdc user",
            "c) If a change data capture enabled database is dropped, change data capture jobs are not removed",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When this job is executed it runs the system stored procedure sys.sp_MScdc_capture_job."
    },
    {
        "id": 677,
        "Question": "Which of the following disable database for Change Data Capture?",
        "Options": [
            "a) EXEC sys.sp_cdc_ensable_db",
            "b) EXEC sys.sp_disable_db",
            "c) EXEC sys.sp_cdc_disable_db",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If either a schema or a database user named cdc currently exists in a database, the database cannot be enabled for change data capture until the schema and or user are dropped or renamed."
    },
    {
        "id": 678,
        "Question": "If you do not want to use a gating role, explicitly set the @role_name parameter to ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) NULL",
            "c) 1",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A member of the sysadmin fixed server role can run the stored procedure sys.sp_cdc_disable_db in the database context to disable change data capture for a database."
    },
    {
        "id": 679,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) By default, all of the columns in the source table are not identified as captured columns",
            "b) By default, the change table is located in the default filegroup of the database",
            "c) The purpose of the named role is to control access to the change data",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When a role is specified, users who are not members of either the sysadmin or db_owner role must also be members of the specified role."
    },
    {
        "id": 680,
        "Question": "Which of the following query determine sessions that had an empty scan?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT * from sys.dm_cdc_log_scan_sessions where empty_scan_count <> 0",
            "b) SELECT * from sys.dm_cdc_log_scan_sessions where empty_scan_count = 0",
            "c) SELECT * from sys.dm_cdc_log_scan_sessions where empty_scan_count < 0",
            "d) SELECT * from sys.dm_cdc_log_scan_sessions where empty_scan_count > 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If only a subset of columns need to be tracked, such as for privacy or performance reasons, use the @captured_column_list parameter to specify the subset of columns."
    },
    {
        "id": 681,
        "Question": "Upper bound on expected throughput of the capture job is calculated using which of the following computation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) (maxtrans * maxscans) / number of seconds between scans",
            "b) (maxtrans * maxscans) * number of seconds between scans",
            "c) (maxtrans * maxscans) – number of seconds between scans",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To support net changes queries, the source table must have a primary key or unique index to uniquely identify rows."
    },
    {
        "id": 682,
        "Question": "The cleanup job is initiated by running the parameterless stored procedure is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp_MScdc_cleanup_job",
            "b) sp_cdc_cleanup_change_job",
            "c) sp_cdc_cleanup_change_tables",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When running in one shot mode, you can compute an upper bound on expected throughput of the capture job"
    },
    {
        "id": 683,
        "Question": "Which of the following error is returned for a query for all changes when a parameter that is used to define the query interval is not valid?",
        "Options": [
            "a) An insufficient number of arguments were supplied for the procedure or function cdc.fn_cdc_get_partial_changes_",
            "b) An insufficient number of arguments were supplied for the procedure or function cdc.fn_cdc_get_all_changes_",
            "c) An insufficient number of arguments were supplied for the procedure or function cdc.fn_cdc_get_net_changes_",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Sometimes even the error message arises when the row filter option is invalid."
    },
    {
        "id": 684,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The function cdc.fn_cdc_get_all_changes_<capture_instance> returns all changes that occurred for the specified interval",
            "b) The update mask that is returned from a query function is a compact representation that identifies few columns that changed in a row of change data",
            "c) A typical application scenario for querying for change data is to periodically request change data by using a receiver window bounded by timestamp values",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Entries are always returned sorted, first by the transaction commit LSN of the change, and then by a value that sequences the change within its transaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 685,
        "Question": "The commit time of each transaction with an associated entry in a database change table is available in the table __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) cdc.log_time_mapping",
            "b) cdc.lsn_time_mapping",
            "c) cdc.lsn_time_audit",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Using cdc.lsn_time_mapping table entry, you can return the tran_end_time along with the change data to stamp the change with the commit time of the transaction at the source."
    },
    {
        "id": 686,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) cdc.lsn_time_mapping applies to SQL Server 2014",
            "b) Datetime wrappers are owned by the user, and not are created in the default schema of the caller",
            "c) Change data capture supports up to two capture instances for a single tracked source table",
            "d) The name of the function to wrap the all changes query is fn_all_changes_ followed by the capture instance name."
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The SQL Server data collector lets you collect snapshots of data from any table or dynamic management view and build a performance data warehouse."
    },
    {
        "id": 687,
        "Question": "Which of the following query returns the average latency for the most recent sessions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT latency FROM sys.dm_cdc_log_audit_sessions WHERE session_id = 0",
            "b) SELECT latency FROM sys.dm_cdc_log_scan_ WHERE session_id = 0",
            "c) SELECT latency FROM sys.dm_cdc_audit_scan_sessions WHERE session_id = 0",
            "d) SELECT latency FROM sys.dm_cdc_log_scan_sessions WHERE session_id = 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: cdc.lsn_time_mapping applies to SQL Server (SQL Server 2008 through current version)."
    },
    {
        "id": 688,
        "Question": "__________  gives DBAs an option to shut down the server in case of an audit log failure.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Shut down server on partial failure",
            "b) Shut down server on audit log failure",
            "c) Shut down server on complete failure",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: You can use latency data to determine how fast or slow the capture process is processing transactions."
    },
    {
        "id": 689,
        "Question": "Which of the following field in cdc.lsn_time_mapping has varbinary data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) tran_begin_time",
            "b) tran_id",
            "c) start_lsn",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Queue delay (in milliseconds) defines the time interval after which the events will be written in the logs."
    },
    {
        "id": 690,
        "Question": "Which of the following query returns the average throughput for the most recent sessions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT command_count*duration AS [Throughput] FROM sys.dm_cdc_log_scan_sessions WHERE session_id = 0",
            "b) SELECT command_count/duration AS [Throughput] FROM sys.dm_cdc_log_scan_sessions WHERE session_id = 0",
            "c) SELECT command_count/duration AS [Throughput] FROM sys.dm_cdc_log_scan_sesss WHERE session_id = 0",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: tran_id denotes ID of the transaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 691,
        "Question": "sys.fn_cdc_map_time_to_lsn returns ________ value from the start_lsn column in the cdc.lsn_time_mapping system table for the specified time.",
        "Options": [
            "a) LSN",
            "b) LNS",
            "c) SLN",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To determine the throughput of a session, divide the value in the command_count column by the value in the duration column."
    },
    {
        "id": 692,
        "Question": "_________ introduces the Management Data Warehouse (MDW) to SQL Server Management Studio for streamlined performance troubleshooting.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server 2005",
            "b) SQL Server 2008",
            "c) SQL Server 2012",
            "d) SQL Server 2014"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MDW is a set of components that enable a database developer or administrator to quickly track down problems that could be causing performance degradation."
    },
    {
        "id": 693,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MDW consist of three components",
            "b) SQL Server Express instances can be targets",
            "c) Setting up the MDW is a one-step process",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MDW consists of three components: Data Collector, MDW database and MDW reports.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 694,
        "Question": "Which of the following mode allows for the collection and uploading of data to occur on demand?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Non-cached mode",
            "b) Cached mode",
            "c) Mixed mode",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In non-cached mode, collection and upload are on the same schedule."
    },
    {
        "id": 695,
        "Question": "Which of the following scenario favours cached mode?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Continuous collection of data",
            "b) Less frequent uploads",
            "c) Data collection and uploading of jobs on different schedules",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Cached mode uses separate schedules for collection and upload."
    },
    {
        "id": 696,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The Data Collection is performed primarily through SSIS packages that control the collection frequency on the target",
            "b) You should  change the database name after creation",
            "c) Do not change any of the job specifications for the data collection and upload jobs",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: You should not change the database name after creation, because all of the jobs created to manage the database collection refer to the database by the original name and will generate errors if the name is changed."
    },
    {
        "id": 697,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the best Practice and Caveat for Management Data Warehouse?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Use a centralized server for the MDW database",
            "b) The XML parameters for a single T-SQL collection item can have multiple <Query> elements",
            "c) Use a distributed server for the MDW database",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Centralized server allows you to use a single point for viewing reports for multiple instances. "
    },
    {
        "id": 698,
        "Question": "____________ stores information about how the management data warehouse reports should group and aggregate performance counters.",
        "Options": [
            "a) core.snapshots_internal",
            "b) core.supported_collector_types_internal",
            "c) core.wait_categories",
            "d) core.performance_counter_report_group_items"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: core.wait_categories contains the categories used to group wait types according to wait_type characteristic."
    },
    {
        "id": 699,
        "Question": "Which of the following table is used in the management data warehouse schema that is required for the Server Activity?",
        "Options": [
            "a) snapshots.query_stat",
            "b) snapshots.os_latch_stats",
            "c) snapshots.active_sessions",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: snapshots.os_latch_stats is a System level resource table."
    },
    {
        "id": 700,
        "Question": "Which of the following is syntax for sp_add_collector_type procedure?",
        "Options": [
            "a) core.sp_add_collector [ @collector_type_uid = ] ‘collector_type_uid’",
            "b) core.sp_add_collector_type [ @collector_type_uid = ].",
            "c) core.sp_add_collector_type [ @collector_type_uid = ] ‘collector_type_uid’",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: core.sp_add_collector_type adds a new entry to the core.supported_collector_types view in the management data warehouse database."
    },
    {
        "id": 701,
        "Question": "Which of the following syntax is valid?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SET SHOWPLAN_XML { ON | OFF }",
            "b) SET SHOWPLAN { ON | OFF }",
            "c) SET SHOW_XML { ON | OFF }",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SET SHOWPLAN_XML causes SQL Server not to execute Transact-SQL statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 702,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SET SHOWPLAN_TEXT causes Microsoft SQL Server to execute Transact-SQL statements",
            "b) The setting of SET SHOWPLAN_ALL is set at execute or run time and not at parse time",
            "c) The setting of SET SHOWPLAN_XML is set at execute or run time and not at parse time",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When SET SHOWPLAN_XML is ON, SQL Server returns execution plan information for each statement without executing it."
    },
    {
        "id": 703,
        "Question": "___________ displays the profile information for a statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SET STATISTICS",
            "b) SET STATS PROFILE",
            "c) SET STATISTICS PROFILE",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: STATISTICS PROFILE works for ad hoc queries, views, and stored procedures."
    },
    {
        "id": 704,
        "Question": "To produce execution plan output by using most Showplan Transact-SQL SET options, users must have _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHOW SHOWPLAN",
            "b) SHOW PLAN",
            "c) SHOWPLAN",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The SHOWPLAN permission on the databases that contain objects referred to in the Transact-SQL statement, such as views, stored procedures, or user-defined functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 705,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SET SHOWPLAN_XML can be specified inside a stored procedure",
            "b) SET SHOWPLAN_XML returns information as a set of XML documents",
            "c) SET SHOWPLAN_XML is intended to return output as nvarchar(max) for applications such as the sqlcmd utility",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: It must be the only statement in a batch."
    },
    {
        "id": 706,
        "Question": "The document containing the XML schema for the XML output by SET STATISTICS XML is located at ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) \\Microsoft SQL Server\\100\\Tools\\Binn\\schemas\\sqlserver\\2004\\07\\showplan\\showplanxml. xml",
            "b) \\Microsoft SQL Server\\100\\Tools\\Binn\\schemas\\sqlserver\\2004\\07\\showplan\\showplanxml. xsl",
            "c) \\Microsoft SQL Server\\100\\Tools\\Binn\\schemas\\sqlserver\\2004\\07\\showplan\\showplanxml. xsd",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  SET STATISTICS XML produces XML output in the form of schema."
    },
    {
        "id": 707,
        "Question": "Which of the following is valid syntax for SET STATISTICS XML?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SET STATISTICS XML { OFF }",
            "b) SET STATISTICS XML { ON | OFF }",
            "c) SET STATISTICS XML { ON }",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SET STATISTICS XML causes Microsoft SQL Server to execute Transact-SQL statements and generate detailed information about how the statements were executed in the form of a well-defined XML document."
    },
    {
        "id": 708,
        "Question": "__________  returns detailed information about how the statements are executed.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SET STATISTICS XML",
            "b) SET SHOWPLAN_TEXT",
            "c) SET STATISTICS PROFILE",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SET SHOWPLAN_TEXT causes Microsoft SQL Server not to execute Transact-SQL statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 709,
        "Question": "The way that a statement can be physically executed is called _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) query plan",
            "b) execution plan",
            "c) query execution plan",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: An execution plan is composed of primitive operations. Examples of primitive operations are: reading a table completely, using an index, performing a nested loop or a hash join."
    },
    {
        "id": 710,
        "Question": "SET SHOWPLAN_TEXT is intended to return readable output for ________ utility.",
        "Options": [
            "a) osql",
            "b) tsql",
            "c) plsql",
            "d) pgsql"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: osql is Microsoft Win32 command prompt application."
    },
    {
        "id": 711,
        "Question": "Setting the SORT_IN_TEMPDB option to ON can direct the SQL Server Database Engine to use ________ to store the intermediate sort results.",
        "Options": [
            "a) tempdb",
            "b) master",
            "c) msdb",
            "d) model"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: It is required to create or rebuild an index when tempdb is on a set of disks different from that of the user database. "
    },
    {
        "id": 712,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The Database Engine merges the sorted runs of index leaf rows into a single, sorted stream",
            "b) SQL Server also supports full-text indexes and XML indexes, but those are relevant only for specific data types",
            "c) The fill-factor value is a percentage from 1 to 50",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The sort merge component of the Database Engine starts with the first page of each sort run, finds the lowest key in all the pages, and passes that leaf row to the index create component."
    },
    {
        "id": 713,
        "Question": "Which of the following guideline is considered during column design?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Keep the length of the index key short for non clustered indexes",
            "b) An xml data type can only be a key column only in an XML index",
            "c) Examine column which have composite primary keys",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The fill-factor value is a percentage from 1 to 100, and the server-wide default is 0 which means that the leaf-level pages are filled to capacity."
    },
    {
        "id": 714,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server supports only two index types: clustered and non-clustered",
            "b) Appropriate indexes can make a world of difference in performance",
            "c) SET option requires ALTER permission on the table or view",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: QL Server 2012 SP1 introduces a new type of XML index known as a Selective XML Index. This new index can improve querying performance over data stored as XML in SQL Server, allow for much faster indexing of large XML data workloads."
    },
    {
        "id": 715,
        "Question": "By default, indexes are stored in the ______ filegroup as the base table on which the index is created.",
        "Options": [
            "a) same",
            "b) different",
            "c) may be same or different",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are plenty of indexes in SQL Server such as full text, columnstore index in SQL Server 2012"
    },
    {
        "id": 716,
        "Question": "Specifying the order in which key values are stored in an index is useful when queries referencing the table have _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ORDER BY clauses",
            "b) SORT clauses",
            "c) WHERE clauses",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A nonpartitioned clustered index and the base table always reside in the same filegroup."
    },
    {
        "id": 717,
        "Question": "Every table should have a ________ index defined on the column or columns.",
        "Options": [
            "a) CLUSTERED",
            "b) NON CLUSTERED",
            "c) FULL TEXT",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  In these cases, the index can remove the need for a SORT operator in the query plan; therefore, this makes the query more efficient."
    },
    {
        "id": 718,
        "Question": "Which of the following option is immediately applied to the index by using the SET clause in the ALTER INDEX statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALLOW_PAGE_LOCKS",
            "b) ALLOW_COLUMN_LOCKS",
            "c) STATISTICS_RECOMPUTE",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Clustered indexes sort and store the data rows in the table based on their key values."
    },
    {
        "id": 719,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) When SORT_IN_TEMPDB is set to OFF, the default, the sort runs are stored in the source filegroup",
            "b) The Database Engine first scans the data pages of the base table to retrieve key values and builds an index leaf row for each data row",
            "c) When SORT_IN_TEMPDB is set to ON, the default, the sort runs are stored in the destination filegroup",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Enabling a disabled index can be done using SSMS."
    },
    {
        "id": 720,
        "Question": "Which of the following query enables the IX_Employee_OrganizationLevel_OrganizationNode index on the Employee table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DBCC DBREINDEX (“Employee”, IX_Employee_OrganizationLevel_OrganizationNode);",
            "b) DBCC REINDEX (“Employee”, IX_Employee_OrganizationLevel_OrganizationNode);",
            "c) DBCC DBINDEX (“Employee”, IX_Employee_OrganizationLevel_OrganizationNode);",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When the internal sort buffers have been filled with leaf index entries, the entries are shorted and written to disk as an intermediate sort run."
    },
    {
        "id": 721,
        "Question": "Which of the following query can enable all indexes on Employee table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DBCC DBREINDEX (“Employee”, ” “);",
            "b) DBCC DBREINDEX (“EMP”, ” “);",
            "c) DBCC DBREINDEX (“HumanResources.Employee”, “ALL”);",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: DBCC DBREINDEX rebuilds one or more indexes for a table in the specified database."
    },
    {
        "id": 722,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) If SORT_IN_TEMPDB is set to OFF, the free space in the destination filegroup must be large enough to store the final index structure",
            "b) When you create a clustered index on a table that has nonclustered indexes, you must have available as free space",
            "c) When you set the SORT_IN_TEMPDB option to ON, you must have sufficient free disk space available in master database",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: DBCC DBREINDEX can enable all indexes for a table in the specified database."
    },
    {
        "id": 723,
        "Question": "Which of the following index operations require no additional disk space?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER INDEX",
            "b) DROP INDEX",
            "c) CREATE INDEX",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: tempdb is used to store the sort runs, and sufficient free space in the destination filegroup to store the final index structure."
    },
    {
        "id": 724,
        "Question": "Which of the following index operation require additional disk space?",
        "Options": [
            "a) UPDATE INDEX",
            "b) DROP INDEX MOVE TO",
            "c) ALTER INDEX ADD CONSTRAINT",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ALTER statement is used to enable or disable the index."
    },
    {
        "id": 725,
        "Question": "The SORT_IN_TEMPDB option cannot be set for ________ statements.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER INDEX",
            "b) DROP INDEX",
            "c) CREATE INDEX",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: DROP INDEX does not require space when you are dropping a clustered index offline without specifying the MOVE TO clause and nonclustered indexes do not exist."
    },
    {
        "id": 726,
        "Question": "The use of parameters, including parameter markers in _______ applications, can increase the reuse of execution plans.",
        "Options": [
            "a) OLE DB",
            "b) ADO",
            "c) ODBC",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Using parameters or parameter markers to hold values that are typed by end users is more secure than concatenating the values into a string."
    },
    {
        "id": 727,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) JDBC use parameter markers",
            "b) Parameter markers are question marks (?) that replace a constant in an SQL statement",
            "c) When forced parameterization is tried but fails, simple parameterization is still subsequently tried",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Parameter markers are bound to a variable"
    },
    {
        "id": 728,
        "Question": "Use to bind an integer variable to the first parameter marker in an SQL statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQLParameter",
            "b) SQLBind",
            "c) SQLBindParameter",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SQLBindParameter is used in ODBC applications"
    },
    {
        "id": 729,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MisGuided Plan Executions/sec represents the number of plan executions per second in which the query plan has been generated by using a plan guide",
            "b) Execution plans remain in the procedure cache as long as there is enough memory to store them",
            "c) When a user process inserts an execution plan into the cache, the user process sets the current cost equal to the original query compile cost",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When Forced parameterization is enabled, Simple parameterization can still occur. "
    },
    {
        "id": 730,
        "Question": "Which of the following SQL Server SQL Statistics counter represents number of auto-parameterization attempts per second?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Batch Requests/sec",
            "b) Failed Auto-Params/sec",
            "c) Forced parameterizations/sec",
            "d) Auto-Param Attempts/sec"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Guided Plan Executions/sec represents number of plan executions per second in which the query plan has been generated by using a plan guide."
    },
    {
        "id": 731,
        "Question": "The maximum size for all caches is a function of the ________ size.",
        "Options": [
            "a) RAM",
            "b) Buffer pool",
            "c) Hard disk",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Auto-parameterization occurs when an instance of SQL Server tries to parametrize a Transact-SQL request by replacing some literals with parameters so that reuse of the resulting cached execution plan across multiple similar-looking requests is possible."
    },
    {
        "id": 732,
        "Question": "The conditions that invalidate a plan include which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a) An explicit call to sp_compile",
            "b) Executing a stored procedure using the WITH COMPILE option",
            "c) Changes made to a table or view referenced by the query",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The resource monitor and user threads can examine plans run concurrently to decrease the current cost for each unused execution plan."
    },
    {
        "id": 733,
        "Question": "What is the syntax for DBCC FREEPROCCACHE with all the optional parameters in T-SQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DBCC FREEPROCCACHE [ ( { plan_handle | sql_handle | pool_name } ) ] ",
            "b) DBCC FREEPROCCACHE [ ( { plan_handle | sql_handle | pool_name } ) ] [ WITH NO_INFOMSGS ] ",
            "c) DBCC FREEPROCCACHE [ ( { sql_handle | pool_name } ) ] [ WITH NO_INFOMSGS ] ",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ALTER TABLE and ALTER VIEW are used to made changes to the table."
    },
    {
        "id": 734,
        "Question": "_________ uniquely identifies a query plan for a batch that has executed and whose plan resides in the plan cache.",
        "Options": [
            "a) pool_name",
            "b) plan_handle",
            "c) sql_handle",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: DBCC FREEPROCCACHE removes all elements from the plan cache, removes a specific plan from the plan cache by specifying a plan handle or SQL handle, or removes all cache entries associated with a specified resource pool."
    },
    {
        "id": 735,
        "Question": "The INSERT, UPDATE, or DELETE statement fails if the OLE DB provider used to access the linked server does not support the _________ interface.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ITransJoin",
            "b) ITransactionJoin",
            "c) IactionJoin",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ITransactionJoin is exposed only by providers that support distributed transactions. "
    },
    {
        "id": 736,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Transaction ID Returns an object that can be used to specify configuration options for a subsequent call to ITransactionJoin",
            "b) COMMIT WORK syntax, with or without specifying the optional keyword WORK, is compatible with SQL-92",
            "c) You can use ROLLBACK WORK TRANSACTION to erase all data modifications made from the start of the transaction",
            "d) SQL-92 was the third revision of the SQL database query language"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQL-92 was the third revision of the SQL database query language."
    },
    {
        "id": 737,
        "Question": "__________ marks the end of a successful implicit or explicit transaction.",
        "Options": [
            "a) COMMIT TRANSACTION",
            "b) ROLLBACK TRANSACTION",
            "c) COMMIT WORK",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 738,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) BEGIN TRANSACTION represents a point at which the data referenced by a connection is logically and physically consistent",
            "b) BEGIN TRANSACTION deccrements @@TRANCOUNT by 2",
            "c) BEGIN TRANSACTION starts a local transaction for the connection issuing the statement",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: COMMIT WORK marks the end of a transaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 739,
        "Question": "____________ rolls back a user-specified transaction to the beginning of the transaction.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ROLLBACK",
            "b) ROLLBACK WORK",
            "c) SAVE TRANSACTION",
            "d) COMMIT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: BEGIN TRANSACTION increments @@TRANCOUNT by 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 740,
        "Question": "In _______ transaction we include the DML statements that need to be executed as a unit.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Explicit",
            "b) Implicit",
            "c) Distributed",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The savepoint defines a location to which a transaction can return if part of the transaction is conditionally canceled. "
    },
    {
        "id": 741,
        "Question": "_________ permissions default to any valid user.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ROLLBACK WORK",
            "b) ROLLBACK",
            "c) COMMIT",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Generally we don’t include Select statement in a transaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 742,
        "Question": "If @@TRANCOUNT is 1 ________  makes all data modifications performed since the start of the transaction a permanent part of the database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) COMMIT TRANSACTION",
            "b) SAVE TRANSACTION",
            "c) ROLLBACK TRANSACTION",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When nesting transactions, ROLLBACK WORK always rolls back to the outermost BEGIN TRANSACTION statement and decrements the @@TRANCOUNT system function to 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 743,
        "Question": "Which of the following argument is ignored by database engine in COMMIT TRANSACTION?",
        "Options": [
            "a) @tran_name_variable",
            "b) @tran_name",
            "c) transaction_name",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: transaction_name specifies a transaction name assigned by a previous BEGIN TRANSACTION. transaction_name must conform to the rules for identifiers"
    },
    {
        "id": 744,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ROLLBACK TRANSACTION with a savepoint_name or transaction_name rolls back to the beginning of the transaction",
            "b) A ROLLBACK TRANSACTION statement does  produce any messages to the user",
            "c) Issuing a COMMIT TRANSACTION when @@TRANCOUNT is 0 results in an error",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  Error condition implies that there is no corresponding BEGIN TRANSACTION."
    },
    {
        "id": 745,
        "Question": "____________ is the preferred statement for indicating errors in the transaction.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT",
            "b) PRINT",
            "c) RAISERROR",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  If warnings are needed in stored procedures or triggers, use RAISERROR."
    },
    {
        "id": 746,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) It is the responsibility of the Transact-SQL programmer to issue COMMIT TRANSACTION only at a point when all data referenced by the transaction is logically correct",
            "b) The Database Engine increments the transaction count within a statement only when the transaction count is 1 at the start of the statement",
            "c) You cannot roll back a transaction after a COMMIT TRANSACTION statement is issued",
            "d) COMMIT transaction requires membership in the public role"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You cannot roll back a transaction after a COMMIT TRANSACTION statement is issued because the data modifications have been made a permanent part of the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 747,
        "Question": "A ROLLBACK TRANSACTION statement specifying a savepoint_name releases any locks that are acquired beyond the savepoint, with the exception of __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) escalations",
            "b) containment",
            "c) contention",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The Database Engine increments the transaction count within a statement only when the transaction count is 1 at the start of the statement. "
    },
    {
        "id": 748,
        "Question": "What is the fundamental difference between COMMIT and COMMIT WORK?",
        "Options": [
            "a) COMMIT TRANSACTION accepts a user-defined transaction name",
            "b) COMMIT WORK accepts a user-defined transaction name",
            "c) COMMIT TRANSACTION accepts a user-defined function",
            "d) COMMIT WORK accepts a user-defined stored procedure"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: These locks are not released, and they are not converted back to their previous lock mode."
    },
    {
        "id": 749,
        "Question": "Implicit transactions are maintained by SQL Server for ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT",
            "b) DDL",
            "c) DML",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: COMMIT syntax, with or without specifying the optional keyword WORK, is compatible with SQL-92."
    },
    {
        "id": 750,
        "Question": "ROLLBACK WORK always rolls back to the outermost BEGIN TRANSACTION statement for ___________ transactions.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Simple",
            "b) Nested",
            "c) Distributed",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: If there is an error occurring within these statements individually, SQL Server will roll back the complete statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 751,
        "Question": "Which of the following condition will ignore the request to enable delayed durability?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DELAYED_DURABILITY = FORCED",
            "b) DELAYED_DURABILITY = 0",
            "c) DELAYED_DURABILITY = IGNORED",
            "d) DELAYED_DURABILITY = NULL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When nesting transactions, ROLLBACK WORK decrements the @@TRANCOUNT system function to 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 752,
        "Question": "Which of the following resource can be locked in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) TID",
            "b) RID",
            "c) PID",
            "d) SID"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: RID stands for Row identifier and is used to lock a single row within a table."
    },
    {
        "id": 753,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Deadlocking is same as normal blocking",
            "b) No other transactions can read or modify data locked with shared lock",
            "c) A deadlock occurs when there is a cyclic dependency between two or more threads for some set of resources",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Deadlock is a condition that can occur on any system with multiple threads, not just on a relational database management system."
    },
    {
        "id": 754,
        "Question": "______________ allow concurrent transactions to read (SELECT) a resource.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Update locks",
            "b) Shared locks",
            "c) Exclusive Locks",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Shared (S) locks on a resource are released as soon as the data has been read."
    },
    {
        "id": 755,
        "Question": "Which is the most restrictive isolation level in transaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Repeatable Read",
            "b) Snapshot",
            "c) Read Committed",
            "d) SERIALIZABLE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: When SERIALIZABLE isolation level is set – a range lock is placed on the data set, preventing other users from updating or inserting rows into the data set until the transaction is complete."
    },
    {
        "id": 756,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Schema modification (Sch-M) locks are used when a table data definition language operation is being performed",
            "b) By default, SQL Server transactions times out after a certain time",
            "c) Disallowing a locking level can affect concurrency adversely",
            "d) Table-level locking hints can be used when a finer control of the types of locks acquired on an object is required"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQL Server transactions do not time out (unless LOCK_TIMEOUT is set)."
    },
    {
        "id": 757,
        "Question": "__________ locks allow processes to bulk copy data concurrently into the same table.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Bulk update",
            "b) Bulk import",
            "c) Bulk export",
            "d) Bulk copy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Bulk update (BU) locks are used when bulk copying data into a table and either the TABLOCK hint is specified. "
    },
    {
        "id": 758,
        "Question": "Which of the following locking hint is similar to NOLOCK?",
        "Options": [
            "a) PAGLOCK",
            "b) READCOMMITTED",
            "c) READUNCOMMITTED",
            "d) SERIALIZABLE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Do not issue shared locks and do not honor exclusive locks."
    },
    {
        "id": 759,
        "Question": "Which of the following mode indicates the intention of the transaction to read all of the resources lower in the hierarchy?",
        "Options": [
            "a) IS",
            "b) IX",
            "c) SIX",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SIX stands for Shared with intent exclusive and can modify some (but not all) resources lower in the hierarchy by placing IX locks on those individual resources."
    },
    {
        "id": 760,
        "Question": "Which of the following lock is incompatible with all lock modes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Intent exclusive (IX)",
            "b) Schema stability",
            "c) Schema modification",
            "d) Bulk update"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SQL Server allows only one Sch-M lock on an object at a time."
    },
    {
        "id": 761,
        "Question": "Which of the following mode has exclusive range and exclusive resource lock?",
        "Options": [
            "a) RangeX_X",
            "b) RangeS_U",
            "c) RangeS_S",
            "d) RangeI_N"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: RangeX-X locks are exclusive resource locks acquired on Index key values from a specific range when the transaction modifies a key value from the Index."
    },
    {
        "id": 762,
        "Question": "Which of the following design strategy can reduce the occurrence of blocking locks?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Use non-clustered indexes on high-usage tables",
            "b) Use clustered indexes on high-usage tables",
            "c) Use clustered indexes on less-usage tables",
            "d) Make sure that CREATE and DROP statements use an existing index"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Clustered index should be created on frequently used tables."
    },
    {
        "id": 763,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Avoid less row count SQL statements that can cause a table lock",
            "b) A blocking lock occurs when one lock causes another process to wait in a holding queue",
            "c) Lock is a done by database when any connection access a different piece of data concurrently",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If blocking locks are common (rather than infrequent), there is probably some kind of design or query implementation problem."
    },
    {
        "id": 764,
        "Question": "Which of the following occurs when two connections need access to same piece of data concurrently and the meanwhile another is blocked because at a particular time, only one connection can have access?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Lock",
            "b) Block",
            "c) Deadlock",
            "d) Exclusive lock"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Deadlock occurs when one connection is blocked and waiting for a second to complete its work."
    },
    {
        "id": 765,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server lock monitor has a performance monitor that periodically checks the locks",
            "b) A deadlock graph shows us the sessions and resources that were involved in a deadlock",
            "c) Prior to SQL Server 2008, if a deadlock occurred in SQL Server, we’d have to enable trace flag",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Lock is done by database when any connection access the same piece of data concurrently and another is demanding for it."
    },
    {
        "id": 766,
        "Question": "An XML deadlock graph has ______ main sections.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server lock monitor has a deadlock detector that periodically checks the locks to see if there are any circular locking chains."
    },
    {
        "id": 767,
        "Question": "_____________  section lists all the resources that were involved in the deadlock.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Processes",
            "b) Resources",
            "c) WAIT stats",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: An XML deadlock graph has two main sections: Processes section and Resources section."
    },
    {
        "id": 768,
        "Question": "___________ is a deadlock between a statement that is reading and a statement that is performing some form of data modification.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reader",
            "b) Writer",
            "c) Reader-Writer",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Resources section lists all the resources that were involved in the deadlock, which locks each process acquired and which locks they requested."
    },
    {
        "id": 769,
        "Question": "Which of the following best practice should be carried out concerning data types?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Avoid using NOLOCK on SQL Server UPDATE and DELETE statements",
            "b) Capturing SQL Server Deadlock Information in XML Format",
            "c) Optimistic Locking in SQL Server using the ROWVERSION",
            "d) Processing Data Queues in SQL Server with READPAST and UPDLOCK"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sys.partitions contains a row for each partition of all the tables and most types of indexes in the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 770,
        "Question": "The transaction log supports which of the following operations?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Recovery of all incomplete transactions when SQL Server is started",
            "b) Recovery of individual transactions",
            "c) Supporting transactional replication",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The transaction log also supports high availability and disaster recovery solutions."
    },
    {
        "id": 771,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The Database Engine supports two types of checkpoints",
            "b) Long-running uncommitted transactions decrease recovery time for all types of checkpoints",
            "c) Log truncation deletes inactive virtual log files from the logical transaction log of a SQL Server database",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Log truncation frees space in the log file for reuse by the transaction log."
    },
    {
        "id": 772,
        "Question": "Which of the log_reuse_wait_desc value has log_reuse_wait value 0?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CHECKPOINT",
            "b) ACTIVE_TRANSACTION",
            "c) NOTHING",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: log_reuse_wait value 0 indicates currently there are one or more reusable virtual log files."
    },
    {
        "id": 773,
        "Question": "ACTIVE_TRANSACTION has log_reuse_wait value is _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: A long-running transaction might exist at the start of the log backup. In this case, freeing the space might require another log backup."
    },
    {
        "id": 774,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) For performance reasons, the Database Engine performs modifications to database pages in memory",
            "b) Log truncation does reduce the size of the physical log file",
            "c) Log truncation is essential to keep the log from filling",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To reduce the physical size of a physical log file, you need to shrink the log file."
    },
    {
        "id": 775,
        "Question": "________ logging is not supported for memory-optimized tables.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Full",
            "b) Minimal",
            "c) Bulk",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Minimal logging involves logging only the information that is required to recover the transaction without supporting point-in-time recovery."
    },
    {
        "id": 776,
        "Question": "Index page deallocation during a ________ operation is always fully logged.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP INDEX",
            "b) CREATE INDEX",
            "c) ALTER INDEX",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The DBCC DBREINDEX statement is deprecated so you should avoid using it in new applications."
    },
    {
        "id": 777,
        "Question": "Which of the following checkpoint has ‘recovery interval’ less than zero?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Automatic",
            "b) Direct",
            "c) Indirect",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Automatic checkpoints whose target recovery interval is specified by the user defined setting of the sp_configure recovery interval option."
    },
    {
        "id": 778,
        "Question": "Internal checkpoint is generated in response to which of the following event?",
        "Options": [
            "a) A database snapshot is deleted, whether explicitly or internally for DBCC CHECK",
            "b) Bringing a SQL Server failover cluster instance (FCI) offline",
            "c) Bringing a SQL Server failover cluster instance (FCI) online",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Internal Checkpoints are generated by various server components to guarantee that disk images match the current state of the log."
    },
    {
        "id": 779,
        "Question": "__________ backups are taken in bulk or full recovery models only.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Log",
            "b) Active",
            "c) Passive",
            "d) Replica"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A log backup is required before the transaction log can be truncated. When the next log backup is completed, some log space might become reusable."
    },
    {
        "id": 780,
        "Question": "Which of the following compression type is supported by SQL Server 2014?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Row",
            "b) Column",
            "c) Both row and column",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SQL Server 2014 supports columnstore and columnstore archival compression for columnstore tables and indexes."
    },
    {
        "id": 781,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The details of data compression are subject to change without notice in service packs or subsequent releases",
            "b) Compression is not available for system tables",
            "c) If you specify a list of partitions or a partition that is out of range, an error will be generated",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: These are considerations made before using row and page compression."
    },
    {
        "id": 782,
        "Question": "Use _________ data compression to compress columnstore data with archival compression.",
        "Options": [
            "a) COLUMNSTOREARCHIVE",
            "b) COLUMNSTORE_ARCHIVE",
            "c) COLUMNSTORE",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To perform archival compression, SQL Server runs the Microsoft XPRESS compression algorithm on the data."
    },
    {
        "id": 783,
        "Question": "To remove archival compression and restore the data to columnstore compression _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Use ALTER TABLE",
            "b) Use ALTER COLUMN",
            "c) Use ALTER DATABASE",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: use ALTER TABLE (Transact-SQL) or ALTER INDEX (Transact-SQL) with the REBUILD option and DATA COMPRESSION = COLUMNSTORE. "
    },
    {
        "id": 784,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) You can enable or disable ROW or PAGE compression in online state only",
            "b) When you are compressing indexes, leaf-level pages can be compressed with both row and page compression",
            "c) Non–leaf-level pages do not receive page compression",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Enabling compression on a heap is single threaded for an online operation."
    },
    {
        "id": 785,
        "Question": "The data_compression and data_compression_desc columns include ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) COLUMNSTOREARCHIVE",
            "b) COLUMNSTORE_ARCH",
            "c) COLUMNSTORE",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  The type and type_desc columns include CLUSTERED COLUMNSTORE and NONCLUSTERED COLUMNSTORE."
    },
    {
        "id": 786,
        "Question": "8. What is the purpose of schema name in the following code syntax?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">sp_estimate_data_compression_savings \n     <span class=\"br0\">[</span> @schema_name <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"st0\">'schema_name'</span>  \n   <span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">[</span> @object_name <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"st0\">'object_name'</span> \n   <span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">[</span>@index_id <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">]</span> index_id \n   <span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">[</span>@partition_number <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">]</span> partition_number \n   <span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">[</span>@data_compression <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"st0\">'data_compression'</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">[</span>;<span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Name of the table",
            "b) Name of the database schema",
            "c) Name of the indexed view",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The following query first executes the stored procedure sp_estimate_data_compression_savings to return the estimated size of the object if it were to use the ROW compression setting. The example then enables ROW compression on all partitions in the specified table."
    },
    {
        "id": 787,
        "Question": "sp_estimate_data_compression_savings requires ______ permission on the table.",
        "Options": [
            "a) UPDATE",
            "b) SELECT",
            "c) DELETE",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  If schema_name is NULL, the default schema of the current user is used."
    },
    {
        "id": 788,
        "Question": "Which of the following query estimates the size of the Production.WorkOrderRouting table if it is compressed by using ROW compression?",
        "Options": [
            "a) EXEC sp_estimate_data_compression_savings ‘Production’, ‘WorkOrderRouting’, NULL, NULL, ‘ROW’ ;",
            "b) EXEC sp_estimate_data_compression_savings ‘Production’, ‘WorkOrderRouting’, NULL, 1, ‘ROW’ ;",
            "c) EXEC sp_estimate_data_compression_savings ‘Production’, ‘WorkOrderRouting’, 1, NULL, ‘ROW’ ;",
            "d) EXEC sp_estimate_data_compression_savings ‘Production’, ‘WorkOrderRouting’, NULL, NULL, ‘COLUMN’ ;"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Use sp_estimate_data_compression_savings to estimate the savings that can occur when you enable a table or partition for row or page compression."
    },
    {
        "id": 789,
        "Question": "SQL Server 2014 supports up to ________ partitions by default.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 20000",
            "b) 2000",
            "c) 1000",
            "d) 15000"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  In versions earlier than SQL Server 2012, the number of partitions was limited to 1,000 by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 790,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) On x86-based systems, creating a table or index with more than 1000 partitions is possible",
            "b) Compressing large tables or indexes can have manageability and performance benefit",
            "c) Partitioning slow tables or indexes can have the following manageability and performance benefit",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Partitioning feature is not supported on x86 system."
    },
    {
        "id": 791,
        "Question": "__________ is a database object that defines how the rows of a table or index are mapped to a set of partitions based on the values of certain column.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Partition function",
            "b) Partition scheme",
            "c) Partition column",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Partition function defines the number of partitions that the table will have and how the boundaries of the partitions are defined."
    },
    {
        "id": 792,
        "Question": "Designing an nonaligned partitioned index can be useful in the following case?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The base table has not been partitioned",
            "b) The index key is unique and it does not contain the partitioning column of the table",
            "c) You want the base table to participate in collocated joins with more tables using different join columns",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Nonaligned index is an index partitioned independently from its corresponding table."
    },
    {
        "id": 793,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Computed columns that participate in a partition function must be explicitly marked PERSISTED",
            "b) The new, higher limit of 15,000 partitions affects memory, partitioned index operations, DBCC commands, and queries",
            "c) Partitioning column is the process by which the query optimizer accesses only the relevant partitions to satisfy the filter criteria of the query",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Partition elimination is the process by which the query optimizer accesses only the relevant partitions to satisfy the filter criteria of the query.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 794,
        "Question": "At least _______ of RAM is recommended if a large number of partitions are in use.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 16 GB",
            "b) 4 GB",
            "c) 8 GB",
            "d) 2 GB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Systems with 16 GB of RAM that run many memory-intensive processes may run out of memory on operations that run on a large number of partitions."
    },
    {
        "id": 795,
        "Question": "With a larger number of partitions, ______ commands could take longer to execute as the number of partitions increases.",
        "Options": [
            "a) DML",
            "b) DDL",
            "c) DBCC",
            "d) TCL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The Transact-SQL programming language provides DBCC statements that act as Database Console Commands for SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 796,
        "Question": "SQL Server 2008 provides enhanced partitioning information for __________ execution plans.",
        "Options": [
            "a) compile-time",
            "b) run time",
            "c) both compile-time and run-time",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Execution plans now provide an optional Partitioned attribute that indicates that an operator, such as a seek, scan, insert, update, merge, or delete, is performed on a partitioned table."
    },
    {
        "id": 797,
        "Question": "Which of the following partitioned attribute can appear in the following physical and logical operators?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Index Seek",
            "b) Drop",
            "c) Alter",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When an operator such as an Index Seek is executed on a partitioned table or index, the Partitioned attribute appears in the compile-time and run-time plan and is set to True."
    },
    {
        "id": 798,
        "Question": "The query processor uses a __________ execution strategy for queries that select from partitioned objects.",
        "Options": [
            "a) distributed",
            "b) parallel",
            "c) lock",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: As part of the execution strategy, the query processor determines the table partitions required for the query and the proportion of threads to allocate to each partition."
    },
    {
        "id": 799,
        "Question": "Resource Governor is a feature that enables you to specify limits on the amount of ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CPU",
            "b) Physical IO",
            "c) Memory",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SQL Server Resource Governor is a feature than you can use to manage SQL Server workload and system resource consumption."
    },
    {
        "id": 800,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) You can set IO thresholds on the internal resource pool",
            "b) There is workload monitoring or workload management between SQL Server instances",
            "c) A resource group represents the physical resources of the server",
            "d) Resource management is limited to the SQL Server Database Engine"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Resource Governor can not be used for Analysis Services, Integration Services, and Reporting Services."
    },
    {
        "id": 801,
        "Question": "You cannot use the ____________ statement to enable Resource Governor when in a user transaction.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER RESOURCE GOVERNOR",
            "b) ALTER GOVERNOR",
            "c) ALTER RESOURCE",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can enable the Resource Governor by using either SQL Server Management Studio or Transact-SQL."
    },
    {
        "id": 802,
        "Question": "Enabling the Resource Governor requires _________ permission.",
        "Options": [
            "a) CONTROL SERVER",
            "b) CONTROL",
            "c) SERVER",
            "d) SELECT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The classifier function is run for new connections so that their workloads can be assigned to workload groups."
    },
    {
        "id": 803,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Two workload groups (internal and default) are created and mapped to their corresponding resource pools when SQL Server is installed",
            "b) A resource group serves as a container for session requests that have similar classification criteria",
            "c) Resource Governor also supports user-defined workload groups",
            "d) Resource Governor does not impose any controls on a dedicated administrator connection (DAC)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A workload allows for aggregate monitoring of the sessions, and defines policies for the sessions."
    },
    {
        "id": 804,
        "Question": "Which of the following query enables the Resource Governor?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER RESOURCE GOVERNOR CONFIGURE;",
            "b) ALTER RESOURCE RECONFIGURE;",
            "c) ALTER RESOURCE GOVERNOR RECONFIGURE;",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The Resource Governor is turned off by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 805,
        "Question": "Which of the following query disables the resource governor?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER RESOURCE GOVERNOR ENABLE CONFIGURE;",
            "b) ALTER  GOVERNOR DISABLE;",
            "c) ALTER RESOURCE GOVERNOR DISABLE;",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You can disable the Resource Governor by using either SQL Server Management Studio or Transact-SQL."
    },
    {
        "id": 806,
        "Question": "____________  is a hard cap limit on the CPU bandwidth for all requests in the resource pool.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MIN_CPU_PERCENT",
            "b) CAP_CPU_PERCENT",
            "c) MAX_CPU_PERCENT",
            "d) MAX_MEMORY_PERCENT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Workloads associated with the pool can use CPU capacity above the value of MAX_CPU_PERCENT if it is available, but not above the value of CAP_CPU_PERCENT."
    },
    {
        "id": 807,
        "Question": "___________ lets you affinitize a resource pool to one or more schedulers or NUMA nodes for greater isolation of CPU resources.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MAX_IOPS_PER_VOLUME",
            "b) AFFINITY",
            "c) MAX_CPU_PERCENT",
            "d) MAX_MEMORY_PERCENT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: By using the AFFINITY option the Sales and Marketing workloads can be scheduled on different CPUs."
    },
    {
        "id": 808,
        "Question": "Which of the following formula is used for calculating the effective MAX %?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 100 – sum(MIN %)",
            "b) min(X,Y)",
            "c) max(X,Y)",
            "d) Effective MAX % – MIN %"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The minimum of the configured MAX value of a pool and the sum of the MIN values of other pools is subtracted from 100 percent."
    },
    {
        "id": 809,
        "Question": "Business intelligence (BI) is a broad category of application programs which includes _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Decision support",
            "b) Data mining",
            "c) OLAP",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Business intelligence (BI) is a broad category of application programs and technologies for gathering, storing, analyzing, and providing access to data from various data sources."
    },
    {
        "id": 810,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) OLAP is an umbrella term that refers to an assortment of software applications for analyzing an organization’s raw data for intelligent decision making",
            "b) Business intelligence equips enterprises to gain business advantage from data",
            "c) BI makes an organization agile thereby giving it a lower edge in today’s evolving market condition",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Once an organization is powered with BI it can anticipate enhanced turnaround time on data collection, come up with fresh ideas for novel business initiatives."
    },
    {
        "id": 811,
        "Question": "BI can catalyze a business’s success in terms of _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Distinguish the products and services that drive revenues",
            "b) Rank customers and locations based on profitability",
            "c) Ranks customers and locations based on probability",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SQL Server Business Intelligence delivers a comprehensive platform empowering organizations to build and deploy secure, scalable and manageable BI apps."
    },
    {
        "id": 812,
        "Question": "Which of the following areas are affected by BI?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Revenue",
            "b) CRM",
            "c) Sales",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Customer relationship management (CRM) is a system for managing a company’s interactions with current and future customers. It often involves using technology to organize, automate and synchronize sales, marketing, customer service, and technical support."
    },
    {
        "id": 813,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data is factual information for analysis",
            "b) BI is a category of database software that provides an interface to help users quickly and interactively scrutinize the results in a variety of dimensions of the data",
            "c) Customer relationship management (CRM) entails all aspects of interaction that a company has with its customer",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Online Analytical Processing is a category of database software that provides an interface to help users quickly and interactively scrutinize the results in a variety of dimensions of the data."
    },
    {
        "id": 814,
        "Question": "________ is a performance management tool that recapitulates an organization’s performance from several standpoints on a single page.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Balanced Scorecard",
            "b) Data Cube",
            "c) Dashboard",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The balanced scorecard (BSC) is a strategy performance management tool – a semi-standard structured report, supported by design methods and automation."
    },
    {
        "id": 815,
        "Question": "__________ is a system where operations like data extraction, transformation and loading operations are executed.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data staging",
            "b) Data integration",
            "c) ETL",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In computing, Extract, Transform and Load (ETL) refers to a process in database usage and especially in data warehousing"
    },
    {
        "id": 816,
        "Question": "_________ is a category of applications and technologies for presenting and analyzing corporate and external data.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data warehouse",
            "b) MIS",
            "c) EIS",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: EIS stands for Enterprise Information System."
    },
    {
        "id": 817,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the process of basing an organization’s actions and decisions on actual measured results of performance?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Institutional performance management",
            "b) Gap analysis",
            "c) Slice and Dice",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  incorporates performance measures, benchmarks, and goals to attain the best results."
    },
    {
        "id": 818,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not form part of BI Stack in SQL Server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SSRS",
            "b) SSIS",
            "c) SSAS",
            "d) OBIEE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Oracle Business Intelligence Enterprise Edition Plus, also termed OBI EE Plus, is Oracle Corporation’s set of business intelligence tools."
    },
    {
        "id": 819,
        "Question": "The Analysis Services __________ role defines administrative access of Windows users and groups to an instance of Analysis Services.",
        "Options": [
            "a) database",
            "b) server",
            "c) user",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Members of this role have access to all Analysis Services databases and objects on an instance of Analysis Services."
    },
    {
        "id": 820,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The permissions of a role may allow members to access and administer the database",
            "b) Server roles, roles defined by administrators to control access to objects and data for non-administrator user",
            "c) Database roles, roles defined by administrators to control access to objects and data for administrator user",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Each permission has one or more access rights associated with it, which in turn gives the permission finer control over access to a particular object in the database. "
    },
    {
        "id": 821,
        "Question": "Which of the following role is created as a separate object in an Analysis Services database, and applies only to the database in which that role is created?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Database",
            "b) Membership",
            "c) Client",
            "d) Server"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: An Analysis Services database role defines user access to objects and data in an Analysis Services database."
    },
    {
        "id": 822,
        "Question": "_________ let you create external, user-defined functions using any common language runtime (CLR) language.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Aggregate",
            "b) Assemblies",
            "c) Synonym",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Assemblies let you extend the business functionality of MDX and DMX."
    },
    {
        "id": 823,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The SSAS host-level policy is a combination of Analysis Services fixed policy for system assemblies and user-specified policy for user assemblies",
            "b) Security for assemblies is based on the .NET Framework security model, which is a code-access security model",
            "c) Calling a user-defined function in an assembly is performed just like calling an intrinsic function",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The Analysis Services host-level policy is a combination of Analysis Services fixed policy for system assemblies and user-specified policy for user assemblies."
    },
    {
        "id": 824,
        "Question": "Which of the following permission setting provides internal computation permission?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Unsafe",
            "b) ExternalAccess",
            "c) Safe",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: This permission bucket does not assign permissions to access any of the protected resources in the .NET Framework. "
    },
    {
        "id": 825,
        "Question": "If the __________ setting is used, the execution context corresponds to the Windows login user account IUSER_servername on the server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ImpersonateAnon",
            "b) Anonymous",
            "c) ImpersonateAnonymous",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The default setting, ImpersonateCurrentUser, runs an assembly under the current user’s network login account."
    },
    {
        "id": 826,
        "Question": "Which of the following namespace discover set of assemblies?",
        "Options": [
            "a) System.Reflection",
            "b) System.Refraction",
            "c) Sys.Reflection",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Analysis Services does not expose application domains directly."
    },
    {
        "id": 827,
        "Question": "Security for stored procedures is set with the _________ property on a stored procedure.",
        "Options": [
            "a) PermissionSet",
            "b) SetPermissionSet",
            "c) Permission",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can use stored procedures to call external routines from Microsoft SQL Server 2005 Analysis Services(SSAS)."
    },
    {
        "id": 828,
        "Question": "If functions in one assembly call functions in a separate assembly, you must register both assemblies in ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) client",
            "b) server",
            "c) table",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Stored procedures are registered on a server or on a database. Server stored procedures can be called from any query context."
    },
    {
        "id": 829,
        "Question": "1.In Microsoft SQL Server 2005 Analysis Services (SSAS), a _________ is a language-specific representation of the name of a dimension.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Translation",
            "b) Dimension translation",
            "c) Dim translation",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Translations provide server support for client applications that can support multiple languages."
    },
    {
        "id": 830,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The collation and language information for the client computer is stored in the form of a locale identifier (LCID)",
            "b) SQL Server 2008 Analysis Services also supports translations of cube objects",
            "c) SQL Server 2000 Analysis Services supports translations of cube objects",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The instance uses the LCID to determine which set of translations to use when providing metadata for Analysis Services objects."
    },
    {
        "id": 831,
        "Question": "Members of a _________ dimension can only be moved within the same level.",
        "Options": [
            "a) readback",
            "b) writeback",
            "c) readwrite",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For a write-enabled dimension, updates are recorded directly in the dimension’s table."
    },
    {
        "id": 832,
        "Question": "Updates to the ______ attribute in a parent-child hierarchy must not include updates to any other properties or attributes.",
        "Options": [
            "a) child",
            "b) parent",
            "c) both child and parent",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If a member of a parent-child hierarchy is deleted, the member’s children are moved to the member’s parent."
    },
    {
        "id": 833,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The data in a dimension is generally read-write both",
            "b) Upon connection, the client passes the LCID to the instance of Analysis Services",
            "c) For a write-enabled cube or partition, updates are stored in a writeback table separate from the cube’s source tables",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The data in a dimension is generally read-only."
    },
    {
        "id": 834,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not supported by linked dimensions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) readback",
            "b) writeback",
            "c) readwrite",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In Microsoft SQL Server 2005 Analysis Services (SSAS), a linked dimension is based on a dimension that is stored in another Analysis Services database."
    },
    {
        "id": 835,
        "Question": "The _______ attribute is the attribute in a dimension that identifies the columns in the dimension main table that are used in foreign key relationships to the fact table.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Dim",
            "b) KEY",
            "c) PK",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Typically, the key attribute represents the primary key column or columns in the dimension table."
    },
    {
        "id": 836,
        "Question": "Which of the following property is set to zero so that all levels are not created?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Aggregatable",
            "b) IsAggregatable",
            "c) IsAggregate",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The All level contains the aggregated value of the attribute’s members across the measures in each measure group to which the dimension of which the attribute is related is a member."
    },
    {
        "id": 837,
        "Question": "By default, in a ________ schema, all attributes are directly related to the key attributes.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Relational",
            "b) Snowflake",
            "c) Star",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Star schema enables users to browse the facts in the cube based on any attribute hierarchy in the dimension."
    },
    {
        "id": 838,
        "Question": "Parent-child hierarchies are automatically detected by the _________ Wizard.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Dimension",
            "b) Cube",
            "c) Dimension and Cube",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A multilevel hierarchy is a parent-child hierarchy based on parent-child relationships defined in the underlying dimension table. "
    },
    {
        "id": 839,
        "Question": "_______ is currency used to store transactions on which measures to be converted are based in SSAS.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Local currency",
            "b) Pivot currency",
            "c) Global currency",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  A Local currency identifier associated with an attribute in a dimension table that is then associated with a transaction in the fact table."
    },
    {
        "id": 840,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The Type property of the dimension is set to Reporting Currency",
            "b) The Type property of one attribute for the dimension is set to CurrencyName in Latin",
            "c) The values of Type attribute must be used in all columns that should contain a currency identifier",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Currency dimension is a database dimension defined with type property of the dimension set to Currency."
    },
    {
        "id": 841,
        "Question": "For _________ currency conversions, the pivot currency and reporting currency are the same.",
        "Options": [
            "a) one-to-one",
            "b) many-to-one",
            "c) many-many",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Reporting currency is the currency to which transactions are converted from the pivot currency."
    },
    {
        "id": 842,
        "Question": "You can use the __________  Wizard to specify which measures from the rate measure group are used to convert values.",
        "Options": [
            "a) BI",
            "b) ETL",
            "c) MIS",
            "d) OBIEE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You choose the exchange rate direction on the Set currency conversion options page of the Business Intelligence Wizard."
    },
    {
        "id": 843,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Transactions are stored in the fact table in local currencies for many-to-many conversion",
            "b) Transactions are stored in the fact table in the pivot currency for one-to-many conversion",
            "c) If you choose a many-to-many or one-to-many conversion type for your currency conversion, you need to specify the reporting currencies",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Transactions are stored in the fact table in the pivot currency, and then converted to one or more other reporting currencies. "
    },
    {
        "id": 844,
        "Question": "The Business Intelligence Wizard supports ______ different types of currency conversion.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 6"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Specifying the conversion type allows the Business Intelligence Wizard to define the named query and dimension structure of the reporting currency dimension."
    },
    {
        "id": 845,
        "Question": "If you select the __________ conversion type, a reporting currency dimension is also created.",
        "Options": [
            "a) one-to-one",
            "b) many-to-one",
            "c) many-many",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer:  b\nExplanation: The dimension contains only one member representing the pivot currency because the pivot currency is also used as the reporting currency for one-to-many currency conversion."
    },
    {
        "id": 846,
        "Question": "Which of the following Sort order sorts and compares data in Analysis Services based on the bit patterns defined for each character?",
        "Options": [
            "a) BIN2 (_BIN2)1",
            "b) Binary (_BIN)1",
            "c) Case-sensitive (_CS)",
            "d) Case-insensitive"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Binary sort order is case sensitive and accent sensitive. Binary is also the fastest sorting order."
    },
    {
        "id": 847,
        "Question": "____________  distinguishes between a single-byte character and the same character when represented as a double-byte character.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Accent-insensitive (_AI)",
            "b) Kana-sensitive (_KS)",
            "c) Accent-sensitive (_AS)",
            "d) Width-sensitive (_WS)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: There is no sort order suffix for width-insensitive sorting."
    },
    {
        "id": 848,
        "Question": "Which of the following property enables Analysis Services to use a faster algorithm for string hashing and comparison?",
        "Options": [
            "a) EnableFast1033Local",
            "b) EnableFast1036Locale",
            "c) EnableFast1033Locale",
            "d) EnableQuick1033Locale"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: For the Analysis Services instance, you can get additional performance benefits by setting the EnableFast1033Locale configuration property to true."
    },
    {
        "id": 849,
        "Question": "_______ lets you manage cube context from within an MDX script.",
        "Options": [
            "a) CALCULATE",
            "b) CALC",
            "c) SCOPE CALC",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In Microsoft SQL Server Analysis Services, a Multidimensional Expressions (MDX) script is made up of one or more MDX expressions or statements that populate a cube with calculations."
    },
    {
        "id": 850,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Few MDX queries run within a specified cube context",
            "b) SELECT statement is the most frequently used query in MDX",
            "c) When formulating a Multidimensional Expressions (MDX) SELECT statement, an application typically examines a cube and divides the set of hierarchies into three subsets",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: By understanding how an MDX SELECT statement must specify a result set, what the syntax of the SELECT statement is, and how to create a simple query using the SELECT statement, you will have a solid understanding of how to use MDX to query multidimensional data."
    },
    {
        "id": 851,
        "Question": "________ causes the server to raise an error when Microsoft SQL Server Analysis Services finds any error in the MDX script.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ignore",
            "b) IgnoreNone",
            "c) IgnoreAll",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Error handling is done through the ScriptErrorHandlingMode enumerator. "
    },
    {
        "id": 852,
        "Question": "The Backus-Naur Form (BNF) of {*(<comment> | <whitespace> | <newline>)} will be parsed as ______ for backwards compatibility.",
        "Options": [
            "a) {\\}",
            "b) {*}",
            "c) {+}",
            "d) {-}"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: By using calculated cells, the client application can specify a rollup value for a particular set of cells, instead of for an entire set of cells as in the case of a custom rollup formula or a calculated member."
    },
    {
        "id": 853,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The WHERE clause describes the slicer axis in an MDX query",
            "b) MDX syntax distinguishes sets by surrounding tuples or members with braces",
            "c) MDX queries can have three query axes in the SELECT statement",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Each axis behaves in exactly the same way, unlike SQL where there are significant differences between how the rows and the columns of a query behave."
    },
    {
        "id": 854,
        "Question": "___________ creates a calculation that evaluates a Multidimensional Expressions (MDX) expression over a specified set of tuples within a cube.",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE CELL CALCULATION",
            "b) CREATE CELL CALC",
            "c) CREATE MEMBER CALCULATION",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: CREATE CELL CALCULATION statement creates a calculated cell formula for a specified set of tuples within a cube."
    },
    {
        "id": 855,
        "Question": "7. The following code is a syntax of which statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"br0\">[</span> <span class=\"kw1\">SESSION</span> <span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"br0\">[</span>HIDDEN<span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"br0\">[</span> CALCULATED <span class=\"br0\">]</span> MEMBER CURRENTCUBE <span class=\"sy0\">|</span> Cube_Name<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>Member_Name \n   <span class=\"kw1\">AS</span> MDX_Expression\n      <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>Property_Name <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> Property_Value<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">...</span>n<span class=\"br0\">]</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">......</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>SCOPE_ISOLATION <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> CUBE<span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE SESSION",
            "b) CREATE CUBE",
            "c) CREATE MEMBER",
            "d) CREATE MDX"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: CREATE MEMBER creates a calculated member."
    },
    {
        "id": 856,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the MDX Data Definition Statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE ACTION",
            "b) DROP CUBE",
            "c) CREATE CUBE",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Creates an action that can be associated with a cube, dimension, hierarchy, or subordinate object."
    },
    {
        "id": 857,
        "Question": "Valid syntax for REFRESH CUBE statement is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) REFRESH CUBECube_Name",
            "b) REFRESH CUBE Cube_Name",
            "c) REFRESH CUBE “Cube_Name”",
            "d) REFRESH CUBE \\Cube_Name\\"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: REFRESH CUBECube_Name refreshes the client’s cache for a cube."
    },
    {
        "id": 858,
        "Question": "__________ is the set of hierarchies from which data is retrieved for a single member.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Slicer axis",
            "b) Query axes",
            "c) Dice axis",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  query and slicer axes can be constructed from multiple hierarchies of the cube to be queried"
    },
    {
        "id": 859,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only dropping the default member is supported in MDX Scripting",
            "b) In the SELECT statement, the FROM clause determines the cube context",
            "c) Very few cube can control how errors within a Multidimensional Expressions (MDX) script are handled",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This context can be the whole cube or just a subcube from that cube. Having specified cube context through the FROM clause, you can use additional functions to expand or restrict that context."
    },
    {
        "id": 860,
        "Question": "When you include a many-to-many dimension, which of the following rules apply?",
        "Options": [
            "a) You must add the intermediary measure group",
            "b) You must add the entire many-to-many dimension",
            "c) You must add the entirety of all dimensions common to the two measure groups involved in the many-to-may relationship",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Reference dimensions are materialized and added as regular dimensions."
    },
    {
        "id": 861,
        "Question": " _________ statement is used to write back data to any cell in a cube that aggregates to its parent using the SUM aggregation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) UPDATE CUBE",
            "b) DELETE CUBE",
            "c) ALTER CUBE",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: You can update the value of a specified leaf or non leaf cell in a cube, optionally allocating the value for a specified non-leaf cell across dependent leaf cells."
    },
    {
        "id": 862,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) A weight expression should be expressed as a decimal value between zero (0) and 1",
            "b) Each UPDATE CUBE allocation should be considered to be atomic for transactional purposes",
            "c) When updated cells overlap, the Update Isolation Level connection string property can be used to enhance performance for UPDATE CUBE",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When updated cells do not overlap, the Update Isolation Level connection string property can be used to enhance performance for UPDATE CUBE."
    },
    {
        "id": 863,
        "Question": "If a weight expression is not specified, the UPDATE CUBE statement implicitly uses which of the following expression?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Weight_Expression = <leaf cell value> * <existing value>",
            "b) Weight_Expression = <leaf cell value> / <existing value>",
            "c) Weight_Expression = <leaf cell value> – <existing value>",
            "d) Weight_Expression = <leaf cell value> + <existing value>"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It may be helpful to think of the UPDATE CUBE statement as a subroutine that will automatically generate a series of individual cell writeback operations to leaf and non-leaf cells that will roll up into a specified sum."
    },
    {
        "id": 864,
        "Question": "When used on a measure that contains integers, the _________ method can return imprecise results caused by incremental rounding changes.",
        "Options": [
            "a) USE_EQUAL_ALLOCATION",
            "b) USE_WEIGHTED_ALLOCATION",
            "c) USE_WEIGHTED_INCREMENT",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Every leaf cell that contributes to the updated cell will be assigned an equal value "
    },
    {
        "id": 865,
        "Question": "Which of the following keyword forces a specified set to be evaluated within the current context?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SCOPE",
            "b) CASE",
            "c) EXISTING",
            "d) FREEZE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: DRILLTHROUGH statement retrieves the underlying table rows that were used to create a specified cell in a cube."
    },
    {
        "id": 866,
        "Question": "Which of the following tool requires Reporting Services in SharePoint mode?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Report Designer",
            "b) Power View",
            "c) Report Builder",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Power view gives interactive data exploration and visual presentation experience designed to let you create and interact with reports based on Analysis Services tabular models."
    },
    {
        "id": 867,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The tools that you use is independent of the deployment mode of your report server",
            "b) A set of scripting tools are available for administering the report server in SQL Server Reporting Services",
            "c) SQL Server Reporting Services contains a set of graphical and scripting tools that support the development and use of rich reports in a managed environment",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The tool set includes development tools, configuration and administration tools, and report viewing tools."
    },
    {
        "id": 868,
        "Question": "______________ does not help you manage report server content, enable additional features, or grant access to the server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reporting Services Configuration Manager",
            "b) SSMS",
            "c) SQL Server Configuration Manager",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Reporting Services Configuration Manager is used to configure a Reporting Services installation."
    },
    {
        "id": 869,
        "Question": "__________ is a tool to configure and manage a report server connection to the report server database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Rskeymgmt Utility",
            "b) Windows Management Instrumentation (WMI) Classes",
            "c) Rsconfig Utility",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: You can also use it to specify a user account to use for unattended report processing."
    },
    {
        "id": 870,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Report Manager works in all modes",
            "b) A report server is a computer that has an instance of Reporting Services installed",
            "c) A report server integrated with SharePoint has two possible configurations",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Report Manager works in native mode only."
    },
    {
        "id": 871,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a tool for Report Content Management?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Report Server Web service URL",
            "b) Rskeymgmt Utility",
            "c) Configuration manager",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Use Report Server Web service URL tool to browse content in the report catalog in a generic item navigation page."
    },
    {
        "id": 872,
        "Question": "Which of the following mode lets you interact with the report server, reports, and report related items by using a browser with Report Manager or URL access commands?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SharePoint mode report server",
            "b) Native",
            "c) SSRS",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A report server configured in native mode is a computer that has SQL Server Reporting Services installed and configured as a stand-alone server."
    },
    {
        "id": 873,
        "Question": "Reports use __________ to retrieve data for a report when a query runs or when the report is processed.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data connections",
            "b) Data source definition",
            "c) Connection string",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A data connection includes a name and connection properties that are dependent on the connection type."
    },
    {
        "id": 874,
        "Question": "A _________ is an item stored internally in an alerting database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Connection string",
            "b) Data alert",
            "c) Shared data source",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A data alert definition includes which data to use from existing report data feeds, the conditions to be met, a schedule."
    },
    {
        "id": 875,
        "Question": "A __________ is a report server item that contains a pointer to the report definition.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Drilldown report",
            "b) Linked report",
            "c) Subreport",
            "d) Drillthrough report"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Linked reports include security, parameters, location, subscriptions, and schedules."
    },
    {
        "id": 876,
        "Question": "A _________ report solution includes a main report that displays summary information with hyperlinks to one or more reports that display detailed information.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Main",
            "b) Detail",
            "c) Drillthrough",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The drillthrough report opens separately from the main report. A hyperlink can be defined on any report item that has an Action property."
    },
    {
        "id": 877,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) A published report is a report definition (.rdl) file",
            "b) A saved report is a published report definition that is converted to a newer schema when a report server is upgraded",
            "c) Report history is a collection of report snapshots",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Report history is not intended for reports that contain confidential or personal data."
    },
    {
        "id": 878,
        "Question": "An ___________ report is a fully paged report saved in a specific file format.",
        "Options": [
            "a) exported",
            "b) fully processed",
            "c) compiled",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  Export formats depend on installed rendering extensions and can be customized. By default, export formats include Excel, Word, XML, PDF, TIFF, and CSV."
    },
    {
        "id": 879,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a list type in RDL with base 64 encoded value?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Boolean",
            "b) Binary",
            "c) Enum",
            "d) Name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Name is a property with a string text value."
    },
    {
        "id": 880,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) A report snapshot is a report that contains layout information and query results that were retrieved at a specific point in time. Unlike on-demand reports",
            "b) A detailed report is a saved copy of a compiled report and report data",
            "c) A report model is a user-friendly description of an underlying database, with pre-established data relationships and auto-generated queries",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Cached reports are used to improve performance by reducing the number of processing requests to the report processor and by reducing the time that is required to retrieve large report datasets."
    },
    {
        "id": 881,
        "Question": "You can use Report Manager in ________ mode and SharePoint site administration pages in ________ mode.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Native, Sharepoint",
            "b) Sharepoint, Native",
            "c) Native, Native",
            "d) Sharepoint, Sharepoint"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Schedule operations are not available in every edition of SQL Server."
    },
    {
        "id": 882,
        "Question": "__________ are portable, multipurpose items that contain ready-to-use schedule information.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Report-specific schedule",
            "b) Shared schedules",
            "c) File schedules",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Shared schedules are system-level items, creating a shared schedule requires system-level permissions."
    },
    {
        "id": 883,
        "Question": "The Schedule and Delivery Processing feature must be enabled through the ____________ property.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ScheduleEventsDeliveryEnabled",
            "b) ScheduleEventsAndReportDeliveryEnabled",
            "c) ScheduleEventsAndReportDelivery",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The Scheduling and Delivery Processor requires that the Report Server service and SQL Server Agent are started."
    },
    {
        "id": 884,
        "Question": "The functionality that SQL Server Agent provides to Reporting Services can be replaced with custom code that uses the _________ method to add schedule events to the queue.",
        "Options": [
            "a) FireEvent",
            "b) FireEventdata",
            "c) Eventdata",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ReportingService2010.FireEvent Method raises an event based on the supplied parameters."
    },
    {
        "id": 885,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is used to retrieve rows from the view ExecutionLog3?",
        "Options": [
            "a) select * from ExecutionLog3 order by TimeStart DESC",
            "b) select * from ExecLog3 order by TimeStart DESC",
            "c) select * from ExecutionLog4 order by TimeStart DESC",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ExecutionLog3 view added additional performance diagnostics node inside the XML based AdditionalInfo column."
    },
    {
        "id": 886,
        "Question": "_____________ for Office is a lightweight set of tools for predictive analytics.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server 2008 Data Mining Add-ins",
            "b) SQL Server 2012 Data Mining Add-ins",
            "c) SQL Server 2014 Data Mining Add-ins",
            "d) SQL Server 2012 Data Mining Excel"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQL Server 2012 Data Mining Add-ins lets you use data in Excel to build analytical models for prediction, recommendation, or exploration."
    },
    {
        "id": 887,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) You cannot create and save connections to re-use data sources, repeat experiments, or re-train models",
            "b) The add-ins are built on the capabilities of the .NET Framework 2.0 and the .NET programmability support provided by Office 2007",
            "c) The SQL Server 2005 Data Mining Add-ins for Office 2007 allow you to uncover hidden patterns and relationships in your data",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To use the Microsoft SQL Server 2005 Data Mining Add-Ins for Office 2007, you must be connected to a SQL Server 2005 Analysis Services database."
    },
    {
        "id": 888,
        "Question": "_____________ allows you to analyze your spreadsheet data in powerful ways.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data Mining Templates for Visio",
            "b) Table Analysis Tools for Excel",
            "c) Data Mining Client for Excel",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Table Analysis Tools for Excel is available in Data Mining Add-ins for Office 2007 package."
    },
    {
        "id": 889,
        "Question": "___________  analyzes the patterns in data that have the strongest influence on a certain outcome.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Analyze Key Influencers",
            "b) Detect Categories",
            "c) Fill From Example",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  Analyze Key Influencers can analyze the factors that are key to determining which customers will spend the most money."
    },
    {
        "id": 890,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The Detect Categories tool detects the rows in the data table that contain similar characteristics and groups them into categories",
            "b) The tool employs SQL Server Data Mining to detect patterns in the sample you provide and apply those to the remaining missing values",
            "c) The Detect categories tool predicts future values based on trends in existing time series data",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The Forecast tool predicts future values based on trends in existing time series data."
    },
    {
        "id": 891,
        "Question": "Fill From Example tool also produces a patterns report similar to ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Analyze Key Influencers",
            "b) Detect Categories",
            "c) Fill From Example",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  Analyze Key Influencers tool describes the rules that were applied to fill in the missing values."
    },
    {
        "id": 892,
        "Question": "Which of the following tool analyzes and highlights data rows that do not appear to match the general patterns found in the rest of the table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Exceptions",
            "b) Highlight",
            "c) Scenario Analysis",
            "d) Highlight Exceptions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  Highlight Exceptions not only highlights exception rows, but it also highlights the specific column value in each row that is likely to be the cause of the exception."
    },
    {
        "id": 893,
        "Question": "Scenario Analysis tool allows you to model _______ types of scenarios.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Scenario Analysis tool report the effect on either a single row or the entire table of input data."
    },
    {
        "id": 894,
        "Question": "In order to use the Analyze in Excel feature, you must have ___________ installed on the system.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SSDT",
            "b) SSMS",
            "c) SSMA",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server Data Tools (SSDT) is a toolset that provides an integrated environment for database developers to carry out all their data analysis."
    },
    {
        "id": 895,
        "Question": "The _________ wizard helps you build a classification model based on existing data in an Excel table.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Associate",
            "b) Classify",
            "c) Estimate",
            "d) Aggregate"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A classification model extracts patterns in your data that indicate similarities and helps you make predictions based on groupings of values. "
    },
    {
        "id": 896,
        "Question": "What is SQL Server 2008 R2 Hard Disk Space Requirement for database engine?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 811 Mb",
            "b) 711 Mb",
            "c) 611 Mb",
            "d) 511 Mb"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQL Server 2008 R2 can run on both 32-bit and 64-bit systems."
    },
    {
        "id": 897,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server books online is part of Microsoft SQL Server",
            "b) SQL Server books online is not a part of Microsoft SQL Server",
            "c) SQL Server books online needs to be downloaded separately",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SQL Server Online 2008 books occupy 157 Mb."
    },
    {
        "id": 898,
        "Question": "Which are the SQL Server 2008 R2 components require space more than 1.5 Gb?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SSIS",
            "b) SSAS",
            "c) Client components",
            "d) SSRS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Client components does not include SSIS tools."
    },
    {
        "id": 899,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a feature of SQL Server 2008 R2 Datacenter?",
        "Options": [
            "a) StreamInsight Premium real-time event processing",
            "b) Support for 32-bit and 64-bit processors",
            "c) Support for up to 256 logical CPUs",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQL Server 2008 R2 Datacenter provides the complete feature set available in SQL Server 2008."
    },
    {
        "id": 900,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The Datacenter edition provides the maximum scalability of the different SQL Server 2008 R2 editions",
            "b) The Datacenter edition is priced at $11,990 per processor",
            "c) There are several different editions of SQL Server",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The Datacenter edition is priced at $13,748 if you have Software Assurance (SA)."
    },
    {
        "id": 901,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a feature of SQL Server 2008 R2 Enterprise?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hot-add CPU",
            "b) Hot-add RAM",
            "c) Database partitioning",
            "d) In memory database"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In-memory database capability is provided by 2012."
    },
    {
        "id": 902,
        "Question": "Which of the following operating system is Supported by IA-64 Edition?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Windows Server 2003 R2 SP2 64-bit Itanium Datacenter",
            "b) Windows Server 2003 SP2 64-bit x64 Datacenter",
            "c) Windows Server 2003 SP2 64-bit x64 Enterprise",
            "d) Windows Server 2003 SP2 64-bit x64 Standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server 2008 R2 Enterprise is designed for large, highly scalable enterprise implementations."
    },
    {
        "id": 903,
        "Question": "What does the SQL Server setup program require?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Named Pipes",
            "b) Shared Memory",
            "c) Microsoft Windows Installer 4.5",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: All the x86 and x64 editions of SQL Server, except the SQL Server Express versions."
    },
    {
        "id": 904,
        "Question": "Which is the minimum processor speed for SQL Server 2008?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1.4 GHz",
            "b) 2.4 GHz",
            "c) 3.4 GHz",
            "d) 4.4 GHz"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Recommended speed is 2.0 GHz or faster."
    },
    {
        "id": 905,
        "Question": "The main memory requirements for SQL Server 2008 includes ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Minimum:512 MB",
            "b) Minimum:1 GB",
            "c) Maximum:252 MB",
            "d) Maximum:512 MB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Recommended RAM is 2.048 GB or more for SQL Server 2008."
    },
    {
        "id": 906,
        "Question": "What is SQL Server 2012 R2 Hard Disk Space Requirement for database engine?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 811 Mb",
            "b) 711 Mb",
            "c) 611 Mb",
            "d) 511 Mb"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL Server 2012 can run on both 32-bit and 64-bit systems."
    },
    {
        "id": 907,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server books online is part of Microsoft SQL Server 2012",
            "b) SQL Server books online is not a part of Microsoft SQL Server 2008",
            "c) Resource database is part of System database",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Resource database is added to SQL Server 2012."
    },
    {
        "id": 908,
        "Question": "Which components of SQL Server 2014 require 1182 Mb?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SSIS",
            "b) SSAS",
            "c) Client components",
            "d) SSRS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Client components does not include Integration tools for SQL Server 2012."
    },
    {
        "id": 909,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a feature of SQL Server 2014?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Column oriented database",
            "b) Support for 32-bit and 64-bit processors",
            "c) In memory database",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SQL Server 2014 CTP 1 may contain branding from Microsoft SQL Server 2012 and is versioned as 11.0."
    },
    {
        "id": 910,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement related to SQL Server 2014.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL Server 2014 CTP 1 is pre-release software and should be installed only on a clean machine",
            "b) SQL Server 2014 CTP 1 is a non-production release and should be installed and used in production environments",
            "c) SQL Server 2014 CTP 1 is only available in the English language",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There should be noSQL products other than SQL Server 2014 CTP1."
    },
    {
        "id": 911,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a feature of SQL Server 2012 R2 Enterprise?",
        "Options": [
            "a) In memory database",
            "b) Hot-add RAM",
            "c) Database partitioning",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In-memory database capability is provided by 2012."
    },
    {
        "id": 912,
        "Question": "Which of the following operating system is supported by SQL Server 2014?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Windows Server 2012",
            "b) Windows 8 RTM",
            "c) Windows Vista SP2",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: These are minimum operating system requirements for the SQL Server 2014."
    },
    {
        "id": 913,
        "Question": "Which of the following component is not installed by SQL Server setup 2012 required by the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a) .NET Framework 3.5 SP11",
            "b) Named Pipes",
            "c) SQL Server Setup support files",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SQL Server Setup will block installations on read-only or compressed drives."
    },
    {
        "id": 914,
        "Question": "Which is the minimum processor speed for SQL Server 2012?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1.4 GHz",
            "b) 2.4 GHz",
            "c) 3.4 GHz",
            "d) 4.4 GHz"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The minimum processing requirement is a 1.0GHz CPU for a 32-bit x86 implementation and a 1.4GHz CPU for a 64-bit x64 implementation. Microsoft’s recommended minimum processor speed is 2.0GHz. "
    },
    {
        "id": 915,
        "Question": "The supported storage types for data files are ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) RAM",
            "b) Hard Storage",
            "c) SMB File Share",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SMB storage can be hosted by a Windows File Server or a third party SMB storage device."
    },
    {
        "id": 916,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a system database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Northwind",
            "b) Master",
            "c) Tempdb",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Northwind is a sample database."
    },
    {
        "id": 917,
        "Question": "Point out the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) By default, tempdb auto grows as needed while SQL Server is running",
            "b) By default, master auto grows as needed while SQL Server is running",
            "c) By default, pubs auto grows as needed while SQL Server is running",
            "d) By default, msdb auto grows as needed while SQL Server is running"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Tempdb holds all temporary tables and temporary stored procedures."
    },
    {
        "id": 918,
        "Question": "Which of the following holds temporary data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Northwind",
            "b) Master",
            "c) Tempdb",
            "d) Msdb"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Tempdb is a global resource; the temporary tables and stored procedures for all users connected to the system are stored there."
    },
    {
        "id": 919,
        "Question": "Which is the most important system database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Northwind",
            "b) Master",
            "c) Tempdb",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The master database records all of the system level information for a SQL Server system."
    },
    {
        "id": 920,
        "Question": "Point out the wrong statement related to master database.",
        "Options": [
            "a) They are used to provide details of an backup plans",
            "b) Master records the information for SQL Server temporarily",
            "c) Master records the initialization information for SQL Server",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  Master is the database that records the existence of all other databases."
    },
    {
        "id": 921,
        "Question": "Which database is used as template for all databases?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Northwind",
            "b) Master",
            "c) Tempdb",
            "d) Model"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: When a CREATE DATABASE statement is issued, the first part of the database is created by copying in the contents of the model database."
    },
    {
        "id": 922,
        "Question": "Which of the following database is used by SQL Server Agent?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Pubs",
            "b) Msdb",
            "c) Tempdb",
            "d) Model"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The msdb database is used by SQL Server Agent for scheduling alerts and jobs, and recording operators."
    },
    {
        "id": 923,
        "Question": "How many types of system databases are present in SQL Server 2008?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 6"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Microsoft SQL Server 2008 have four system databases."
    },
    {
        "id": 924,
        "Question": "Which of the following system database occupies more space and memory?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Master",
            "b) Msdb",
            "c) Tempdb",
            "d) Model"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The master database records all of the system level information for a SQL Server system."
    },
    {
        "id": 925,
        "Question": "The _________ database stores basic configuration information for the server.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Master",
            "b) Msdb",
            "c) Tempdb",
            "d) Model"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Master database includes information about the file locations of the user databases, as well as logon accounts, server configuration settings, and a number of other items such as linked servers and startup stored procedures."
    }
]